<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.1">
			<file name="source.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/supplements/tomb-of-annihilation/source.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Tomb of Annihilation" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_TOMB_OF_ANNIHILATION">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p><strong>Dare to defy death in this adventure for the world’s greatest roleplaying game.</strong></p><p>The talk of the streets and taverns has all been about the so-called death curse: a wasting disease afflicting everyone who’s ever been raised from the dead. Victims grow thinner and weaker each day, slowly but steadily sliding toward the death they once denied.</p><p>When they finally succumb, they can’t be raised—and neither can anyone else, regardless of whether they’ve ever received that miracle in the past. Temples and scholars of divine magic are at a loss to explain a curse that has affected the entire region, and possibly the entire world.</p><p>The cause is a necromantic artifact called the Soulmonger, which is located somewhere in Chult, a mysterious peninsula far to the south, ringed with mountains and choked with rainforests.</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">TOA</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/tomb-annihilation</set>
			<set name="image">https://media.dnd.wizards.com/styles/product_tabletop_left/public/images/product/65DX_ToA_ProductShot.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20170919</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="The Tortle Package" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_SOURCE_THE_TORTLE_PACKAGE">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>The Snout of Omgar is a geographical region described briefly in Tomb of Annihilation.</p><p>Not much is revealed about the location or its inhabitants in that adventure, however. The Tortle Package is written for Dungeon Masters who want to know more about the Snout of Omgar. </p><p>This supplement also introduces a new playable character race, the tortle, and a new adventure location: Dangwaru, the Typhoon Palace. All of this is permissible for play within the D&amp;D Adventurers League.</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">TTP</set>
			<set name="url">https://www.dmsguild.com/product/221716/Tortle-Package-5e</set>
			<set name="image">https://www.dmsguild.com/images/44/221716.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20170915</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>