<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Bard College of the Shadowfell</name>
		<author url="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Kr3ZKYy3Me0ZFOhOQAmKBZlB9JUauhW5/view">Jonoman3000</author>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="bard-college-of-the-shadowfell.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/elements/master/homebrew/jonos-guide-to-homebrew/dark-arts-players-companion/bard-college-of-the-shadowfell.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="name" type="Archetype" source="Dark Arts Player’s Companion" id="ID_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_DIVINE_DOMAIN_NIGHT_DOMAIN">
        <supports>Bard College</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Bards of the College of the Shadowfell specialize in the study of that realm, gleaming great knowledge of shadow magic in the process. These bards are few in number and their study is far harder than most, for knowledge of the Shadowfell is hard to come by. These bards occasionally gather in great libraries to share their knowledge, but most of their time is spent out in the world, looking for any glimpses of knowledge that might lead them to their goal.</p>
            <p class="indent">These bards generally do not perform music, and are instead more inclined to creating stories and manufacturing histories, with most of these stories ending as dark as the realm they study.</p>
            <div element="ID_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_SHADOWFELL_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
            <div element="ID_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_SHADOWFELL_SHADOW_STRIDE" />
            <div element="ID_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_SHADOWFELL_SHROUD_OF_DARKNESS" />
            <div element="ID_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_SHADOWFELL_UMBRAL_BODY" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_SHADOWFELL_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_SHADOWFELL_SHADOW_STRIDE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_SHADOWFELL_SHROUD_OF_DARKNESS" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_SHADOWFELL_UMBRAL_BODY" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="Dark Arts Player’s Companion" id="ID_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_SHADOWFELL_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
        <description>
            <p>When you join the College of the Shadowfell at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with medium armor, martial weapons, and the Stealth skill.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Shadow Stride" type="Archetype Feature" source="Dark Arts Player’s Companion" id="ID_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_SHADOWFELL_SHADOW_STRIDE">
        <description>
            <p>Also at 3rd level, you learn how to empower your ally’s movement within shadows and darkness. When a creature that is in darkness or dim light and has a bardic inspiration die from you begins to move, it can choose to roll that die and add 5 times the number rolled to their speed until the end of their turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When a creature that is in darkness or dim light and has a bardic inspiration die from you begins to move, it can choose to roll that die and add 5 times the number rolled to their speed until the end of their turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Shroud of Darkness" type="Archetype Feature" source="Dark Arts Player’s Companion" id="ID_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_SHADOWFELL_SHROUD_OF_DARKNESS">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 6th level, whenever a creature uses a bardic inspiration die from you, that creature becomes imbued with shadow magic. Shadows envelope that creature until the start of your next turn, causing all attacks against it to have disadvantage and allowing it to disengage or hide as a bonus action for the duration.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever a creature uses a bardic inspiration die from you, that creature becomes imbued with shadow magic. Shadows envelope that creature until the start of your next turn, causing all attacks against it to have disadvantage and allowing it to disengage or hide as a bonus action for the duration.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Umbral Body" type="Archetype Feature" source="Dark Arts Player’s Companion" id="ID_DAPC_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COLLEGE_OF_THE_SHADOWFELL_UMBRAL_BODY">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 14th level, you gain the ability to transform into pure shadow. You can cast <i>umbral form</i> at will, without expending a spell slot or material components. When you cast the spell using this feature, you may only target yourself.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can cast <i>umbral form</i> at will, without expending a spell slot or material components. When you cast the spell using this feature, you may only target yourself.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_DAPC_SPELL_UMBRAL_FORM" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
</elements>