<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Mummy</name>
        <author url="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Kr3ZKYy3Me0ZFOhOQAmKBZlB9JUauhW5/view?usp=sharing">Jonoman3000</author>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="race-mummy.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/elements/master/homebrew/jonos-guide-to-homebrew/dark-arts-players-companion/race-mummy.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Mummy" type="Race" source="Dark Arts Player’s Companion" id="ID_DAPC_RACE_MUMMY">
        <description>
            <p>Hidden within ancient tombs in vast deserts, mummies evoke fear in the heart of every adventurer. Raised by dark funerary rites through necromantic rituals, mummies unquestioningly serve the whims of their masters for as long as they live. However, once those masters are gone a rare few mummies may choose to stray from their ancient tasks, traveling out of their tombs to inflict themselves on the world above.</p>
            <h4>THE WILL OF THE DARK GODS</h4>
            <p>An undead mummy is created when the priest of a death god or other dark deity ritually imbues a prepared corpse with necromantic magic. The mummy’s linen wrappings are inscribed with necromantic markings before the burial ritual concludes with an invocation to darkness. As a mummy endures in undeath, it animates in response to conditions specified by the ritual. Most commonly, a transgression against its tomb, treasures, lands, or former loved ones will cause a mummy to rise.</p>
            <p class="indent">The long burial rituals that accompany a mummy’s entombment help protect its body from rot. In the embalming process, the newly dead creature’s organs are removed and placed in special jars, and its corpse is treated with preserving oils, herbs, and wrappings. After the body has been prepared, the corpse is typically wrapped in linen bandages.</p>
            <h4>THE PUNISHED</h4>
            <p>Once deceased, an individual has no say in whether or not its body is made into a mummy. Some mummies were powerful individuals who displeased a high priest or pharaoh, or who committed crimes of treason, adultery, or murder. As punishment, they were cursed with eternal undeath, embalmed, mummified, and sealed away. Other times, mummies acting as tomb guardians are created from slaves put to death specifically to serve a greater purpose. Once created, a mummy obeys the conditions and parameters laid down by the rituals that created it, driven only to punish transgressors.</p>
            <h4>TIMELESS UNDEATH</h4>
            <p>Most mummies have existed far longer than even the oldest elves, though most of them have remained in their tomb for nearly the entire period. Once they awake, they cannot remember their past life or personality, so they remain dry husks even throughout their eons of “life” if you could call it that.</p>
            <p class="indent">However, some mummies do gain some knowledge of the outside world, and even the most rudimentary knowledge from when they were first created may hold untold secrets to the modern world. As a result, some serve as undead repositories of lost lore, and can be consulted by the descendants of those who created them. Powerful individuals sometimes intentionally sequester mummies away for occasional consultation, and particularly talkative mummies are treasured by historians.</p>
            <h4>MUMMY NAMES</h4>
            <p>When they are created, mummies are not often named, and they have no memory of their name in life. Even when they are named, it is usually something extremely simple such as a number. However, once a mummy becomes free of its master, it might choose to give itself a real name, or perhaps let a troop of adventurers choose its name for it. Therefore, mummies can have all types of names based on what names they have encountered. If they have encountered many human adventurers in their time, they may choose a human name, and could do the same for any of the other races.</p>
            <h4>MUMMY TRAITS</h4>
            <p>As a mummy, you have certain traits that you share with other mummies. As a mummy you gain access to powerful magic through your rotting curse and dreadful glare, though both of these magics have been weakened through the death of your master and your departure from the tomb.
                <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span>Your Strength score increases by 2, and your Constitution score increases by 1.<br />
                <span class="feature">Age.</span>As beings of undeath, mummies do not age or mature, and they may live for thousands of years if undisturbed.<br />
                <span class="feature">Alignment.</span>As the creations of evil masters, mummies are often evil themselves. Most often mummies tend towards lawfulness in their devotion to their master.<br />
                <span class="feature">Size.</span>Mummies are between 5 and 6 feet tall and average about 120 pounds. Your size is medium.<br />
                <span class="feature">Speed.</span>Your base walking speed is 25 feet.<br />        
                <span class="feature">Darkvision.</span>Accustomed to the eternal darkness of an ancient tomb, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of grey.<br />
                <span class="feature">Dreadful Glare.</span>As an action, you can target one creature you can see within 10 feet of you. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become frightened of you until the end of your next turn. The DC for this saving throw equals 8 + your Constitution modifier + your Proficiency bonus.<br />After you use your glare, you can’t use it again until you complete a short or long rest.<br />
                <span class="feature">Rotting Fist.</span>Your hands rot those they touch. When you make unarmed attacks against creatures with them, you deal necrotic damage equal to 1d4 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed attack.<br />
                <span class="feature">Undead.</span>You are considered undead for effects such as turn undead and many healing spells. You are immune to disease and the poisoned condition, and you have resistance to poison damage. You do not need to eat or breathe, but you can ingest food or drink if you wish. Instead of sleeping, you enter an inactive state for 4 hours each day. You do not dream in this state, but resting in this way is otherwise identical to sleeping. Magically induced sleep can cause you to enter this inactive state.<br />
                <span class="feature">Languages.</span>You can speak, read, and write Common and one other language you knew in life.<br />      
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <setters>
            <set name="names" type="male"></set>
            <set name="names" type="female"></set>
            <set name="names" type="clan"></set>
            <set name="names-format">{{name}} {{clan}}</set>
            <set name="height" modifier="2d10">4’8"</set>
            <set name="weight" modifier="2d4">110 lb.</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="strength" value="2" />
            <stat name="constitution" value="1" />
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
            <stat name="innate speed" value="25" bonus="base" />
            <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_DAPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_MUMMY_DREADFUL_GLARE" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_DAPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_MUMMY_ROTTING_FIST" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_DAPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_MUMMY_UNDEAD" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
            <select type="Language" name="Language (Mummy)" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    

    <element name="Dreadful Glare" type="Racial Trait" source="Dark Arts Player’s Companion" id="ID_DAPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_MUMMY_DREADFUL_GLARE">
        <description>
            <p>As an action, you can target one creature you can see within 10 feet of you. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become frightened of you until the end of your next turn. The DC for this saving throw equals 8 + your Constitution modifier + your Proficiency bonus.</p>
            <p class="indent">After you use your glare, you can’t use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
            <description>You can target one creature you can see within 10 feet. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (save DC = {{dreadful-glare:dc}}) or become frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="dreadful-glare:dc" value="8" />
            <stat name="dreadful_glare:dc" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="dreadful_glare:dc" value="constitution:modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Rotting Fist" type="Racial Trait" source="Dark Arts Player’s Companion" id="ID_DAPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_MUMMY_ROTTING_FIST">
        <description>
            <p>Your hands rot those they touch. When you make unarmed attacks against creatures with them, you deal necrotic damage equal to 1d4 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed attack.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your unarmed attacks do 1d4 + {{strength:modifier}} necrotic damage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Undead" type="Racial Trait" source="Dark Arts Player’s Companion" id="ID_DAPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_MUMMY_UNDEAD">
        <description>
            <p>You are considered undead for effects such as turn undead and many healing spells. You are immune to disease and the poisoned condition, and you have resistance to poison damage. You do not need to eat or breathe, but you can ingest food or drink if you wish. Instead of sleeping, you enter an inactive state for 4 hours each day. You do not dream in this state, but resting in this way is otherwise identical to sleeping. Magically induced sleep can cause you to enter this inactive state.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You are considered undead for effects such as turn undead and many healing spells. You are immune to disease and the poisoned condition, and you have resistance to poison damage. You do not need to eat or breathe, but you can ingest food or drink if you wish. Instead of sleeping, you enter an inactive state for 4 hours each day. You do not dream in this state, but resting in this way is otherwise identical to sleeping. Magically induced sleep can cause you to enter this inactive state.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

</elements>