<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Shadar-Kai</name>
        <author url="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1Kr3ZKYy3Me0ZFOhOQAmKBZlB9JUauhW5/view?usp=sharing">Jonoman3000</author>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="race-shadar-kai.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/chris-velox/elements/master/homebrew/jonos-guide-to-homebrew/dark-arts-players-companion/race-shadar-kai.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Shadar-Kai" type="Race" source="Dark Arts Player’s Companion" id="ID_DAPC_RACE_SHADARKAI">
        <description>
            <p>Shadar-kai were once humans, native to the world. They were all members of an extended tribe who called themselves Shadar-Kai. These early humans had seen the abuses Nerull, once god of death, perpetrated on the souls who passed into his power. They also feared the unknowable reaches of death into which most souls pass even now. When the Raven Queen slew Nerull and ascended to godhood, in an age now largely forgotten, the Shadar-Kai struck a deal with her. They promised to serve as her mortal agents, and in exchange, she gave them incredibly long life and freedom from frailty. The shadar-kai believe that, through their pact, they became the chosen people of death and winter.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Shadar-Kai moved to the Shadowfell, setting up their communities on the borders of Letherna, the Raven Queen’s domain. Life in shadow changed the humans, reshaping them and altering their appearance. Eventually, they were so different from humans that they became a distinct species. As they expanded their territory in the Shadowfell and began interacting again with the mortal world, the tribal name became the name for their race.</p>
            <h4>ASHEN AND SCARRED</h4>
            <p>Shadar-kai are humanlike, but the weight of existence in the Shadowfell has shaped them to be slightly shorter and much thinner than their human counterparts. A shadar-kai has a colorless complexion that varies from alabaster to dark gray. Shadar-kai hair is similarly drab or raven black. Pale hair might have a hint of color within the range of human norms. The eyes are lustrous and black, lacking any white or clear pupil. Shadows near a shadar-kai sometimes seem to reach out or deepen, especially when the shadar-kai is angry.</p>
            <p class="indent">Although drab in natural appearance, shadar-kai are quite elaborate and idiosyncratic in personal adornment. They like dark and exotic clothing, jewelry, and weapons, often decorated with swatches of bright color. Hair is similarly ornate and often dyed, and many embellish their skin with tattoos, scars, and piercings.</p>
            <p class="indent">The tattoos, scars, and piercings a shadar-kai wears have more than one purpose. They exist as a testament to the wearer’s ability to withstand pain as well as a means of personal expression and decoration. Each decoration can also be a record of a deed done, an honor gained, or a misdeed declared.</p>
            <h4>THE RAVEN QUEEN</h4>
            <p>Through their pact with the Raven Queen, each shadar-kai is aninstrument of death and fate. The Raven Queen doesn’t demandworship from the shadar-kai, although she receives it inabundance. She demands only that they observe the pact bykeeping her commandments regardless of other beliefs. So mostshadar-kai hold no pity for the dying and try to punish those whodefy fate. But shadar-kai also believe that nobody truly knowswhat fate holds.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Raven Queen is a fair mother, if not a loving one. When the shadar-kai called upon her in ancient times, she answered. She still does. While she spares little love, she also never demands the love of her children. Almost all shadar-kai revere the Raven Queen, but each shadar-kai is free to choose his or her destiny and way of life, including religion.</p>
            <h4>STRONG EMOTIONS</h4>
            <p>The Shadowfell saps living creatures of creativity and the will to live. When shadar-kai moved to the Shadowfell ages ago, they were not immune to this depression. Numerous members of their early society gave in to ennui and simply slipped out of existence, driving the shadar-kai to change their lifestyle, embracing strong emotions and peak experiences. These practices, born out of necessity, became traditions over countless generations.</p>
            <p class="indent">The current culture of the shadar-kai is a study in pushing boundaries. Shadar-kai welcome difficult tasks, as well asphysical and emotional extremes, as a way of life. They learn to channel the darkness of the Shadowfell rather than allowing that darkness to consume them. And they accept death as the inevitable end for those who fail to attain the right amount of power or fame.</p>
            <p class="indent">Shadar-kai embrace living with gusto. The limits of pleasure and pain distract them from the wearying melancholy of the Shadowfell. They also strive for personal greatness, so that if they fail to gain the actual ability to live forever, stories of their great deeds will grant a sort of immortality. In this search for personal glory, most shadar-kai ignore banalities such as comfort, morality, and safety.</p>
            <h4>CALL OF THE SHADOWFELL</h4>
            <p>Although shadar-kai leave the Shadowfell to seek fortune in the world and among the planes, a few needs and wants drive a shadar-kai to return home from time to time. Most shadar-kai feela basic need to visit the enveloping dimness of the Shadowfell at least intermittently. The plane is unlike even the darkest reaches of other planes. Obtaining new adornments and equipment in the proper style often requires a return to the Shadowfell. Shadar-kai also return to their gloomy settlements to spend time among those who see extreme, weird, or even deviant as normal. And they come home to brag.</p>
            <h4>SHADAR-KAI NAMES</h4>
            <p>Shadar-kai have similar names to their human counterparts, though they did change slightly due to their isolation in the Shadowfell, with the only real influencing force being the will of the Raven Queen. Their names are often merely the inventions of their parents, though some common names do exist.</p>
            <p>
                <span class="emphasis">Male names:</span> Albrek, Baden, Codren, Emul, Horiam, Hutahn, Ioan, Lucyan, Mahahn, Niku, ovid, Petru, Razvahn, Serbahn, Shathys, Teodahr, Vasylay, Zahar.<br />
                <span class="emphasis">Female names:</span> Afyn, Anka, Bahnka, Codruta, Doru, Dyon, Floahr, Ghita, Helayna, Ioana, Jenit, Katryn, Lucya, Markella, Nadya, Roduka, Sahyeh, Tabita, Yalda, Zyna<br />
            </p>
            <h4>SHADAR-KAI TRAITS</h4>
            <p>The weight of existence in the Shadowfell has shaped the physical qualities of the Shadar-kai, granting them traits unique to their native realm.</p>
            <p>
                <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span> Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Intelligence score increases by 1.<br />
                <span class="feature">Age.</span> The Shadar-kai reach physical maturity at the same rate as humans, but they generally live far longer. A shadar-kai may live up to 800 years.<br />
                <span class="feature">Alignment.</span> Shadar-kai society is often seen as cruel and apathetic. The shadar-kai generally strive to create chaos and death, bringing death for both purposes of evil as well as good.<br />
                <span class="feature">Size.</span> Shadar-kai are generally a tad below 6 feet in height and they weigh between 110 and 170 pounds. Your size is medium.<br />
                <span class="feature">Speed. </span>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.<br />
                <span class="feature">Superior Darkvision.</span> Accustomed to the black skies and eternal shadow of the Shadowfell, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 120 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of grey.<br />
                <span class="feature">Doomspeaker.</span> You gain proficiency in the Intimidation skill.<br />
                <span class="feature">Shadow Jaunt.</span> On your turn, when you reduce a creature to 0 hit points, you can use your bonus action to teleport up to 15 feet.<br />
                <span class="feature">Languages.</span> You can speak, read, and write Common and one other language of your choice.<br />
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <setters>
            <set name="names" type="male">Albrek, Baden, Codren, Emul, Horiam, Hutahn, Ioan, Lucyan, Mahahn, Niku, ovid, Petru, Razvahn, Serbahn, Shathys, Teodahr, Vasylay, Zahar</set>
            <set name="names" type="female">Afyn, Anka, Bahnka, Codruta, Doru, Dyon, Floahr, Ghita, Helayna, Ioana, Jenit, Katryn, Lucya, Markella, Nadya, Roduka, Sahyeh, Tabita, Yalda, Zyna</set>
            <set name="names" type="clan"></set>
            <set name="names-format">{{name}}</set>
            <set name="height" modifier="2d10">4’8"</set>
            <set name="weight" modifier="2d4">110 lb.</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <stat name="dexterity" value="2" />
            <stat name="intelligence" value="1" />
            <stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
            <select type="Language" name="Language (Shadar-Kai)" />
    		<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_SUPERIORDARKVISION" />

            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_DAPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_SHADAR_KAI_SHADOW_JAUNT" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Shadow Jaunt" type="Racial Trait" source="Dark Arts Player’s Companion" id="ID_DAPC_RACIAL_TRAIT_SHADAR_KAI_SHADOW_JAUNT">
        <description>
            <p>On your turn, when you reduce a creature to 0 hit points, you can use your bonus action to teleport up to 15 feet.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>When you reduce a creature to 0 hit points, you can teleport up to 15 feet.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>