<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Feats</name>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="feats.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/homebrew/reddit/arcane-artillery/feats.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<element name="Akimbo Master" type="Feat" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_FEAT_AKIMBO_MASTER" >
		<requirements />
		<description>
			<p>You master the art of wielding two ranged weapons at once. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You can draw or holster two sidearms when you would normally be able to draw or holster only one.</li>
				<li>If you are wielding two ranged weapons with the loading property, you can ignore the loading property for those weapons, and do not need a free hand to reload them.</li>
				<li>You can wield two one-handed ranged weapons at once, even if they do not have the light property.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
				You may draw or holster two sidearms instead of one, you may ignore the loading property and not need a free hand to reload two wielded ranged weapons, and you may wield two one-handed ranged weapons even if they do not have the light property.
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Archaic Gunmaster" type="Feat" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_FEAT_ARCHAIC_GUNMASTER" >
		<requirements />
		<prerequisite>Primitive and Misfire Rules implemented</prerequisite>
		<description>
			<p>You have become well trained with primitive firearms. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>When you make more than two attacks with a primitive firearm during your turn, the firearm's misfire count does not increase by 1.</li>
				<li>These weapons only misfire for you if you roll a 1, regardless of its misfire number.</li>
				<li>Ignore the loading property for non-heavy firearms.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
				You may make more than two attacks with a primitive firearms without the firearm's misfire count increasing, these weapons only misfire if you roll a 1, and you may ignore the loading property for non-heavy firearms.
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Gunmaster" type="Feat" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_FEAT_GUNMASTER" >
		<requirements />
		<description>
			<p>You are a veritable master with guns, and gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Ignore the loading property for non-heavy firearms.</li>
				<li>If you are disarmed, you can use your reaction to draw and fire a light sidearm.</li>
				<li>Increase the normal range of all firearms you wield by 10.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
				You may ignore the loading property for non-heavy firearms, if you are disarmed you may use your reaction to draw and fire a light sidearm, and all the normal ranges for firearms you wield is increased by 10.
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Bayoneteer" type="Feat" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_FEAT_BAYONETEER" >
		<requirements>ID_RDDT_AA_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIDEARMS|ID_RDDT_AA_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGARMS</requirements>
		<prerequisite>Proficiency in firearms</prerequisite>
		<description>
			<p>You have mastered the art of fighting with weapons attached to the barrel of your gun. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You gain a +1 bonus to damage rolls with bayonets.</li>
				<li>You gain proficiency in improvised weapons.</li>
				<li>Firearms with bayonets attached gain a reach of 10 feet.</li>
				<li>When you take the attack action with a firearm that has a bayonet attached to it, you can use a bonus action to make a melee attack with the bayonet at a creature within 5 feet of you.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
				You have +1 to damage rolls with bayonets, you gain proficiency in improvised weapons, firearms with bayonets gain a reach of 10 feet, and when you make an attack with a firearm that has an attached bayonet, you may use your bonus action to make a melee attack against a creature within 5 feet of you.
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<!-- todo: improvised weapon proficiency -->
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Buccaneer" type="Feat" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_FEAT_BUCCANEER" >
		<requirements />
		<description>
			<p>You have mastered the art of dueling with gun and sword, and gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>When you use the attack action with a one-handed melee weapon, you can spend a bonus action to fire a light firearm you wield in your other hand. You can use this bonus action to attack with a one handed melee weapon if you use your attack action with a light firearm.</li>
				<li>While wielding a light firearm and a one-handed melee weapon, you gain a +1 bonus to your AC.</li>
				<li>Ignore the loading time and reload action for light firearms. You do not need a free hand to load in the ammunition.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
				When wielding a one-handed melee weapon and a light firearm, after attacking with one you may use your bonus action to attack with the other, and you gain +1 bonus to your AC. You may also ignore the loading time and reload action for light firearms, you do not need a free hand to load.
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<!-- todo: implement +1 AC when wielding correct weapons -->
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Close Quarters Shooter" type="Feat" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_FEAT_CLOSE_QUARTERS_SHOOTER" >
		<requirements />
		<description>
			<p>You have trained yourself in the delicate art of using ranged weapons in close quarters combat. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Making an attack with a ranged weapon while within 5 feet of a hostile creature does not impose disadvantage on the attack roll.</li>
				<li>You cannot make a ranged attack roll with disadvantage at any target within 30 feet of you. However, if you would normally have disadvantage when making an attack roll within this range, such as a magical effect or obscured vision, you cannot get advantage on the attack roll either.</li>
				<li>You can make opportunity attacks with ranged weapons. The reach for these attacks is 15 feet.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
				You do not have disadvantage when making ranged attacks at 5 feet, you never suffer disadvantage when making ranged attacks within 30 feet, if you would have disadvantage, you are instead prevented from having advantage. You may also make opportunity attacks with ranged weapons at a range of 15 feet.
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Gunsmith Initiate" type="Feat" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_FEAT_GUNSMITH_INITATE" >
		<requirements>[int:13],ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_TINKERS_TOOLS|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_SMITHS_TOOLS</requirements>
		<prerequisite>Intelligence 13, proficiency in smith's tools or tinker's tools</prerequisite>
		<description>
			<p>Your proficiency bonus is doubled in tinker's tools and/or smith's tools, and you can now craft primitive firearms. You are assumed to have gotten the materials for the firearm you wish to craft before you took this feat. You craft these guns at a rate of 5gp per hour.</p><p class="indent">If firearms are common in your world, you can craft firearms as well as primitive firearms.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
				Your proficiency bonus is doubled in tinker's tools and/or smith's tools, and you can now craft primitive firearms. You are assumed to have gotten the materials for the firearm you wish to craft before you took this feat. You craft these guns at a rate of 5gp per hour.
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Gunsmith Adept" type="Feat" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_FEAT_GUNSMITH_ADEPT" >
		<requirements>ID_RDDT_AA_FEAT_GUNSMITH_INITATE,[level:12]</requirements>
		<prerequisite>Gunsmith Initiage, player level 12</prerequisite>
		<description>
			<p>You have gone through extensive training in gunsmithing, letting you create new firearms via experimenting. You can now create firearms, found on the chart above. You can craft special firearms, as well as Attachments and Custom Parts, if it is appropriate for your setting (such as if firearms are prominent). Once per long rest, you can make an Intelligence check with your proficiency bonus added once you complete a short rest. If you succeed, you manage to craft the blueprints for the gun or parts. If you fail, the DC goes down by 1 for subsequent checks (Minimum of 10).</p>
			<p>When the blueprints are created, you can then make the gun or parts. It is assumed that during your travels you came across the required materials to make these items before you took this feat. You craft these items at a rate of 5gp per hour, and can now craft primitive firearms at a rate of 10gp per hour.</p>
			<p>The cost to craft primitive firearms is now cut in half for you (rounded up).</p>
			<p>You can now reduce a primitive firearm's misfire number to a minimum of 1, regardless of its original misfire number.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>
			
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Mounted Shooting" type="Feat" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_FEAT_MOUNTED_SHOOTING" >
		<requirements />
		<description>
			<p>You wield guns with deadly efficiency on mounts. While you are mounted and aren't incapacitated, you gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You get a +1 bonus to attack rolls with firearms while mounted.</li>
				<li>Being within 5 feet of a hostile creature when making an attack roll with firearms while mounted does not impose disadvantage on the attack roll as long as the creature's size is smaller than your mount.</li>
				<li>You have advantage on attacks rolls against any unmounted creature smaller than your mount within your firearm's normal range.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
				While mounted and not incapacitated you get +1 bonus to attack rolls with firearms, you have no disadvantage when using a firearm to attack an enemy that is within 5 feet so long as the enemy is smaller than your mount and you have advantage on attack rolls against any unmounted creature smaller than your mount within your firearm's normal range.
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
		
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Pistol Whipper" type="Feat" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_FEAT_PISTOL_WHIPPER" >
		<requirements />
		<description>
			<p>You are skilled in using guns as melee weapons when and if they run out of bullets. You increase your Strength or Dexterity ability score by 1, to a maximum of 20, and are now considered proficient with firearms you use as melee weapons. The damage die for these firearms is as follows: sidearms are d6, and they are considered finesse weapons, longarms are d8, and heavy longarms are d10. The damage type for these attacks is bludgeoning.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
				You are proficient when using a firearm as a melee weapon. Sidearms are d6 and finesse, longarms are d8 and heavy longarms are d10. They all deal bludgeoning damage.
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Pistol Whipper" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_DEXTERITY" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Rifle Master" type="Feat" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_FEAT_RIFLE_MASTER" >
		<requirements />
		<description>
			<p>Rifles are complex weapons, but you know just how to make every shot count. You gain the following benefits when wielding a rifle, carbine, or a musket and wheellock gun with the rifling property:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You gain a +1 bonus to damage rolls with these weapons.</li>
				<li>You can reroll 1s and 2s to damage with these weapons.</li>
				<li>If you roll a critical hit or deal a killing blow with these weapons, you can use your reaction to take an additional shot at a creature within 10 feet of the creature hit.</li>
				<li>The normal range of these weapons increases by 10, and the long range increases by 30.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
				While wielding weapons with the rifling property you gain +1 damage, 1s and 2s to damage may be rerolled, scoring a critical hit allows you to use your reaction to make a second attack against another creature within 10 feet of the first creature, and the range for these weapons increases by 10/30.
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
		
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Scattershot Master" type="Feat" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_FEAT_SCATTERSHOT_MASTER" >
		<requirements />
		<description>
			<p>You have mastered getting the most effect out of firearms with the scatter property. You get the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You gain a +1 to attack rolls with these weapons</li>
				<li>Your scattershot damage can target any creature of your choosing within the scatter range of your target.</li>
				<li>You can reroll 1s and 2s to your scatter damage.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
				When wielding weapons with the scattershot property you gain +1 to attack rolls, your scattershot damage can target any creature of your choosing within the scatter range of your target, and you may reroll 1s and 2s to scatter damage.
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
		
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Sidearm Master" type="Feat" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_FEAT_SIDEARM_MASTER" >
		<requirements />
		<description>
			<p>You have mastered the art of wielding a sidearm with delicate precision. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls made with these weapons.</li>
				<li>When you take the attack action with a sidearm can use a bonus action to make an attack roll at a creature within 10 feet of you.</li>
				<li>When you roll initiative and are not surprised, you can use your reaction to draw a sidearm and attack a creature within its normal range.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
				When wielding a sidearm you gain +1 to attack rolls, when you use the attack action you may use a bonus action to make an attack roll at a creature within 10 feet of you, and when you roll initiative and are not surprise you may use your reaction to draw a sidearm and make an attack at a creature within its normal range.
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
		
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Six-Gun Ace" type="Feat" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_FEAT_SIX-GUN_ACE" >
		<requirements />
		<description>
			<p>You have perfected the art of shooting with your revolver or hand cannon. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls with these weapons.</li>
				<li>You cannot be disarmed while wielding a revolver or hand cannon in one hand and your other hand is free.</li>
				<li>When you make an attack with your revolver or hand cannon and are not holding anything in your other hand, you can use your bonus action to make two additional attacks against creatures within its normal range. You do not add your ability score modifier to the damage of these attacks, unless that modifier is negative.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
				While wielding a revolver or hand cannon you gain +1 to attack rolls, you cannot be disarmed while your other hand is free, and when you make an attack you may use your bonus action to make two additional attacks against creatures within its normal range. You do not add your ability score modifier to the damage of these attacks, unless that modifier is negative.
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
		
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Superior Marksman" type="Feat" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_FEAT_SUPERIOR_MARKSMAN" >
		<requirements />
		<description>
			<p>You have perfected the art of the slow, steady kill. You gain the following benefits when wielding a ranged weapon with the bulky property:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You gain a +1 to attack rolls with these weapons.</li>
				<li>You can use a bonus action to steady your aim. You can then make an attack roll that can neither have advantage or disadvantage. On a hit, deal double the weapon’s damage die.</li>
				<li>If you make a ranged attack roll with advantage, you can reroll one of the attack rolls once.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
				When wielding ranged weapons with the bulky property you gain +1 to attack rolls, you may use a bonus action to make an attack without advantage or disadvantage and on a hit deal double damage, and if you make an attack with advantage you may reroll one of the attack rolls once.
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Suppressive Fire" type="Feat" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_FEAT_SUPPRESSIVE_FIRE" >
		<requirements />
		<description>
			<p>When you have a firearm with the automatic or burst fire property drawn, you can use an action to suppress a field of fire within a 10 foot radius at any point within your weapon's normal range. This ability expends a number of bullets equal to half your firearm's total reload count when used. You cannot take bonus actions if you take this action. You must have at least half your gun's reload count loaded into your weapon to use this ability. When you use this ability, you gain the following benefits until the beginning of your next turn.</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Creatures within the area have disadvantage on attack rolls and Dexterity Saving Throws.</li>
				<li>Creatures within the area can only move at half speed and cannot Dash.</li>
				<li>If any creatures move or take an action within the area or moves into its area for the first time, you can make an attack against them. You can make this attack for a number of times equal to half your proficiency bonus. You cannot make this attack at the same creature more than once. This attack does not expend ammunition.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
				When wielding a firearm with the automatic or burst fire property and at least half of the gun's reload count loaded you may use your action to lay down suppressive fire in a 10 foot radius within your weapon's normal range. This consumes half your reload count in ammo and prevents you from taking bonus actions. Until the start of your next turn creatures in the area have disadvantage on attack rolls and Dex saving throws, they can only move at half speed and cannot dash, and if they take an action or move into the area you may make an attack against them. You can make this attack an equal number of times to half your proficiency bonus. You cannot make this attack against the same creature more than once and this attack does not consume ammunition.
			</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Tricky" type="Feat" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_FEAT_TRICKY" >
		<requirements />
		<description>
			<p>You have trained in a performance art with firearms that allows you to use special tricks during combat. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You learn two tricks of your choice from among those available to the Virtuoso Archetype in the gunslinger class. If a trick requires your target to make a saving throw to resist the trick's effects, the saving throw DC equals 8 + your proficiency modifier + your Dexterity modifier.</li>
				<li>If you already have superiority dice, you gain two more, otherwise, you have two superiority dice. These are used to fuel your tricks. A superiority die is expended when you use it. You regain your expended superiority dice when you finish a short or long rest.</li>
				<li>If a trick's effect includes a modifier that equals your Gunslinger level, you instead treat that modifier as equal to your highest class level instead.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You learn tricks that are fueled by special dice called superiority dice. You have {{superiority dice:amount}} superiority dice which are d{{superiority dice:size}}s. DC {{superiority dice:dc}}</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="superiority dice:amount" value="2" />
			<stat name="superiority dice:size" value="8" bonus="size"/>
			<stat name="superiority dice:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="superiority dice:dc" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="superiority dice:dc:ability" value="dexterity:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
			<stat name="superiority dice:dc" value="superiority dice:dc:ability" />
			<select name="Tricky" type="Archetype Feature" supports="Virtuoso Tricks" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
</elements>