<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Gunslinger</name>
		<update version="0.0.3">
			<file name="gunslinger.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/homebrew/reddit/arcane-artillery/gunslinger.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<!-- gunslinger -->
	<element name="Gunslinger" type="Class" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_GUNSLINGER">
		<description>
			<p>A Human finishes loading rounds into her gun and and runs straight into a pack of angry kobolds that are threatening her town. She tumbles and spins, her weapon burping out salvo after salvo of hot lead against the poorly armed draconians with naught but simple spears to use against her.</p>
			<p class="indent">Setting his perch up at the top of a tree, a Half Elf begins to train the custom built sights of his homemade rifle on his prize. Amidst the roaming herd of goblins and hobgoblins, there stands a single, massive fire giant shouting commands to the monsters near the edge of a cliff. As he lets out a haughty guffaw, the half-elf sees his opening. His lips curl into a grin, and he pulls the trigger.</p>
			<p class="indent">The sound of rapid clops echoes across the battlefield. A group of goblins tries to close in on a tiefling and her horse. One of them throws a bomb at her horses feet, but in a flash, the horse and its rider suddenly dart to the side, and the bomb explodes among the crowd of pursuers instead, leaving the tiefling unharmed.</p>
			<p class="indent">A half orc examines a strange puzzle before him, holstering his gun after checking that the coast is clear. He looks befuddled at it for a moment, before shrugging and messing around with it. With a click, the puzzle opens, and the half-orc smiles a giddy smile.</p>
			<p class="indent">Whether outlaws from a distant land trying to redeem themselves, swashbucklers with an eye for the explosive, or smiths that wish to show off their talents to the world in the heat of battle, gunslingers come from many backgrounds, but all have one thing in common. They’re all very good with guns, and use unique fighting styles and speed to strike down any foe that challenges them with less advanced weaponry.</p>
			<h4>USING UNIQUE WEAPONS WITH STYLE</h4>
			<p>Though this is heavily dependent on the adventure being run, guns are considered very rare in most adventures, and few know how to operate them. Their exotic nature can lead to confusion and panic among those at the business end of these tools. Gunslingers take advantage of this and combine the usage of these guns with a stylistic grace and speed very few can comprehend. A Gunslinger will hone their skills with these distributors of supersonic lead death and become nearly impossible to track as they strike targets with nearly impossible shots.</p>
			<h4>BORN FOR ADVENTURE</h4>
			<p>Most adventurers seek adventure out. Others have it thrust upon them. Gunslingers seem to have been born with a natural affinity and curiosity for exploration and dealing with the problems out in the wild. You'll find them at the job board before any paladin or fighter, and they'll be eager to take on the challenges of the darkest and most dangerous dungeons. The more challenging the encounter, the greater use they'll get out of their pride and joy.</p>
			<h4>CREATING A GUNSLINGER</h4>
			<p>When creating a gunslinger, consider two major things. Firstly, consider how rare guns are in the adventure your DM is running, and then consider how your character came across their knowledge of how to make and use them? Did they have a eureka moment in a time of renaissance? Did they train with a mentor before deciding to go on their own path? Or did they form a pact with a dark entity for this knowledge? Either way, their background should lead them to come across these deadly tools for use in their adventures.</p>
			<h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
			<p>To quickly build a gunslinger, make Dexterity your highest ability score. Secondly, choose an ability score of your choice to be the second highest. This could be Constitution if you want a hardier gunslinger with more health, Charisma if you want a fast talking slinger that can play a mean tune, Intelligence if you want a gunslinger that's well learned and booksmart, or Wisdom if you want a worldy and perceptive master of firearms. Lastly, choose the Folk Hero background.</p>
			<h3>CLASS FEATURES</h3>
			<p>As a Gunslinger, you get the following class features.</p>
			<h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
			<p>
				<span class="emphasis">Hit Dice:</span> 1d8 per gunslinger level<br />
				<span class="emphasis">Hit Points at 1st Level:</span> 8 + your Constitution modifier<br />
				<span class="emphasis">Hit Points at Higher Levels:</span> 1d8 (or 5) + your Constitution modifier per gunslinger level after 1st
			<br />
			</p>
			<h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
			<p>
				<span class="emphasis">Armor:</span> Light armor, medium armor, shields<br />
				<span class="emphasis">Weapons:</span> Longarms, sidearms, simple weapons, crossbows, shortswords, scimitars, rapiers, whips<br />
				<span class="emphasis">Tools:</span>A  vehicle or musical instrument of your choice
			</p>
			<p>
				<span class="emphasis">Saving Throws:</span> Dexterity, Charisma<br />
				<span class="emphasis">Skills:</span> Choose two from Arcana, Acrobatics, Animal Handling, History, Insight, Intimidation, Investigation, Perception, Performance, Persuasion, Sleight of Hand, or Survival
			</p>
			<h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
			<p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
			<ul>
				<li> <i>(a)</i> scale mail or <i>(b)</i> leather, a flintlock pistol and 10 musketballs</li>
				<li> <i>(a)</i> a wheellock gun and 20 musketballs, <i>(b)</i> a blunderbuss and 20 spreadshot rounds, or <i>(c)</i> a pepperbox and 20 musketballs</li>
				<li> <i>(a)</i> two simple weapons, <i>(b)</i> a flintlock pistol and 10 musketballs, or <i>(c)</i> a shield</li>
				<li> <i>(a)</i>a dungeoneer's pack, <i>(b)</i> an explorer's pack, or <i>(c)</i> a scholar's pack</li>
			</ul>
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_THE_TONGUE" />
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_QUICKDRAW" />
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_GUN_STUNTS" />
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_KNACK" />
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_FIGHTING_STYLE" />
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_SLINGERS_TRAIL" />
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_LUCKY_ITEM" />
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT" />
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_BULLET_TIME" />
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_EVASION" />
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_SHOOTOUT_SENSE" />
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_OVERWATCH" />
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_FINAL_STAND" />
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_SUPERHUMAN_REFLEXES" />
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_GUNSLINGING_SUPREME" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>A master of firearms, showing their power with skill and style.</description>
		</sheet>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">A master of firearms, showing their power with skill and style.</set>
			<set name="hd">d8</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_RDDT_AA_GRANTS_ARCANEARTILLERY_REQUIREMENT" />

			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_RDDT_AA_MULTICLASS_GUNSLINGER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_RDDT_AA_MULTICLASS_GUNSLINGER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" requirements="!ID_RDDT_AA_MULTICLASS_GUNSLINGER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_RDDT_AA_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGARMS" requirements="!ID_RDDT_AA_MULTICLASS_GUNSLINGER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_RDDT_AA_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIDEARMS" requirements="!ID_RDDT_AA_MULTICLASS_GUNSLINGER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_RDDT_AA_MULTICLASS_GUNSLINGER"  />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_INTERNAL_PROFICIENCY_GROUP_CROSSBOWS" requirements="!ID_RDDT_AA_MULTICLASS_GUNSLINGER"  />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SHORTSWORD" requirements="!ID_RDDT_AA_MULTICLASS_GUNSLINGER"  />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SCIMITAR" requirements="!ID_RDDT_AA_MULTICLASS_GUNSLINGER"  />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_RAPIER" requirements="!ID_RDDT_AA_MULTICLASS_GUNSLINGER"  />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_WHIP" requirements="!ID_RDDT_AA_MULTICLASS_GUNSLINGER"  />
			
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency (Gunslinger)" supports="(Tool,Vehicles)||Musical Instrument" number="1" requirements="!ID_RDDT_AA_MULTICLASS_GUNSLINGER"  />
			
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY" requirements="!ID_RDDT_AA_MULTICLASS_GUNSLINGER"  />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_CHARISMA"  requirements="!ID_RDDT_AA_MULTICLASS_GUNSLINGER" />
			
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Gunslinger)" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" number="2"  requirements="!ID_RDDT_AA_MULTICLASS_GUNSLINGER" />
			
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_THE_TONGUE" level="1"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_QUICKDRAW" level="1"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_GUN_STUNTS" level="1"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_KNACK" level="2"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_FIGHTING_STYLE" level="2"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_SLINGERS_TRAIL" level="3"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_LUCKY_ITEM" level="3"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT" level="4"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_BULLET_TIME" level="6"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_EVASION" level="7"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_SHOOTOUT_SENSE" level="11"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_OVERWATCH" level="14"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_FINAL_STAND" level="15"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_SUPERHUMAN_REFLEXES" level="18"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_GUNSLINGING_SUPREME" level="20"/>	
		</rules>
		<multiclass id="ID_RDDT_AA_MULTICLASS_GUNSLINGER">
			<prerequisite>Dexterity 13, Charisma 13</prerequisite>
			<requirements>[dex:13],[cha:13]</requirements>
			<setters>
				<set name="multiclass proficiencies">Light armor, longarms, sidearms, and one vehicle of your choice</set>
			</setters>
			<rules>
				<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_RDDT_AA_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_LONGARMS" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_RDDT_AA_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIDEARMS" />
				<select type="Proficiency" name="Gunslinger Multiclass" supports="(Tool,Vehicles)" number="1" />
			</rules>
		</multiclass>
	</element>
	<element name="The Tongue" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_THE_TONGUE">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 1st level, you learn an ancient and ritualized language, practiced often by gunslingers and certain secretive societies of old. It is a deliberate and ritualized code of speech patterns and dialect, each syllable containing complex nuances and multiple meanings. Nowadays, only gunslingers and certain guilds opened by the people of the past still know and actively teach this language. This language can only be understood by those that know the tongue.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, you understand and can write in a set of ancient symbols and written jargon that conveys the messages of the tongue in deceptively short inscriptions. This writing is generally used to tell stories or to write down spells and rituals, and books containing the tongue are treasures often sought out by linguists and wizards alike due to the potential of finding lost magic or rich historical lore contained within in their text.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>It is a deliberate and ritualized code of speech patterns and dialect, each syllable containing complex nuances and multiple meanings.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Quickdraw" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_QUICKDRAW">
		<description>
			<p>Also at 1st level, your hands are fast as lightning in a shootout. You can stow one weapon and/or draw another as part of your movement or action before needing to take the Use Object action. Additionally, you do not need a free hand to reload weapons with the loading property.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can stow one weapon and/or draw another as part of your movement or action before needing to take the Use Object action and you do not need a free hand to reload weapons with the loading property.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Gun Stunts" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_GUN_STUNTS">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 1st level, you have developed a set of stunts you can use to give you an edge in combat. You gain the following options:</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Run ‘N Gun.</em></strong> You can use Dash as a bonus action.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Slinger’s Senses.</em></strong> You can make a Wisdom (Perception) check as a bonus action if you have a weapon drawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Stock Strike.</em></strong> When you make a melee weapon attack using a firearm on your turn, you use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. Additionally, if the attack hits, you can use your bonus action to not provoke opportunity attacks from the target of the attack until the end of your turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Run ‘N Gun. You can use Dash as a bonus action.
			Slinger’s Senses. You can make a Wisdom (Perception) check as a bonus action if you have a weapon drawn.
			Stock Strike. When you make a melee weapon attack using a firearm on your turn, you use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. Additionally, if the attack hits, you can use your bonus action to not provoke opportunity attacks from the target of the attack until the end of your turn.
			</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Knack" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_KNACK">
		<description>
			<p>At 2nd level, choose a skill or tool you are proficient in. Double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with those skills. When you reach 10th level, you can choose an additional skill or tool proficiency to gain this benefit.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			 <select type="Class Feature" name="Knack (Gunslinger)" level="2" number="1" supports="ID_INTERNAL_SUPPORT_EXPERTISE"/>
			 <select type="Class Feature" name="Knack (Gunslinger)" level="10" number="1" supports="ID_INTERNAL_SUPPORT_EXPERTISE"/>
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Fighting Style" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_FIGHTING_STYLE">
		<description>
			<p>At 2nd level, you adopt a particular style of fighting. Choose one of the following options. You cannot choose the same fighting style twice, even if you get to choose again.</p>
			<h5>AKIMBO SHOOTING</h5>
			<p>When you take the attack action with a light weapon, you can use a bonus action to make an attack with a light ranged weapon you are holding. You do not add your ability score modifier to the damage of this attack, unless that modifier is negative.</p>
			<h5>BREACHER</h5>
			<p>When you hit with a ranged attack roll, you roll a 1 or 2 on the damage die, you can reroll the damage die and must take the new roll, even if the number is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the scatter property in order to gain this benefit.</p>
			<h5>DEADEYE</h5>
			<p>You get a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with martial and simple ranged weapons, as well as longarms which do not have the bulky or scatter property.</p>
			<h5>DUELING</h5>
			<p>When wielding a one-handed weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you get a +2 bonus to your damage rolls with these weapons. This additional damage only applies for ranged attacks made at creatures within 30 feet of you.</p>
			<h5>SNIPER</h5>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls if you attack a creature further than 30 feet away from you with a ranged weapon or a firearm that does not have the scatter property.</p>
			<h5>PHALANX</h5>
			<p>You can now wield a two-handed melee weapon, heavy crossbow, light crossbow, or a longarm with a shield, but you must use an action to brace the weapon against the shield in order to attack with it.</p>
			<p>The weapon stays braced in this way as long as you move no more than 10 feet during your turn. The weapon loses any benefits you gain from using it with two hands while braced.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet/>
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style" supports="Fighting Style, Gunslinger" level="1"/>
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Akimbo Shooting" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_AKIMBO_SHOOTING">
		<supports>Fighting Style, Gunslinger, Ranger</supports>
		<requirements>ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_GUNSLINGER</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>When you take the attack action with a light weapon, you can use a bonus action to make an attack with a light ranged weapon you are holding. You do not add your ability score modifier to the damage of this attack, unless that modifier is negative.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you take the attack action with a light weapon, you can use a bonus action to make an attack with a light ranged weapon you are holding. You do not add your ability score modifier to the damage of this attack, unless that modifier is negative.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Breacher" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_BREACHER">
		<supports>Fighting Style, Gunslinger, Fighter</supports>
		<requirements>ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_GUNSLINGER</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>When you hit with a ranged attack roll, you roll a 1 or 2 on the damage die, you can reroll the damage die and must take the new roll, even if the number is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the scatter property in order to gain this benefit.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you hit with a ranged attack roll, you roll a 1 or 2 on the damage die, you can reroll the damage die and must take the new roll, even if the number is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the scatter property in order to gain this benefit.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Deadeye" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DEADEYE">
		<supports>Fighting Style, Gunslinger, Fighter, Ranger</supports>
		<requirements>ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_GUNSLINGER</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You get a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with martial and simple ranged weapons, as well as longarms which do not have the bulky or scatter property.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You get a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with martial and simple ranged weapons, as well as longarms which do not have the bulky or scatter property.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Dueling" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DUELING">
		<supports>Fighting Style, Gunslinger, Fighter, Ranger</supports>
		<requirements>ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_GUNSLINGER</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>When wielding a one-handed weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you get a +2 bonus to your damage rolls with these weapons. This additional damage only applies for ranged attacks made at creatures within 30 feet of you.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When wielding a one-handed weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you get a +2 bonus to your damage rolls with these weapons. This additional damage only applies for ranged attacks made at creatures within 30 feet of you.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Sniper" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_SNIPER">
		<supports>Fighting Style, Gunslinger, Ranger</supports>
		<requirements>ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_GUNSLINGER</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls if you attack a creature further than 30 feet away from you with a ranged weapon or a firearm that does not have the scatter property.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls if you attack a creature further than 30 feet away from you with a ranged weapon or a firearm that does not have the scatter property.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Phalanx" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_PHALANX">
		<supports>Fighting Style, Gunslinger, Fighter</supports>
		<requirements>ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_GUNSLINGER</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You can now wield a two-handed melee weapon, heavy crossbow, light crossbow, or a longarm with a shield, but you must use an action to brace the weapon against the shield in order to attack with it.</p>
			<p>The weapon stays braced in this way as long as you move no more than 10 feet during your turn. The weapon loses any benefits you gain from using it with two hands while braced.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can now wield a two-handed melee weapon, heavy crossbow, light crossbow, or a longarm with a shield, but you must use an action to brace the weapon against the shield in order to attack with it. The weapon stays braced in this way as long as you move no more than 10 feet during your turn. The weapon loses any benefits you gain from using it with two hands while braced.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Slinger's Trail" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_SLINGERS_TRAIL">
		<description>
			<p>At 3rd level, you begin to train your slinging to go down a particular style of emulation. You can choose from either Myth Breaker, Virtuoso, Vaquero, or Delver, all detailed at the end of the class description. The trail you choose grants you features at 3rd level, and again at 9th, 13th, and 17th level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Archetype" name="Slinger's Trail" supports="Slingers Trail" level="3" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Lucky Item" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_LUCKY_ITEM">
		<description>
			<p>When you reach 3rd level, you have taken up a personal effect that grants you uncanny luck in certain situations and says something interesting about you. This can take the form of a lucky hat that you never take off, a scarf given to you by a lost lover, or a cigar that seems to never run dry. Choose a benefit and a quirk from the table. You can use the benefit’s feature once per long rest. If your lucky item is lost or destroyed, it mysteriously reappears on you at the end of your next long rest. When you reach 13th level, you can choose one additional benefit and quirk. You can use either of the benefits twice before you complete a long rest.</p>
			<h6>BENEFITS AND QUIRKS</h6>
			<table>
				<thead><tr><td>Name</td><td>Bonus</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td><b>Benefit</b></td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Deft (Delver)</td><td>You get the identify and locate object spells and can cast them as rituals.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Fearless</td><td>You can use an action to end one effect on yourself that is causing you to be frightened.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Relief</td><td>You can spend one minute meditating with your item in hand, after which you regain hit die equal to one third your gunslinger level (rounded down).</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Rider (Vaquero)</td><td>You gain the beast bond spell, and can cast it as a ritual.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Seeker (Myth Breaker)</td><td>You get the hunter's mark spell, and can cast it once per long rest without expending a spell slot.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Sly (Virtuoso)</td><td>You gain one Battlemaster Maneuver and treat it as a Virtuoso Trick.</td></tr>
				<tr><td><b>Quirk</b></td><td>—</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Adept</td><td>You gain proficiency in two weapons of your choosing.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Eloquence</td><td>You learn two languages of your choosing.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Socialite</td><td>You gain proficiency in two gaming sets of your choosing.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Erudite</td><td>You gain proficiency in one skill or tool of your choice.</td></tr>
			</table>			
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can use the benefit’s feature(s) {{lucky-item:benefit-use}} time(s) per long rest. If your lucky item is lost or destroyed, it mysteriously reappears on you at the end of your next long rest.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="lucky-item:benefit-use" value="1" level="3" />
			<stat name="lucky-item:benefit-use" value="1" level="13" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Lucky Item (Benefit)" supports="Lucky Item, Benefit" level="3"/>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Lucky Item (Quirk)" supports="Lucky Item, Quirk" level="3"/>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Lucky Item (Benefit)" supports="Lucky Item, Benefit" level="13"/>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Lucky Item (Quirk)" supports="Lucky Item, Quirk" level="13"/>
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Deft" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_LUCKY_ITEM_BENEFIT_DEFT">
		<supports>Lucky Item, Benefit</supports>
		<prerequisites>Delver</prerequisites>
		<requirements>ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_DELVER</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You get the identify and locate object spells and can cast them as rituals.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You get the identify and locate object spells and can cast them as rituals.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_IDENTIFY" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_OBJECT" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Fearless" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_LUCKY_ITEM_BENEFIT_FEARLESS">
		<supports>Lucky Item, Benefit</supports>
		<prerequisites></prerequisites>
		<requirements></requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You can use an action to end one effect on yourself that is causing you to be frightened.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can use an action to end one effect on yourself that is causing you to be frightened.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Relief" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_LUCKY_ITEM_BENEFIT_RELIEF">
		<supports>Lucky Item, Benefit</supports>
		<prerequisites></prerequisites>
		<requirements></requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You can spend one minute meditating with your item in hand, after which you regain hit die equal to one third your gunslinger level (rounded down).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can spend one minute meditating with your item in hand, after which you regain {{relief:hd}} hit die.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="relief:hd" value="1" level="3" />
			<stat name="relief:hd" value="1" level="6" />
			<stat name="relief:hd" value="1" level="9" />
			<stat name="relief:hd" value="1" level="12" />
			<stat name="relief:hd" value="1" level="15" />
			<stat name="relief:hd" value="1" level="18" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Rider" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_LUCKY_ITEM_BENEFIT_RIDER">
		<supports>Lucky Item, Benefit</supports>
		<prerequisites>Vaquero</prerequisites>
		<requirements>ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_VAQUERO</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You gain the beast bond spell, and can cast it as a ritual.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You gain the beast bond spell, and can cast it as a ritual.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_XGTE_SPELL_BEAST_BOND" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Seeker" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_LUCKY_ITEM_BENEFIT_SEEKER">
		<supports>Lucky Item, Benefit</supports>
		<prerequisites>Myth Breaker</prerequisites>
		<requirements>ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_MYTH_BREAKER</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You get the hunter's mark spell, and can cast it once per long rest without expending a spell slot.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You get the hunter's mark spell, and can cast it once per long rest without expending a spell slot.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HUNTERS_MARK" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Sly" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_LUCKY_ITEM_BENEFIT_SLY">
		<supports>Lucky Item, Benefit</supports>
		<prerequisites>Virtuoso</prerequisites>
		<requirements>ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_VIRTUOSO</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You gain one Battlemaster Maneuver and treat it as a Virtuoso Trick.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You gain one Battlemaster Maneuver and treat it as a Virtuoso Trick.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			  <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Gunslinger Lucky Item (Sly)" supports="Maneuver,Battle Master" number="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Adept" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_LUCKY_ITEM_QUIRK_ADEPT">
		<supports>Lucky Item, Quirk</supports>
		<prerequisites></prerequisites>
		<requirements></requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency in two weapons of your choosing.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You gain proficiency in two weapons of your choosing.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select name="Gunslinger Lucky Item (Adept)" type="Proficiency" supports="Weapon" number="2"/>
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Eloquence" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_LUCKY_ITEM_QUIRK_ELOQUENCE">
		<supports>Lucky Item, Quirk</supports>
		<prerequisites></prerequisites>
		<requirements></requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You learn two languages of your choosing.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You learn two languages of your choosing.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select name="Gunslinger Lucky Item (Eloquence)" type="Language" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Socialite" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_LUCKY_ITEM_QUIRK_SOCIALITE">
		<supports>Lucky Item, Quirk</supports>
		<prerequisites></prerequisites>
		<requirements></requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency in two gaming sets of your choosing.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You gain proficiency in two gaming sets of your choosing.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select name="Gunslinger Lucky Item (Socialite)" type="Proficiency" supports="Gaming Set" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Erudite" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_LUCKY_ITEM_QUIRK_ERUDITE">
		<supports>Lucky Item, Quirk</supports>
		<prerequisites></prerequisites>
		<requirements></requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency in one skill or tool of your choice.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You gain proficiency in one skill or tool of your choice.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select name="Gunslinger Lucky Item (Erudite)" type="Proficiency" supports="Skill||Tool" number="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Ability Score Improvement (Gunslinger)" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT">
		<description>
			<p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th level, 12th level, 16th level, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As usual, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Gunslinger 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Gunslinger,4" level="4" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Gunslinger 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Gunslinger,8" level="8" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Gunslinger 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Gunslinger,12" level="12" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Gunslinger 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Gunslinger,16" level="16" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Gunslinger 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Gunslinger,19" level="19" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Extra Attack (Gunslinger)" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_EXTRA_ATTACK">
		<description>
			<p>At 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once when you take the attack action on your turn.</p><p class="indent">Additionally, when you take the Attack action on your turn, you can forgo one of your attacks to reload your weapon.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can attack twice, instead of once when you take the attack action on your turn. You can forgo one of your attacks to reload your weapon.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Bullet Time" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_BULLET_TIME">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 6th level, you've honed your senses to avoid attacks effortlessly. You can now take the Dodge action using a bonus action. You can do this a number of times equal to your Dexterity modifier. You regain the uses of this feature when you complete a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can use the Dodge action as a bonus action. You can do this $Dexterity Modifier) times before you complete a short or long rest.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Evasion" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_EVASION">
		<description>
			<p>At 7th level, your reflexes are as fast as any bullet you fire from your gun. When you make a Dexterity Saving Throw to take half damage from a damaging effect, such as a shotgun's scattering shells or a black dragon's acid breath, you take no damage on a successful save and only half damage on a failed save.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you make a Dexterity Saving Throw to take half damage from a damaging effect, you take no damage on a successful save and only half damage on a failed save.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Shootout Sense" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_SHOOTOUT_SENSE">
		<description>
			<p>By 11th level, you are ready to react to danger at a moment's notice. You gain advantage on initiative rolls.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, you can't be surprised while you are conscious.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You gain advantage on initiative rolls and you can't be surprised while you are conscious.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Overwatch" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_OVERWATCH">
		<description>
			<p>At 14th level, you can use an action to lie in wait to take an action against any enemy that reveals itself. If a creature moves, makes a weapon attack, or casts a spell while within your firearm's range, you can use your reaction to make an attack against them.</p>
			<h5>Saving Throws</h5>
			<p>Overwatch requires targets to make a saving throw to resist the penalties imposed on them. The Saving throw DC is as follows:</p>
			<center>
				<p><b>Overwatch Save DC = 8</b> + your proficiency bonus + your Dexterity modifier.</p>
			</center>
			<br/>
			<p>On a hit, the following effects are imposed in addition to the attack's normal effects.</p>
			<ul>
				<li>If the attack was triggered by the target's movement, it must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, its movement speed is reduced by half until the end of your next turn. On a successful save, their speed is only reduced by 10 until the end of your next turn.</li>
				<li>If the attack was triggered by the creature making a weapon attack, it must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, it has disadvantage on attack rolls until the start of your next turn. On a successful save, it only has disadvantage on the triggering attack.</li>
				<li>If the attack was triggered by the creature casting a spell, it must make a Constitution save. On a failed save, the target(s) of the spell have advantage on the saving throw to resist the effects of the spell, in addition all targeted creatures gain resistance to the spells damage. If the spell requires a spell attack roll it would be made with disadvantage.</li>				
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can use an action to lie in wait to take an action against any enemy that reveals itself. If a creature moves, makes a weapon attack, or casts a spell while within your firearm's range, you can use your reaction to make an attack against them.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Final Stand" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_FINAL_STAND">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 15th level, when you are reduced to 0 hit points and don’t die outright, you can use your reaction before you fall unconscious to make an attack roll at an enemy. This attack is made with disadvantage. If the attack hits, you gain hit points equal to 1d8 + your gunslinger level. Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you are reduced to 0 hit points and don’t die outright, you can use your reaction to make an attack roll at an enemy. This attack is made with disadvantage. If the attack hits, you gain 1d8+{{level:gunslinger}} hit points. Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Superhuman Reflexes" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_SUPERHUMAN_REFLEXES">
		<description>
			<p>At 18th level, a you have sharpened your reflexes to supersonic proportions. You now get the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You can use Disengage as a bonus action.</li>
				<li>Once per short rest, when you are hit by a ranged attack, you can reduce the damage of that attack to 0.</li>
				<li>You can use two gun stunts as a bonus action once per short or long rest.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can use Disengage as a bonus action.
			Once per short rest, when you are hit by a ranged attack, you can reduce the damage of that attack to 0.
			You can use two gun stunts as a bonus action once per short or long rest.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Gunslinging Supreme" type="Class Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_GUNSLINGER_GUNSLINGING_SUPREME">
		<description>
			<p>By the time you reach 20th level, you have become an undisputed slinger extraordinare. Add your proficiency bonus to damage rolls you make with your firearms, except when making an attack that does not normally apply your ability score modifier to it's damage. (For example, making an offhand attack.)</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, if you use the automatic or burst fire area of effect action, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Add your proficiency bonus to damage rolls you make with your firearms, except when making an attack that does not normally apply your ability score modifier to it's damage. (For example, making an offhand attack.)
			Additionally, if you use the automatic or burst fire area of effect action, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	
	<!-- myth breaker -->
	<element name="Myth Breaker" type="Archetype" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_MYTH_BREAKER">
		<supports>Slingers Trail</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Myth Breakers specialize in hunting down and dealing with the most dangerous of beasts. They hunt down anything from ancient dragons to beholders with extreme precision and skill. Determined and well researched in a variety of lore, myth breakers are experts in hunting down that which makes the average person tremble in fear.</p>
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYTHBREAKERSTACTICS"/>
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONSTROUSDEFENCE"/>
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRENGTHINKNOWLEDGE"/>
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGENDARYOVERWATCH" />
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Myth Breakers specialize in hunting down and dealing with the most dangerous of beasts.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYTHBREAKERSTACTICS" level="3"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONSTROUSDEFENCE" level="9"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRENGTHINKNOWLEDGE" level="13"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGENDARYOVERWATCH" level="17"/>
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Myth Breaker's Tactics" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYTHBREAKERSTACTICS">
		<description>
			<p>When you choose this trail at 3rd level, you can choose from one of the following tactics that help you slay various monstrosities.</p>
			<h5>Crowd Control</h5>
			<p>Your quick trigger finger lends itself well to killing hordes of creatures. Once per turn, when you make a firearm attack roll against a creature, you can make an additional attack against a creature that's within 5 feet of the targeted creature and in range of your firearm.</p>
			<h5>Legendary Buster</h5>
			<p>The crack of your gunshot is a symbol of teamwork as you mark powerful targets for death. When you succeed a firearm attack roll against a creature, the next attack made against the offending creature deals an extra d8 damage on a hit. You can only use this ability on one creature per turn.</p>
			<h5>Leviathan Feller</h5>
			<p>Your skill with a gun can send even big monstrosities reeling. When you hit with a firearm attack roll against a creature, you can push them back 10 feet from you in the direction you hit them. This forced move can only be done once per turn.</p>
			<h5>Varmint Slayer</h5>
			<p>You have a knack for landing precision shots that help you hit small or dodgy pests. You get advantage with firearm attacks on creatures that have moved further than 15 feet or taken the dodge or disengage action before your turn.</p>
			<h5>Showstopper</h5>
			<p>Creatures with exotic movements are no match for your expertly placed shots. If you hit with a firearm attack roll on a creature, it must succeed a Strength saving throw or have its flying speed, swim speed, climbing speed, walking speed and burrowing speed reduced by half, or become 0 if it was 5 feet until the end of its next turn. You can only use this ability once per turn.</p><p class="indent">Showstopper Save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Dexterity or Intelligence modifier.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Myth Breaker's Tactics" supports="Myth Breakers Tactics" number="1"/>
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Crowd Control" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYTHBREAKERSTACTICS_CROWDCONTROL">
		<supports>Myth Breakers Tactics</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your quick trigger finger lends itself well to killing hordes of creatures. Once per turn, when you make a firearm attack roll against a creature, you can make an additional attack against a creature that's within 5 feet of the targeted creature and in range of your firearm.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Once per turn, when you make a firearm attack roll against a creature, you can make an additional attack against a creature that's within 5 feet of the targeted creature and in range of your firearm.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Legendary Buster" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYTHBREAKERSTACTICS_LEGENDARYBUSTER">
		<supports>Myth Breakers Tactics</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The crack of your gunshot is a symbol of teamwork as you mark powerful targets for death. When you succeed a firearm attack roll against a creature, the next attack made against the offending creature deals an extra d8 damage on a hit. You can only use this ability on one creature per turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you succeed a firearm attack roll against a creature, the next attack made against the offending creature deals an extra d8 damage on a hit. You can only use this ability on one creature per turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Leviathan Feller" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYTHBREAKERSTACTICS_LEVIATHANFELLER">
		<supports>Myth Breakers Tactics</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your skill with a gun can send even big monstrosities reeling. When you hit with a firearm attack roll against a creature, you can push them back 10 feet from you in the direction you hit them. This forced move can only be done once per turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you hit with a firearm attack roll against a creature, you can push them back 10 feet from you in the direction you hit them. This forced move can only be done once per turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Varmint Slayer" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYTHBREAKERSTACTICS_VARMINTSLAYER">
		<supports>Myth Breakers Tactics</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have a knack for landing precision shots that help you hit small or dodgy pests. You get advantage with firearm attacks on creatures that have moved further than 15 feet or taken the dodge or disengage action before your turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You get advantage with firearm attacks on creatures that have moved further than 15 feet or taken the dodge or disengage action before your turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Showstopper" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MYTHBREAKERSTACTICS_SHOWSTOPPER">
		<supports>Myth Breakers Tactics</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Creatures with exotic movements are no match for your expertly placed shots. If you hit with a firearm attack roll on a creature, it must succeed a Strength saving throw or have its flying speed, swim speed, climbing speed, walking speed and burrowing speed reduced by half, or become 0 if it was 5 feet until the end of its next turn. You can only use this ability once per turn.</p><p class="indent">Showstopper Save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Dexterity or Intelligence modifier.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>If you hit with a firearm attack roll on a creature, it must succeed a Strength saving throw or have its flying speed, swim speed, climbing speed, walking speed and burrowing speed reduced by half, or become 0 if it was 5 feet until the end of its next turn. You can only use this ability once per turn.
			Showstopper Save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Dexterity or Intelligence modifier.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Monstrous Defense" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONSTROUSDEFENCE">
		<description>
			<p>When you reach 9th level, you can learn one of the following defensive tactics that add to your monster hunting skillset.</p>
			<h5>Critter Sense</h5>
			<p>Your dedication to tracking dangerous pests has allowed you to develop senses to help hunt them down. You gain 15 feet of blindsight and tremorsense, and creatures cannot get advantage on attack rolls or benefit from being hidden or invisible while within 15 feet of you, as long as you are not incapacitated.</p>
			<h5>Uncanny Dodge</h5>
			<p>You always keep your eyes about you, making surprise attacks from above and below difficult. When a creature damages you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve that damage against you.</p>
			<h5>Into the Fray</h5>
			<p>Creatures that crowd upon you find it quite hard to attack you. When a hostile creature makes an attack roll against you while another hostile creature is within 5 feet of you or it, the creature makes the roll with disadvantage.</p>
			<h5>Mythical Guardian</h5>
			<p>When keeping track of legendary creatures, your hunter's senses heighten your defense. You can end one effect on yourself causing you to be charmed or poisoned.</p>
			<h5>Slayer's Discipline</h5>
			<p>You are stalwart in the face of any kind of danger. You get proficiency in a saving throw of your choice.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
		
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select name="Monstrous Defense" type="Archetype Feature" supports="Monstrous Defense" number="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Critter Sense" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONSTROUSDEFENCE_CRITTERSENSE">
		<supports>Monstrous Defense</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your dedication to tracking dangerous pests has allowed you to develop senses to help hunt them down. You gain 15 feet of blindsight and tremorsense, and creatures cannot get advantage on attack rolls or benefit from being hidden or invisible while within 15 feet of you, as long as you are not incapacitated.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You gain 15 feet of blindsight and tremorsense, and creatures cannot get advantage on attack rolls or benefit from being hidden or invisible while within 15 feet of you, as long as you are not incapacitated.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Uncanny Dodge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONSTROUSDEFENCE_UNCANNYDODGE">
		<supports>Monstrous Defense</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You always keep your eyes about you, making surprise attacks from above and below difficult. When a creature damages you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve that damage against you.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When a creature damages you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve that damage against you.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Into the Fray" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONSTROUSDEFENCE_INTOTHEFRAY">
		<supports>Monstrous Defense</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Creatures that crowd upon you find it quite hard to attack you. When a hostile creature makes an attack roll against you while another hostile creature is within 5 feet of you or it, the creature makes the roll with disadvantage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When a hostile creature makes an attack roll against you while another hostile creature is within 5 feet of you or it, the creature makes the roll with disadvantage.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Mythical Guardian" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONSTROUSDEFENCE_MYTHICALGUARDIAN">
		<supports>Monstrous Defense</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When keeping track of legendary creatures, your hunter's senses heighten your defense. You can end one effect on yourself causing you to be charmed or poisoned.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When keeping track of legendary creatures, your hunter's senses heighten your defense. You can end one effect on yourself causing you to be charmed or poisoned.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Slayer's Discipline" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MONSTROUSDEFENCE_SLAYERSDISCIPLINE">
		<supports>Monstrous Defense</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You are stalwart in the face of any kind of danger. You get proficiency in a saving throw of your choice.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You get proficiency in a saving throw of your choice.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select name="Monstrous Defence (Slayer's Discipline) Saving Throw Proficiency" type="Proficiency" supports="Saving Throw" number="1"/> 
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Strength in Knowledge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_STRENGTHINKNOWLEDGE">
		<description>
			<p>At 13th level, you have augmented your mind and strengthened your resolve against the horrors out in the great beyond. You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, petrified, paralyzed or poisoned.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, petrified, paralyzed or poisoned.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Legendary Overwatch" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LEGENDARYOVERWATCH">
		<description>
			<p>Once you reach 17th level, you are able to stop the most fearsome creatures right in their tracks with nothing but your bullets. If you make a successful overwatch attack against a creature, you can make it suffer the following effects:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>If the creature is moving, it is stunned until the end of your next turn.</li>
				<li>If the creature is making an attack roll, it automatically fails that attack roll and cannot make any more attacks until the end of your next turn.</li>
				<li>If it is casting a spell or forcing a creature or creatures to make a saving throw, the spell or area of effect attack automatically fails, dealing no damage if it would normally do so. If the creature was casting a spell, the spell slot is wasted.</li>
			</ul>
			<p>Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>
				<p>Once you reach 17th level, you are able to stop the most fearsome creatures right in their tracks with nothing but your bullets. If you make a successful overwatch attack against a creature, you can make it suffer the following effects:</p>
				<ul>
					<li>If the creature is moving, it is stunned until the end of your next turn.</li>
					<li>If the creature is making an attack roll, it automatically fails that attack roll and cannot make any more attacks until the end of your next turn.</li>
					<li>If it is casting a spell or forcing a creature or creatures to make a saving throw, the spell or area of effect attack automatically fails, dealing no damage if it would normally do so. If the creature was casting a spell, the spell slot is wasted.</li>
				</ul>
				<p>Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a short or long rest.</p>
			</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!-- virtuoso -->
	<element name="Virtuoso" type="Archetype" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_VIRTUOSO">
		<supports>Slingers Trail</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Virtuosos don’t see guns as just a mere tool of destruction, they see them as an art form that they wish to master. Those who chose to train as virtuosos collect and train with as many guns as possible in to become more versatile and powerful shooters whose skill and showmanship is unrivaled.</p>
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THEARTOFLEAD" />
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEADINTHEGAME" />
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SKILLEDANDWITTY" />
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRICKPRODIGY" />
		</description>
		<sheet>
		
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THEARTOFLEAD" level="3"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEADINTHEGAME" level="9"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SKILLEDANDWITTY" level="13"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRICKPRODIGY" level="17"/>
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="The Art of Lead" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_THEARTOFLEAD" >
		<description>
			<p>Starting when you choose this trail at level 3, Virtuosos get a bevy of special skills enhanced by special dice called superiority dice.</p>
			<h5>Tricks</h5>
			<p>You learn three tricks of your choice, which are detailed under "tricks" below. Many tricks enhance an attack or assist allies/debilitate enemies in some way, shape or form. You can only use one trick per attack.</p>
			<p>You learn two additional tricks at 9th level, 13th level, and 17th level. Each time you learn a new trick, you can also replace one Trick you know with a different one.</p>
			<h5>Superiority Dice</h5>
			<p>You have four superiority dice, which are d8s, to spend on Tricks. When you use a superiority die, it's expended. You regain all your superiority dice when you finish a short or long rest. You get an additional superiority die at 9th level, and one more at 17th level.</p>
			<h5>Superiority Dice Improvements</h5>
			<p>Superiority dice turn into d10s at 9th level and d12s at 17th level.</p>
			<h5>Saving Throws</h5>
			<p>Some of your Tricks require your target to make a saving throw to resist the trick's effects. The save DC is calculated as follows:</p><p class="indent">Trick Save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Dexterity or Charisma modifier.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You learn tricks that are fueled by special dice called superiority dice. You have {{superiority dice:amount}} superiority dice which are d{{superiority dice:size}}s. DC $superiority dice:dc)</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="superiority dice:amount" value="4" />
			<stat name="superiority dice:amount" value="1" level="9" />
			<stat name="superiority dice:amount" value="1" level="17" />
			<stat name="superiority dice:size" value="8" bonus="size"/>
			<stat name="superiority dice:size" value="2" level="9"/>
			<stat name="superiority dice:size" value="2" level="17"/>
			<stat name="superiority dice:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="superiority dice:dc" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="superiority dice:dc:ability" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
			<stat name="superiority dice:dc:ability" value="dexterity:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
			<stat name="superiority dice:dc" value="superiority dice:dc:ability" />
			<select name="The Art of Lead (Level 3)" type="Archetype Feature" supports="Virtuoso Tricks" number="3" />
			<select name="The Art of Lead (Level 9)" type="Archetype Feature" supports="Virtuoso Tricks" number="2" level="9" />
			<select name="The Art of Lead (Level 13)" type="Archetype Feature" supports="Virtuoso Tricks" number="2" level="13" />
			<select name="The Art of Lead (Level 17)" type="Archetype Feature" supports="Virtuoso Tricks" number="2" level="17" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Head in the Game" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_HEADINTHEGAME" >
		<description>
			<p>At 9th level, you are constantly on top of your game, and are always ready for action. You add your Charisma modifier to your initiative rolls.</p><p class="indent">Additionally, you gain proficiency in Wisdom saving throws.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
		
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_WISDOM" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Skilled and Witty" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SKILLEDANDWITTY" >
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 13th level, you have become an epitome of expertise and sheer skill, both on and off the battlefield. You learn an additional skill, tool, or language of your choice. Alternatively, you can choose a skill or tool you are proficient in. Double your proficiency bonus for checks made using that skill or tool.</p><p class="indent">Additionally, you get advantage on Persuasion and Intimidation checks when trying to defuse a fight.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You get advantage on Persuasion and Intimidation checks when trying to defuse a fight.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Skilled and Witty" supports="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SKILLEDANDWITTY_NEWSKILL|ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SKILLEDANDWITTY_EXPERTISE|ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SKILLEDANDWITTY_NEWLANGUAGE|ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SKILLEDANDWITTY_NEWTOOL" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Expertise (Skilled and Witty)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SKILLEDANDWITTY_EXPERTISE" >
		<description>
			<p>Choose a skill or tool you are proficient in. Double your proficiency bonus for checks made using that skill or tool.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Expertise (Skilled and Witty)" number="1" supports="ID_INTERNAL_SUPPORT_EXPERTISE"/>
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Additional Skill (Skilled and Witty)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SKILLEDANDWITTY_NEWSKILL" >
		<description>
			<p>You learn an additional skill, tool, or language of your choice.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Additional Skill (Skilled and Witty)" number="1" supports="Skill" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Additional Language (Skilled and Witty)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SKILLEDANDWITTY_NEWLANGUAGE" >
		<description>
			<p>You learn an additional skill, tool, or language of your choice.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Language" name="Additional Skill (Skilled and Witty)" number="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Additional Tool Proficiency (Skilled and Witty)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SKILLEDANDWITTY_NEWTOOL" >
		<description>
			<p>You learn an additional skill, tool, or language of your choice.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Additional Skill (Skilled and Witty)" number="1" supports="Tool" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Trick Prodigy" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_TRICKPRODIGY" >
		<description>
			<p>Once you reach 17th level, you regain 1 superiority die if you roll initiative and have no superiority dice remaining.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Once you reach 17th level, you regain 1 superiority die if you roll initiative and have no superiority dice remaining.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Break Cover" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VIRTUOSO_TRICK_BREAKCOVER" >
		<supports>Virtuoso Tricks</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Spend a superiority die to attack a creature in cover with an attack roll. Add the number rolled to the attack's damage. This attack ignores any cover bonuses the target is benefiting from.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Spend a superiority die to attack a creature in cover with an attack roll. Add the number rolled to the attack's damage. This attack ignores any cover bonuses the target is benefiting from.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Commander's Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VIRTUOSO_TRICK_COMMANDERSSTRIKE" >
		<supports>Virtuoso Tricks</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can forgo one of your attacks and use a bonus action to direct one of your companions to strike. When you do so, choose a friendly creature who can see or hear you and expend one superiority die. That creature can immediately use its reaction to make one weapon attack, adding the superiority die to the attack's damage roll.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can forgo one of your attacks and use a bonus action to direct one of your companions to strike. When you do so, choose a friendly creature who can see or hear you and expend one superiority die. That creature can immediately use its reaction to make one weapon attack, adding the superiority die to the attack's damage roll.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Concussive Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VIRTUOSO_TRICK_CONCUSSIVEATTACK" >
		<supports>Virtuoso Tricks</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you make a successful weapon attack, you can spend a superiority die and add the number rolled to the attack's damage. You cause your target to be discombobulated, imposing disadvantage on the next attack they make.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you make a successful weapon attack, you can spend a superiority die and add the number rolled to the attack's damage. You cause your target to be discombobulated, imposing disadvantage on the next attack they make.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Disarming Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VIRTUOSO_TRICK_DISARMINGATTACK" >
		<supports>Virtuoso Tricks</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Make an attack roll and expend a superiority die and add the number rolled to the attack's damage. If it succeeds, you force the creature hit to drop one of its held items. The creature must make a Strength saving throw. If they fail, they drop the held item down to their feet.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Make an attack roll and expend a superiority die and add the number rolled to the attack's damage. If it succeeds, you force the creature hit to drop one of its held items. The creature must make a Strength saving throw. If they fail, they drop the held item down to their feet.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Disorienting Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VIRTUOSO_TRICK_DISORIENTINGATTACK" >
		<supports>Virtuoso Tricks</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you make a successful weapon attack, you can spend a superiority die to disorient them, giving allies an opening. The next attack roll that's made against the target has advantage if the attack is made before the start of your next turn. Add the result of your superiority die to the ally's attack roll.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you make a successful weapon attack, you can spend a superiority die to disorient them, giving allies an opening. The next attack roll that's made against the target has advantage if the attack is made before the start of your next turn. Add the result of your superiority die to the ally's attack roll.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Evasive Footwork" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VIRTUOSO_TRICK_EVASIVEFOOTWORK" >
		<supports>Virtuoso Tricks</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you move, you can expend one superiority die, rolling the die and adding the number rolled to your AC until you stop moving.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you move, you can expend one superiority die, rolling the die and adding the number rolled to your AC until you stop moving.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Intercept" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VIRTUOSO_TRICK_INTERCEPT" >
		<supports>Virtuoso Tricks</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When an enemy that you can see makes a ranged spell attack or a ranged attack within your firearm's range, you can expend a superiority die in order to use a reaction to attempt to shoot it out of the air. Make a ranged weapon attack against the missile or spell. Add the number rolled on your superiority die to the attack roll. These missiles and ranged spells have an AC equal to the attack roll of the creature that shot or cast them. If you succeed, the attack automatically fails as you strike it and either interrupts its effects or knocks it off course. You can use this trick before or after the attack roll is made, but before it's revealed to be a hit or a miss.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When an enemy that you can see makes a ranged spell attack or a ranged attack within your firearm's range, you can expend a superiority die in order to use a reaction to attempt to shoot it out of the air. Make a ranged weapon attack against the missile or spell. Add the number rolled on your superiority die to the attack roll. These missiles and ranged spells have an AC equal to the attack roll of the creature that shot or cast them. If you succeed, the attack automatically fails as you strike it and either interrupts its effects or knocks it off course. You can use this trick before or after the attack roll is made, but before it's revealed to be a hit or a miss.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Piercing Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VIRTUOSO_TRICK_PIERCINGATTACK" >
		<supports>Virtuoso Tricks</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you hit with a ranged weapon attack, you can expend a superiority die to have the shot continue on through the target after hitting it in order to attempt to damage an additional creature. If the creature within range of your shot and in the same line as your shot would have been hit by your attack roll, they take damage equal to the number rolled on your superiority die + your Dexterity or Charisma modifier. The damage is the same as the type dealt by the original attack.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you hit with a ranged weapon attack, you can expend a superiority die to have the shot continue on through the target after hitting it in order to attempt to damage an additional creature. If the creature within range of your shot and in the same line as your shot would have been hit by your attack roll, they take damage equal to the number rolled on your superiority die + your Dexterity or Charisma modifier. The damage is the same as the type dealt by the original attack.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Precision Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VIRTUOSO_TRICK_PRECISIONATTACK" >
		<supports>Virtuoso Tricks</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you make a weapon attack roll against a creature, you can expend one superiority die and add the number rolled to the roll. You can use this trick before or after making the attack roll, but before any effects of the attack are applied.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you make a weapon attack roll against a creature, you can expend one superiority die and add the number rolled to the roll. You can use this trick before or after making the attack roll, but before any effects of the attack are applied.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Rocket Jump" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VIRTUOSO_TRICK_ROCKETJUMP" >
		<supports>Virtuoso Tricks</supports>
		<description>
			<p>If you make a jump, you can spend a superiority die to make the jump with vim and vigor, adding the number rolled + your Dexterity modifier to that jump's distance.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>If you make a jump, you can spend a superiority die to make the jump with vim and vigor, adding the number rolled + your Dexterity modifier to that jump's distance.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Slinger's Luck" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VIRTUOSO_TRICK_SLINGERSLUCK" >
		<supports>Virtuoso Tricks</supports>
		<description>
			<p>If your weapon would misfire, you can expend a superiority die in order to channel the inherent luck of your craft to avoid the misfire entirely. Add the number rolled on your superiority die to your next attack roll.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>If your weapon would misfire, you can expend a superiority die in order to channel the inherent luck of your craft to avoid the misfire entirely. Add the number rolled on your superiority die to your next attack roll.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Trip Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VIRTUOSO_TRICK_TRIPATTACK" >
		<supports>Virtuoso Tricks</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to knock the target down. You add a superiority die to the attack’s damage roll, and if the target is Large or smaller, it must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, you knock the target prone.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to knock the target down. You add a superiority die to the attack’s damage roll, and if the target is Large or smaller, it must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, you knock the target prone.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Warning Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VIRTUOSO_TRICK_WARNINGATTACK" >
		<supports>Virtuoso Tricks</supports>
		<description>
			<p>When you miss a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend a superiority die to attempt to frighten the target as the shot whizzes past them. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw. Subtract the result of your superiority die from their roll. On a failed save, it is frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you miss a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend a superiority die to attempt to frighten the target as the shot whizzes past them. The target must make a Wisdom saving throw. Subtract the result of your superiority die from their roll. On a failed save, it is frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	

	<!-- vaquero -->
	<element name="Vaquero" type="Archetype" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_VAQUERO">
		<supports>Slingers Trail</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Vaqueros are born and raised in the life of the commonfolk, tending to ranches and animals. Because of this, they are experts at fighting on mounts. Vaqueros are speedy combatants that are hard to pin down, as well as experts at travel and exploration. This makes them naturally inclined to adventure.</p>
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BACKINTHESADDLE"/>
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GALLOPINGGAUCHO"/>
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FRONTIERSMAN"/>
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEFTEVASIVENESS"/>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
		
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BACKINTHESADDLE" level="3"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GALLOPINGGAUCHO" level="9"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FRONTIERSMAN" level="13"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEFTEVASIVENESS" level="17"/>
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Back in the Saddle" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BACKINTHESADDLE" >
		<description>
			<p>When you choose this trail at 3rd level, your expertise in mount riding shows forth as well. You have advantage on saving throws made to avoid falling off your mount. If you fall off your mount and descend no more than 10 feet, you can land on your feet if you’re not incapacitated.</p><p class="indent">Additionally, mounting or dismounting a creature costs you only 5 feet of movement, rather than half your speed.</p><p class="indent">Finally, when you Run 'N Gun, you can move an additional 5 feet. You can do this a number of times equal to your Dexterity modifier, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have advantage on saving throws made to avoid falling off your mount and if you fall off your mount and descend no more than 10 feet, you can land on your feet if you’re not incapacitated. Mounting or dismounting a creature costs you only 5 feet of movement, and when you Run 'N Gun, you can move an additional 5 feet. You can do this a number of times equal to your Dexterity modifier, and you regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.
			</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>		
	<element name="Galloping Gaucho" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GALLOPINGGAUCHO" >
		<description>
			<p>At 9th level, you are hard to pin down, whether you're mounted or not. If you've moved at least 20 feet in a straight line on your turn, you gain a bonus to your AC equal to half your proficiency bonus (rounded down) until the start of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>If you've moved at least 20 feet in a straight line on your turn, you gain a bonus to your AC equal to half your proficiency bonus (rounded down) until the start of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>		
	<element name="Frontiersman" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_FRONTIERSMAN" >
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 13th level, you have become adept at surviving the toughest of conditions out in the wild. You are immune to poison and disease, and have advantage on saving throws and ability checks to resist being shoved or knocked prone.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You are immune to poison and disease, and have advantage on saving throws and ability checks to resist being shoved or knocked prone.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_POISON" />
		</rules>
	</element>		
	<element name="Deft Evasiveness" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DEFTEVASIVENESS" >
		<description>
			<p>Once you reach 17th level, your vigilance to danger lets you dash in and out of danger with the greatest of ease. Creatures have disadvantage on opportunity attacks against you. Additionally, when you are subject to a damaging effect, such as a trap or a cone of cold spell, you can use your reaction to move 10 feet in any direction or command your mount to move 10 feet in any direction before making the saving throw to resist it. If this movement would place you outside of the area subject to the effect, you do not need to make a saving throw to resist it, and are not affected.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Creatures have disadvantage on opportunity attacks against you. Additionally, when you are subject to a damaging effect, you can use your reaction to move 10 feet in any direction or command your mount to move 10 feet in any direction before making the saving throw to resist it. If this movement would place you outside of the area subject to the effect, you do not need to make a saving throw to resist it, and are not affected.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	
	<!-- delver -->
	<element name="Delver" type="Archetype" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_DELVER">
		<supports>Slingers Trail</supports>
		<description>
			<p>In the darkest tombs, the most cursed catacombs, and the deepest of dungeons, Delvers are right at home. Skilled navigators and experts at finding and procuring artifacts, they have a nose for trouble, and the right set of skills and know how to get out of any scrape.</p>
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CATACOMBCRAWLER"/>
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAPDASHPLOY"/>
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ONESTEPAHEAD"/>
			<div element="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ACEINTHEHOLE"/>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
		
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CATACOMBCRAWLER" level="3"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAPDASHPLOY" level="9"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ONESTEPAHEAD" level="13"/>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ACEINTHEHOLE" level="17"/>
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Catacomb Crawler" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CATACOMBCRAWLER" >
		<description>
			<p>When you choose this trail at 3rd level, your talent for raiding dungeons begins to truly surface. You gain darkvision out to 60 feet if it do not have it already, and you can move while squeezed into a space smaller than yourself without spending extra movement.</p><p class="indent">Additionally, you gain proficiency in thieves' tools and navigator’s tools, and get a climb speed of 20 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You gain darkvision out to 60 feet if it do not have it already, and you can move while squeezed into a space smaller than yourself without spending extra movement and get a climb speed of 20 feet.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_THIEVES_TOOLS" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_NAVIGATORS_TOOLS" />
		</rules>
	</element>	
	<element name="Slapdash Ploy" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SLAPDASHPLOY" >
		<description>
			<p>At 9th level, you seem to perform your best work when you have no idea what you're doing. When you use a skill, make a saving throw, or make an attack roll with a weapon you are not proficient with, you can choose to add your proficiency bonus to the roll. You can do this before or after the roll is made, but before it is determined to be a success or failure.</p><p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you use a skill, make a saving throw, or make an attack roll with a weapon you are not proficient with, you can choose to add your proficiency bonus to the roll. You can do this before or after the roll is made, but before it is determined to be a success or failure. Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="One Step Ahead" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ONESTEPAHEAD" >
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 13th level, you gain a knack for dealing with the dangers of dungeons and their eldritch inhabitants. You are resistant to damage dealt by traps. Additionally, you have advantage on checks you make to disarm traps or identifying creatures.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You are resistant to damage dealt by traps. Additionally, you have advantage on checks you make to disarm traps or identifying creatures.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
	<element name="Ace in the Hole" type="Archetype Feature" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ACEINTHEHOLE" >
		<description>
			<p>Once your reach 17th level, you have a trick up your sleeve that you can pull out the moment it is needed. At any time during another creature’s turn, you can use your reaction to immediately take an extra turn, interrupting the current turn. Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you complete a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>At any time during another creature’s turn, you can use your reaction to immediately take an extra turn, interrupting the current turn. Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you complete a long rest.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>	
</elements>
