<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Items</name>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="magic-items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/homebrew/reddit/arcane-artillery/magic-items.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Ammunition, Double Tap" type="Magic Item" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMO_DOUBLE_TAP">
		<description>
			<p>When you attack with this ammunition, regardless of whether or not you hit, you can repeat the attack roll against the same creature you fired at again at the beginning of your next turn. If the creature was brought to 0 HP by the ammunition on the first attack, you can instead make the second attack roll at a different target within 30 feet of the creature attacked at the beginning of your next turn. Otherwise this ammunition drops to the ground harmlessly. If both attack rolls were able to be made with this ammunition, it loses its magic and becomes mundane.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any ammunition</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="name-format">Double Tap {{parent}}</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Ammunition, Returning" type="Magic Item" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMO_RETURNING">
		<description>
			<p>This ammunition can take the form of either arrows, sling bullets, crossbow bolts, or gun rounds. When it is fired for the first time, it teleports back to you. Every time you fire this ammunition from here on out, there's a 50% chance it will teleport back into your inventory. This ammunition can always be recovered after battles.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any ammunition</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="name-format">Returning {{parent}}</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Ammunition, Tracer" type="Magic Item" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_MAGIC_ITEM_AMMO_TRACER">
		<description>
			<p>When you make an attack roll with this ammunition, it has advantage. On a hit, the round begins to glow and seems to draw attacks toward it. The next creature that makes an attack roll against the creature hit by the ammunition makes the roll with advantage. On a hit, the creature's attack deals an extra d6 damage. The ammunition then loses its magic when used.</p>
			<p class="indent">The round can always be recovered after a battle if it does not hit a creature.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any ammunition</set>
			<set name="category">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any ammunition">Ammunition</set>
			<set name="attunement">false</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="name-format">Tracer {{parent}}</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Arctic Grasp" type="Magic Item" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_MAGIC_ITEM_ARCTIC_GRASP">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls you make with this freezing cold rifle. This rifle does not fire normal bullets, but rather a freezing cold beam of energy that deals 2d6 cold damage on a hit, and half as much damage on a miss. This rifle has 7 charges. When this rifle expends all its rounds, you can use an action or an action and expend a charge to regain the gun's ammunition. You cannot recharge it if you have been subjected to fire damage within the past minute. This gun regains all 7 charges at the end of a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent">Glacial Beam. You can use an action to fire a 120 foot line that is 5 feet wide. Creatures within the line take 4d6 cold damage and must make a DC 13 Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, they take an additional 2d6 cold damage on a hit and have their speed reduced to 0, and cannot take reactions. Creatures within 5 feet of the line must succeed a DC 13 Dexterity saving throw. They take 4d6 cold damage on a failed save, and half as much damage on a successful save. Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you complete a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any rifle</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any rifle">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_RDDT_AA_WEAPON_GROUP_RIFLES</set>
			<set name="name-format">Arctic Grasp</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Artemis Cannon" type="Magic Item" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_MAGIC_ITEM_ARTEMIS_CANNON">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic rifle. This weapon has 4 charges. You can use an action to expend one charge and cast conjure barrage, or you can use an action to expend 2 charges to cast conjure volley.</p>
			<p>The spells are cast with the following changes:</p>
			<p class="indent">This spell deals force damage instead of the weapon's original damage.</p>
			<p>This weapon reagains 1d4 charges when you complete a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any rifle</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any rifle">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_RDDT_AA_WEAPON_GROUP_RIFLES</set>
			<set name="name-format">Artemis Cannon</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Ashes to Ashes" type="Magic Item" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_MAGIC_ITEM_ASHES_TO_ASHES">
		<description>
			<p>Ornate red and orange runes flicker across this weapon like embers. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls with this weapon, and it deals an additional 1d8 fire damage on a hit. After firing this weapon, a swirling cloud of gunsmoke that unleashes blazing embers appears in a 5-foot radius around you. The cloud spreads around corners and is heavily obscured. The cloud remains until the start of your next turn or until a wind of moderate or greater speed (at least 10 miles per hour) disperses it. This cloud heavily obscures thearea for all creatures except you.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any pistol</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any pistol">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_RDDT_AA_WEAPON_GROUP_PISTOLS</set>
			<set name="name-format">Ashes to Ashes</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Brimstone" type="Magic Item" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_MAGIC_ITEM_BRIMSTONE">
		<description>
			<p>This shoulder cannon deals fire damage instead of its normal damage. The weapon has 3 charges. You can expend one of these charges to cast fireball without expending a spell slot. You regain all expended charges when you complete a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">shoulder cannon</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="shoulder cannon">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Shoulder Cannon</set>
			<set name="name-format">Brimstone</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Crimson Fang" type="Magic Item" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_MAGIC_ITEM_CRIMSON_FANG">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic pistol. In addition, while you are attuned to this weapon, you regenerate 10 hit points per round that you are not in direct sunlight. You also gain 120 feet of darkvision, are permanently under the effects of a spider climb spell, and are immune to poison and disease.</p>
			<p class="indent">Blood Draining Shot. When you deal damage to a target using this pistol, you regain hit points equal to half the damage you dealt.</p>
			<p class="indent">Charm. Once per long rest, you can attempt to charm a creature within 30 feet of you that you can see. The creature must succeed a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw against this magic or become charmed by you. The charmed target regards you as a trusted friend to be heeded and protected. Although the target isn’t under your control, it takes your requests or actions in the most favorable way it can. Each time you or creatures friendly to you do anything harmful to the target, it can repeat the saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success. Otherwise, the effect lasts 24 hours or until you are killed, are on a different plane of existence than the target, or if you take a bonus action to end the effect.</p>
			<p class="indent">Curse. This pistol is cursed, and becoming attuned to it extends the curse to you. Using the identify spell on this weapon will reveal it to be a +1 pistol. As long as you remain cursed, you are unwilling to part with the pistol, and keep it as close to you as possible. Every time you complete a long rest, you must drink the blood of a humanoid creature that is indifferent to you or friendly to you, willing or unwilling. If you do not, you gain 1 point of exhaustion after you complete the rest. This number goes up by 1 every 2 weeks you are attuned to this weapon, to a maximum of 10. At the start of the day, each time you drink, it must be from a different creature, or you will gain a point of exhaustion. In addition, your skin slowly starts to become pallid and sickly, and your canines grow longer and sharper when talking to you. When you kill a humanoid creature with this pistol, you must succeed a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw or spend your next turn moving toward the creature’s corpse and feasting on its blood. Once you do this, you lose the compulsion for blood. You must consume the blood of 5 hostile humanoid creatures in order to remove or prevent the exhaustion from the weapon’s curse. This number goes up by 5 every 2 weeks you are attuned to this weapon, to a maximum of 25.</p>
			</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">pistol</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="pistol">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_RDDT_AA_WEAPON_GROUP_PISTOLS</set>
			<set name="name-format">Crimson Fang</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Cursebringer" type="Magic Item" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_MAGIC_ITEM_CURSEBRINGER">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic carbine, and rounds fired from it deal necrotic damage instead of piercing damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">Deathcurse. You can cast the hex spell two times without expending a spell slot. You regain expended uses when you complete a long rest. When you reduce a creature to 0 hit points that has the hex on it using this weapon, the round explodes. Any creature within 10 feet of the creature hit must succeed a DC 14 Dexterity saving throw. They take 4d6 necrotic damage on a failed save, and half that damage on a successful save.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">carbine</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="carbine">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_RDDT_AA_WEAPON_GROUP_CARBINES</set>
			<set name="name-format">Cursebringer</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Cold Famine" type="Magic Item" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_MAGIC_ITEM_COLD_FAMINE">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls you make with this magic gun. This weapon deals an extra 1d8 cold damage on a hit.</p>
			</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">heavy rifle</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="heavy rifle">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_RDDT_AA_WEAPON_HEAVYRIFLE</set>
			<set name="name-format">Cold Famine</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Debt Collector" type="Magic Item" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_MAGIC_ITEM_DEBT_COLLECTOR">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic gun. When you roll a 20 with this weapon, you can immediately make a melee weapon attack with the bayonet that deals 1d12 slashing damage on a hit as part of that attack.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">rifleblade</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapon</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="rifleblade">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="weapon">Rifleblade</set>
			<set name="name-format">Debt Collector</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<!--Next Item: Dragon Cannon, Page 24-->

	<element name="Lucky Seven" type="Magic Item" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_MAGIC_ITEM_LUCKY_SEVEN">
		<description>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls you make with this magic six shooter. This gun has golden lines along its body and green three leaf clovers on its grip, and sparkles dimly in your hands. Each shot feels like you're gambling for something big.</p>
			<p class="indent">Seven of Clovers. If you roll a 7 on an attack roll with this weapon, your attack automatically hits and is considered a critical hit. It does maximum damage for both damage rolls.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any revolver</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any revolver">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_RDDT_AA_WEAPON_GROUP_REVOLVERS</set>
			<set name="name-format">Lucky Seven</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Man's Best Friend" type="Magic Item" source="Arcane Artillery" id="ID_RDDT_AA_MAGIC_ITEM_MANS_BEST_FRIEND">
		<description>
			<p>This weapon, hidden deep within the confines of a mad laboratory, is a strange conglomeration of science and necromancy, and appears to be a human wizard and a magic using gunslinger’s attempt to keep their favorite pet around after its passing. The brain itself, or at least a piece of it is floating in a jar attached to the body of the gun, and the sights are arranged with two floppy ear like mechanisms. The face of the deceased animal is painted either on the body itself or around the sights, and magic runes of necromancy are engraved into its barrel.</p>
			<p class="indent">Only a gunslinger or a wizard can attune to this weapon. Any other creatures attempting to do so will be growled at by the weapon and fail to attune to it.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls you make with this odd sentient firearm. It has the following additional properties. Sentience. Man’s Best Friend contains the soul of a friendly dog with an Intelligence of 6, a Wisdom of 14, and a Charisma of 8. It has 60 feet of darkvision, and also has advantage on saving throws on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell.</p>
			<p class="indent">The weapon can understand Common, any language its previous masters knew and any language you know while attuned to it. It communicates in barks, yips, whines and growls that are audible out to 60 feet. However, it can translate those barks when speaking directly to you as primal feelings and emotions, such as fear, excitement or sadness.</p>
			<p>Personality. Man’s Best Friend is extraordinarily curious, and will constantly try to direct you towards interesting things, such as caves, treasure, and squirrels. It is extremely loyal to you once you form a bond to it, and will growl whenever it senses dangerous intentions from other creatures, or pant happily in the presence of creatures friendly to you. The weapon can move ever so slightly in your grip, but never enough to force your aim off or drop it. It usually does this when it wishes to be pet. Man’s Best Friend thrives on affection and assurance, and if those things are not regularly provided to it by its wielder, a conflict between the two will occur after 10 consecutive days of neglect.</p>
			<p class="indent">Nose For Danger. This weapon makes Wisdom (Perception) rolls whenever it chooses to check for hostile creatures within range of its senses, rolled by the DM. If it senses any, the ears perk up on the gun and it begins to emit a low growl. It will roll Wisdom (Insight) checks every minute you spend in the presence of a creature that is indifferent to you or does not know you personally. If it senses ill intent or hostility, it will react similarly.</p>
			<p class="indent">Bloodhound. Man’s Best Friend can cast find traps and 5th level hunter’s mark once per long rest. It decides when to cast these spells, and will maintain concentration on the latter.</p>
			<p class="indent">Guard Gun. When in combat, the gun will bark viciously when attacking, and will yip and whine when its wielder is badly hurt. The gun can take its own actions in combat, and will always take its turn before its wielder in the initiative order. The gun can use its action to make a Wisdom (Perception) check or give a bark of encouragement to you, granting you a d4 to use on your next attack roll or saving throw for 1 minute or until used.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">any firearm</set>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any firearm">Weapon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="weapon">ID_RDDT_AA_WEAPON_GROUP_FIREARMS</set>
			<set name="name-format">Man’s Best Friend</set>
			<set name="enhancement">3</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!--Next Item: Metalmancy, Page 25-->
	
</elements>