<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Pact Boon</name>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="pact-boon.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/homebrew/reddit/arcane-artillery/pact-boon.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Pact of the Firearm" type="Class Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_RDDT_AA_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_BOON_PACT_OF_THE_FIREARM">
		<supports>Pact Boon</supports>
		<requirements>ID_RDDT_AA_GRANTS_ARCANEARTILLERY_REQUIREMENT</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>You can use your action to create a pact weapon in your empty hand. You can choose the form that this firearm takes each time you create it . You are proficient with it while you wield it. This firearm counts as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage. This firearm uses a magical reserve of ammunition supplied by your patron that does not run out. You still have to reload it, however.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can only summon a primitive firearm as your pact weapon until you reach 13th level, when you can now summon firearms.</p>
			<p class="indent">Your pact firearm disappears if it is more than 5 feet away from you for 1 minute or more. It also disappears if you use this feature again, if you dismiss the weapon (no action required), or if you die. You can transform one magic firearm into your pact weapon by performing a special ritual while you hold the firearm. You perform the ritual over the course of 1 hour, which can be done during a short rest. You can then dismiss the weapon, shunting it into an extradimensional space, and it appears whenever you create your pact weapon thereafter. You can’t affect an artifact or a sentient weapon in this way. The weapon ceases being your pact weapon if you die, if you perform the 1-hour ritual on a different weapon, or if you use a 1-hour ritual to break your bond to it. The weapon appears at your feet if it is in the extradimensional space when the bond breaks.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can use your action to create a pact firearm in your empty hand. This weapon counts as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage. You can only summon a primitive firearm as your pact weapon until you reach 13th level, when you can now summon firearms.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules />
	</element>
</elements>