<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Feats</name>
		<description>This month's Unearthed Arcana introduces new feats for fifth edition.</description>
		<author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/articles/features/feats">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.0.3">
			<file name="20160606.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/unearthed-arcana/2016/20160606.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Unearthed Arcana: Feats" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_UNEARTHED_ARCANA_20160606">
		<description>
			<p>This month's Unearthed Arcana introduces new feats for fifth edition.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">UA20160606</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/articles/features/feats</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="playtest">true</set>
			<set name="release">20160606</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!-- WEAPON FEATS -->
	<element name="Fell Handed" type="Feat" source="Unearthed Arcana: Feats" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_FELL_HANDED">
		<description>
			<p>You master the handaxe, battleaxe, greataxe, warhammer, and maul. You gain the following benefits when using any of them:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls you make with the weapon.</li>
				<li>Whenever you have advantage on a melee attack roll you make with the weapon and hit, you can knock the target prone if the lower of the two d20 rolls would also hit the target.</li>
				<li>Whenever you have disadvantage on a melee attack roll you make with the weapon, the target takes bludgeoning damage equal to your Strength modifier (minimum of 0) if the attack misses but the higher of the two d20 rolls would have hit.</li>
				<li>If you use the Help action to aid an ally’s melee attack while you’re wielding the weapon, you knock the target’s shield aside momentarily. In addition to the ally gaining advantage on the attack roll, the ally gains a +2 bonus to the roll if the target is using a shield.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When using a handaxe, battleaxe, greataxe, warhammer or a maul, you gain +1 to attack rolls with that weapon. 
			Whenever you have advantage on a melee attack roll you make with the weapon and hit, you can knock the target prone if the lower of the two d20 rolls would also hit the target. Whenever you have disadvantage on a melee attack roll you make with the weapon, the target takes {{fell handed:damage}} bludgeoning damage if the attack misses but the higher of the two d20 rolls would have hit. 
			If you use the Help action to aid an ally’s melee attack while you’re wielding the weapon, you knock the target’s shield aside momentarily. In addition to the ally gaining advantage on the attack roll, the ally gains a +2 bonus to the roll if the target is using a shield.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="handaxe:attack" value="1" />
			<stat name="battleaxe:attack" value="1" />
			<stat name="greataxe:attack" value="1" />
			<stat name="warhammer:attack" value="1" />
			<stat name="maul:attack" value="1" />
			<stat name="fell handed:damage" value="0" bonus="fell handed" />
			<stat name="fell handed:damage" value="strength:modifier" bonus="fell handed" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Blade Mastery" type="Feat" source="Unearthed Arcana: Feats" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_BLADE_MASTERY">
		<description>
			<p>You master the shortsword, longsword, scimitar, rapier, and greatsword. You gain the following benefits when using any of them:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls you make with the weapon.</li>
				<li>On your turn, you can use your reaction to assume a parrying stance, provided you have the weapon in hand. Doing so grants you a +1 bonus to your AC until the start of your next turn or until you’re not holding the weapon.</li>
				<li>When you make an opportunity attack with the weapon, you have advantage on the attack roll.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When using a shortsword, longsword, scimitar, rapier, or a greatsword, you gain +1 to attack rolls with that weapon. 
			On your turn, you can use your reaction to assume a parrying stance, provided you have the weapon in hand. Doing so grants you a +1 bonus to your AC until the start of your next turn or until you’re not holding the weapon. When you make an opportunity attack with the weapon, you have advantage on the attack roll.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="shortsword:attack" value="1" />
			<stat name="longsword:attack" value="1" />
			<stat name="scimitar:attack" value="1" />
			<stat name="rapier:attack" value="1" />
			<stat name="greatsword:attack" value="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Flail Mastery" type="Feat" source="Unearthed Arcana: Feats" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_FLAIL_MASTERY">
		<description>
			<p>The flail is a tricky weapon to use, but you have spent countless hours mastering it. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls you make with the weapon.</li>
				<li>As a bonus action on your turn, you can prepare yourself to extend your flail to sweep over targets’ shields. Until the end of this turn, your attack rolls with a flail gain a +2 bonus against any target using a shield.</li>
				<li>When you hit with an opportunity attack using a flail, the target must succeed on a Strength saving throw (DC 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength modifier) or be knocked prone.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When using a flail, you gain +1 to attack rolls with that weapon.
			As a bonus action on your turn, you can prepare yourself to extend your flail to sweep over targets’ shields. Until the end of this turn, your attack rolls with a flail gain a +2 bonus against any target using a shield.
			When you hit with an opportunity attack using a flail, the target must succeed on a DC{{flail mastery:dc}} Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="flail:attack" value="1" />
			<stat name="flail mastery:dc" value="8" bonus="flail mastery" />
			<stat name="flail mastery:dc" value="proficiency" bonus="flail mastery" />
			<stat name="flail mastery:dc" value="strength:modifier" bonus="flail mastery" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Spear Mastery" type="Feat" source="Unearthed Arcana: Feats" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_SPEAR_MASTERY">
		<description>
			<p>Though the spear is a simple weapon to learn, it rewards you for the time you have taken to master it. You gain the following benefits.</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls you make with a spear.</li>
				<li>When you use a spear, its damage die changes from a d6 to a d8, and from a d8 to a d10 when wielded with two hands. (This benefit has no effect if another feature has already improved the weapon’s die.)</li>
				<li>You can set your spear to receive a charge. As a bonus action, choose a creature you can see that is at least 20 feet away from you. If that creatures moves within your spear’s reach on its next turn, you can make a melee attack against it with your spear as a reaction. If the attack hits, the target takes an extra 1d8 piercing damage, or an extra 1d10 piercing damage if you wield the spear with two hands.You can’t use this ability if the creature used the Disengage action before moving.</li>
				<li>As a bonus action on your turn, you can increase your reach with a spear by 5 feet for the rest of your turn.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When using a spear, you gain +1 to attack rolls with that weapon. 
			Its damage die changes from a d6 to a d8, and from a d8 to a d10 when wielded with two hands. (This benefit has no effect if another feature has already improved the weapon’s die.).
			You can set your spear to receive a charge. As a bonus action, choose a creature you can see that is at least 20 feet away from you. If that creatures moves within your spear’s reach on its next turn, you can make a melee attack against it with your spear as a reaction. If the attack hits, the target takes an extra 1d8 piercing damage, or an extra 1d10 piercing damage if you wield the spear with two hands.You can’t use this ability if the creature used the Disengage action before moving. 
			As a bonus action on your turn, you can increase your reach with a spear by 5 feet for the rest of your turn.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="spear:attack" value="1" />
			<!-- to implement: increase weapon's damage die -->
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- TOOL FEATS -->
	<element name="Alchemist" type="Feat" source="Unearthed Arcana: Feats" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_ALCHEMIST">
		<description>
			<p>You have studied the secrets of alchemy and are an expert in its practice, gaining the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
				<li>You gain proficiency with alchemist’s supplies. If you are already proficient with them, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with them.</li>
				<li>As an action, you can identify one potion within 5 feet of you, as if you had tasted it. You must see the liquid for this benefit to work.</li>
				<li>Over the course of any short rest, you can temporarily improve the potency of one potion of healing of any rarity. To use this benefit, you must have alchemist’s supplies with you, and the potion must be within reach. If the potion is drunk no more than 1 hour after the short rest ends, the creature drinking the potion can forgo the potion’s die roll and regains the maximum number of hit points that the potion can restore.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your Intelligence is increased by 1. You gain proficiency with alchemist’s supplies. If you are already proficient with them, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with them. As an action, you can identify one potion within 5 feet of you, as if you had tasted it. You must see the liquid for this benefit to work. Over the course of any short rest, you can temporarily improve the potency of one potion of healing of any rarity. To use this benefit, you must have alchemist’s supplies with you, and the potion must be within reach. If the potion is drunk no more than 1 hour after the short rest ends, the creature drinking the potion can forgo the potion’s die roll and regains the maximum number of hit points that the potion can restore.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="intelligence" value="1" />
			<grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_ALCHEMIST_SUPPLIES_DOUBLE_PROFICIENCY" requirements="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_ALCHEMISTS_SUPPLIES,!ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_ALCHEMIST_SUPPLIES_PROFICIENCY" />
			<grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_ALCHEMIST_SUPPLIES_PROFICIENCY" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_ALCHEMISTS_SUPPLIES" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Alchemist (Alchemist’s Supplies Proficiency)" type="Feat Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Feats" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_ALCHEMIST_SUPPLIES_PROFICIENCY">
		<supports>Alchemist</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You become proficient with Alchemist’s Supplies.</p>
			<div element="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_ALCHEMISTS_SUPPLIES" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_ALCHEMISTS_SUPPLIES" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Alchemist (Alchemist’s Supplies Double Proficiency)" type="Feat Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Feats" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_ALCHEMIST_SUPPLIES_DOUBLE_PROFICIENCY">
		<supports>Alchemist</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any check you make with Alchemist’s Supplies.</p>
			<div element="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_ALCHEMISTS_SUPPLIES" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="alchemist’s supplies:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Burglar" type="Feat" source="Unearthed Arcana: Feats" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_BURGLAR">
		<description>
			<p>You pride yourself on your quickness and your close study of certain clandestine activities. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Increase your Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
				<li>You gain proficiency with thieves’ tools. If you are already proficient with them, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with them.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your Dexterity is increased by 1. You gain proficiency with thieves’ tools. If you are already proficient with them, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with them.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
			<grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_BURGLAR_THIEVES_TOOLS_DOUBLE_PROFICIENCY" requirements="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_THIEVES_TOOLS,!ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_BURGLAR_THIEVES_TOOLS_PROFICIENCY" />
			<grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_BURGLAR_THIEVES_TOOLS_PROFICIENCY" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_THIEVES_TOOLS" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Burglar (Thieves’ Tools Proficiency)" type="Feat Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Feats" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_BURGLAR_THIEVES_TOOLS_PROFICIENCY">
		<supports>Burglar</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You become proficient with Thieves’ Tools.</p>
			<div element="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_THIEVES_TOOLS" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_THIEVES_TOOLS" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Burglar (Thieves’ Tools Double Proficiency)" type="Feat Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Feats" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_BURGLAR_THIEVES_TOOLS_DOUBLE_PROFICIENCY">
		<supports>Burglar</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any check you make with Thieves’ Tools.</p>
			<div element="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_THIEVES_TOOLS" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="thieves’ tools:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Gourmand" type="Feat" source="Unearthed Arcana: Feats" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_GOURMAND">
		<description>
			<p>You have mastered a variety of special recipes, allowing you to prepare exotic dishes with useful effects. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Increase your Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
				<li>You gain proficiency with cook’s utensils. If you are already proficient with them, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with them.</li>
				<li>As an action, you can inspect a drink or plate of food within 5 feet of you and determine whether it is poisoned, provided that you can see and smell it.</li>
				<li>During a long rest, you can prepare and serve a meal that helps you and your allies recover from the rigors of adventuring, provided you have suitable food, cook’s utensils, and other supplies on hand. The meal serves up to six people, and each person who eats it regains two additional Hit Dice at the end of the long rest. In addition, those who partake of the meal have advantage on Constitution saving throws against disease for the next 24 hours.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your Constitution is increased by 1. You gain proficiency with cook’s utensils. If you are already proficient with them, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with them. As an action, you can inspect a drink or plate of food within 5 feet of you and determine whether it is poisoned, provided that you can see and smell it. During a long rest, you can prepare and serve a meal that helps you and your allies recover from the rigors of adventuring, provided you have suitable food, cook’s utensils, and other supplies on hand. The meal serves up to six people, and each person who eats it regains two additional Hit Dice at the end of the long rest. In addition, those who partake of the meal have advantage on Constitution saving throws against disease for the next 24 hours.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="constitution" value="1" />
			<grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_GOURMAND_COOKS_UTENSILS_DOUBLE_PROFICIENCY" requirements="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_COOKS_UTENSILS,!ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_GOURMAND_COOKS_UTENSILS_PROFICIENCY" />
			<grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_GOURMAND_COOKS_UTENSILS_PROFICIENCY" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_COOKS_UTENSILS" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Gourmand (Cook’s Utensils Proficiency)" type="Feat Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Feats" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_GOURMAND_COOKS_UTENSILS_PROFICIENCY">
		<supports>Gourmand</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You become proficient with Cook’s Utensils.</p>
			<div element="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_COOKS_UTENSILS" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_COOKS_UTENSILS" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Gourmand (Cook’s Utensils Double Proficiency)" type="Feat Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Feats" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_GOURMAND_COOKS_UTENSILS_DOUBLE_PROFICIENCY">
		<supports>Gourmand</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any check you make with Cook’s Utensils.</p>
			<div element="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_COOKS_UTENSILS" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="cook’s utensils:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Master of Disguise" type="Feat" source="Unearthed Arcana: Feats" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_MASTER_OF_DISGUISE">
		<description>
			<p>You have honed your ability to shape your personality and to read the personalities of others. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
				<li>You gain proficiency with the disguise kit. If you are already proficient with it, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</li>
				<li>If you spend 1 hour observing a creature, you can then spend 8 hours crafting a disguise you can quickly don to mimic that creature. Making the disguise requires a disguise kit. You must make checks as normal to disguise yourself, but you can assume the disguise as an action.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20. You gain proficiency with the disguise kit. If you are already proficient with it, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it. If you spend 1 hour observing a creature, you can then spend 8 hours crafting a disguise you can quickly don to mimic that creature. Making the disguise requires a disguise kit. You must make checks as normal to disguise yourself, but you can assume the disguise as an action.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="charisma" value="1" />
			<grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_MASTER_OF_DISGUISE_DISGUISE_KIT_DOUBLE_PROFICIENCY" requirements="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_DISGUISE_KIT,!ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_MASTER_OF_DISGUISE_DISGUISE_KIT_PROFICIENCY" />
			<grant type="Feat Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_MASTER_OF_DISGUISE_DISGUISE_KIT_PROFICIENCY" requirements="!ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_DISGUISE_KIT" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Master of Disguise (Disguise Kit Proficiency)" type="Feat Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Feats" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_MASTER_OF_DISGUISE_DISGUISE_KIT_PROFICIENCY">
		<supports>Master of Disguise</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You become proficient with Disguise Kit.</p>
			<div element="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_DISGUISE_KIT" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_DISGUISE_KIT" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Master of Disguise (Disguise Kit Double Proficiency)" type="Feat Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Feats" id="ID_WOTC_UA_FEAT_MASTER_OF_DISGUISE_DISGUISE_KIT_DOUBLE_PROFICIENCY">
		<supports>Master of Disguise</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any check you make with Disguise Kit.</p>
			<div element="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_DISGUISE_KIT" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<stat name="disguise kit:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>