<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Unearthed Arcana: The Ranger, Revised</name>
        <description>A warrior who uses martial prowess and nature magic to combat threats on the edges of civilization..</description>
        <author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/articles/features/unearthed-arcana-ranger-revised">Wizards of the Coast</author>
        <update version="0.0.3">
            <file name="20160912.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/unearthed-arcana/2016/20160912.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    <element name="The Ranger, Revised" type="Class" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_The_Ranger,_Revised">
        <supports />
        <requirements />
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">A warrior who uses martial prowess and nature magic to combat threats on the edges of civilization.</p>
      <p>Rough and wild looking, a human stalks alone through the shadows of trees, hunting the ores he knows are planning a raid on a nearby farm. Clutching a shortsword in each hand, he becomes a whirlwind of steel, cutting down one enemy after another.</p>
      <p class="indent">After tumbling away from a cone of freezing air, an elf finds her feet and draws back her b ow to loose an arrow at the white dragon. Shrugging off the wave of fear that emanates from the dragon like the cold of its breath, she sends one arrow after another to find the gaps between the dragon’s thick scales.</p>
      <p class="indent">Holding his hand high, a half-elf whistles to the hawk that circles high above him, calling the bird back to his side. Whispering instructions in Elvish, he points to the owlbear he’s been tracking and sends the hawk to distract the creature while he readies his bow.</p>
      <p class="indent">Far from the bustle of cities and towns, past the hedges that shelter the most distant farms from the terrors of the wild, amid the dense-packed trees of trackless forests and across w ide and empty plains, rangers keep their unending watch.</p>
      <h4>DEADLY HUNTERS</h4>
      <p>Warriors of the wilderness, rangers specialize in hunting the monsters that threaten the edges of civilization—humanoid raiders, rampaging beasts and monstrosities, terrible giants, and deadly dragons. They learn to track their quarry as a predator does, moving stealthily through the wilds and hiding themselves in brush and rubble. Rangers focus their combat training on techniques that are particularly useful against their specific favored foes.</p>
      <p class="indent">Thanks to their familiarity with the wilds, rangers acquire the ability to cast spells that harness nature’s power, much as a druid does. Their spells, like their combat abilities, emphasize speed, stealth, and the hunt. A ranger’s talents and abilities are honed with deadly focus on the grim task of protecting the borderlands.</p>
      <h4>INDEPENDENT ADVENTURERS</h4>
      <p>Though a ranger might make a living as a hunter, a guide, or a tracker, a ranger’s true calling is to defend the outskirts of civilization from the ravages of monsters and humanoid hordes that press in from the wild. In some places, rangers gather in secretive orders or join forces with druidic circles. Many rangers, though, are independent almost to a fault, knowing that, when a dragon or a band of orc s attacks, a ranger might be the first—and possibly the last—line of defense.</p>
      <p class="indent">This fierce independence makes rangers well suited to adventuring, since they are accustomed to life far from the comforts of a dry bed and a hot bath. Faced with city-bred adventurers w ho grouse and whine about the hardships of the wild, rangers respond with some mixture of amusement, frustration, and compassion. But they quickly learn that other adventurers who can carry their own weight in a fight against civilization’s foes are worth any extra burden. Coddled city folk might not know how to feed themselves or find fresh water in the wild, but they make up for it in other ways.</p>
      <h4>CREATING A RANGER</h4>
      <p>As you create your ranger character, consider the nature of the training that gave you your particular capabilities. Did you train with a single mentor, wandering the wilds together until you mastered the ranger’s ways? Did you leave your apprenticeship, or was your mentor slain— perhaps by the same kind of monster that became your favored enemy? Or perhaps you learned your skills as part of a band of rangers affiliated with a druidic circle, trained in mystic paths as well as wilderness lore. You might be self-taught, a recluse who learned combat skills, tracking, and even a magical connection to nature through the necessity of surviving in the wilds.</p>
      <p class="indent">What’s the source of your particular hatred of a certain kind of enemy? Did a monster kill someone you loved or destroy your home village? Or did you see too much of the destruction these monsters cause and commit yourself to reining in their depredations? Is your adventuring career a continuation of your work in protecting the borderlands, or a significant change? What made you join up with a band of adventurers? Do you find it challenging to teach new allies the ways of the wild, or do you welcome the relief from solitude that they offer?</p>
      <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
      <p>You can make a ranger quickly by following these suggestions. First, make Dexterity your highest ability score, followed by Wisdom. (Some rangers who focus on two-weapon fighting make Strength higher than Dexterity.) Second, choose the outlander background.</p>
      <h3>CLASS FEATURES</h3>
      <p>As a ranger, you gain the following class features.</p>
      <h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
      <p>
        <span class="emphasis">Hit Dice:</span>1d10 per ranger level
        <br />
        <span class="emphasis">Hit Points at 1st Level:</span>10 + your Constitution modefier
        <br />
        <span class="emphasis">Hit Points at Higher Levels:</span>1d10 (or 6) + your Constitution modifier per ranger level after 1st
        <br />
      </p>
      <h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
      <p>
        <span class="emphasis">Armor:</span>Light armor, medium armor, shields
        <br />
        <span class="emphasis">Weapons:</span>Simple weapons, martial weapons
        <br />
        <span class="emphasis">Tools:</span>None
        <br />
      </p>
      <p>
        <span class="emphasis">Saving Throws:</span>Strength, Dexterity
        <br />
        <span class="emphasis">Skills:</span>Choose three skills from Animal Handling, Athletics, Insight, Investigation, Nature, Perception, Stealth, and Survival
        <br />
      </p>
      <h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
      <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>
          <i>(a)</i> scale mail or 
          <i>(b)</i> leather armor
        </li>
        <li>
          <i>(a)</i> two shortswords or 
          <i>(b)</i> two simple melee weapons
        </li>
        <li>
          <i>(a)</i> a dungeoneer’s pack or 
          <i>(b)</i> an explorer’s pack
        </li>
        <li>A longbow and a quiver of 20 arrows</li>
            </ul>
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger, Revised_FAVORED_ENEMY" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The Ranger, Revised_NATURAL_EXPLORER" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The Ranger, Revised_FIGHTING_STYLE" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The Ranger, Revised_SPELLCASTING" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The Ranger, Revised_PRIMEVAL_AWARENESS" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The Ranger, Revised_RANGER_CONCLAVE" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT_The Ranger, Revised" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The Ranger, Revised_RANGER_CONCLAVE_FEATURE" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The Ranger, Revised_GREATER_FAVORED_ENEMY" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The Ranger, Revised_FLEET_OF_FOOT" />
           <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The Ranger, Revised_HIDE_IN_PLAIN_SIGHT" />
           <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The Ranger, Revised_VANISH" />
           <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The Ranger, Revised_FERAL_SENSES" />
           <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The Ranger, Revised_FOE_SLAYER" />
       </description>
        <sheet display="false">
      <description>A warrior who uses martial prowess and nature magic to combat threats on the edges of civilization.</description>
    </sheet>
    <setters>
      <set name="short">A warrior who uses martial prowess and nature magic to combat threats on the edges of civilization.</set>
      <set name="hd">d10</set>
      <set name="spellcaster">true</set>
      <set name="spellcastingAbility">Wisdom</set>
            <set name="sourceUrl">http://dnd.wizards.com/articles/unearthed-arcana/The Ranger, Revised</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false"/>
        <rules>
        <!-- <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_HALF" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS"/> -->
      <!-- <grant type="Grants" name="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_AVERAGE_HP_D10" /> -->

      <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA_MULTICLASS_THE_RANGER,_REVISED" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA_MULTICLASS_THE_RANGER,_REVISED" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA_MULTICLASS_THE_RANGER,_REVISED" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA_MULTICLASS_THE_RANGER,_REVISED" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA_MULTICLASS_THE_RANGER,_REVISED" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA_MULTICLASS_THE_RANGER,_REVISED" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA_MULTICLASS_THE_RANGER,_REVISED" />
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (THE RANGER, REVISED)" supports="Skill,Ranger" number="3" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA_MULTICLASS_THE_RANGER,_REVISED" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_FAVORED_ENEMY" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_NATURAL_EXPLORER" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_FIGHTING_STYLE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_SPELLCASTING" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_PRIMEVAL_AWARENESS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_RANGER_CONCLAVE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT_The_Ranger,_Revised" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_GREATER_FAVORED_ENEMY" level="6" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_FLEET_OF_FOOT" level="8" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_HIDE_IN_PLAIN_SIGHT" level="10" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_VANISH" level="14" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_FERAL_SENSES" level="10" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_FOE_SLAYER" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_WOTC_UA_MULTICLASS_The_Ranger,_Revised">
            <prerequisite>Dexterity 13 and Wisdom 13</prerequisite>
      <requirements>([dex:13],[wis:13])</requirements>
      <setters>
        <set name="multiclass proficiencies">Light armor, medium armor, shields, simple weapons, martial weapons, one skill from the class’s skill list</set>
      </setters>
      <rules>
        <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />

        <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
        <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
        <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
        <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
        <grant type="Proficiency" name="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
        <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (THE RANGER, REVISED)" supports="Skill,Ranger" number="1"/>
      </rules>
    </multiclass>
        <spellcasting name="The Ranger, Revised" ability="Wisdom" allowReplace="true">
            <list>The Ranger, Revised</list>
        </spellcasting>
    </element>
   <element name="Favored Enemy" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_FAVORED_ENEMY">
    <description>
      <p>Beginning at 1st level, you have significant experience studying, tracking, hunting, and even talking to a certain type of enemy.</p>
      <p class="indent">Choose a  type of favored enemy: beasts, fey, humanoids, monstrosities, or undead. You gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with weapon attacks against creatures of the chosen type.</p>
      <p class="indent">You have advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks to track your favored enemies, as well as on Intelligence checks to recall information about them.</p>
      <p class="indent">When you gain this feature, you also learn one language of your choice, typically one spoken by your favored enemy or creatures associated with it. However, you are free to pick any language you wish to learn.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You have advantage on Survival checks to track your favored enemies, as well as on Intelligence checks to recall information about them.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <select type="Class Feature" name="Favored Enemy" supports="Favored Enemy" level="1" />
      <select type="Language" name="Language (Favored Enemy)" level="1" />
    </element>
    <element name="Natural Explorer" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_NATURAL_EXPLORER">
    <description>
      <p>You are a master of navigating the natural world, and you react with swift and decisive action when attacked. This grants you the following benefits:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>You ignore difficult terrain.</li>
        <li>You have advantage on initiative rolls</li>
        <li>On your first turn during combat, you have advantage on attack rolls against creatures that have not yet acted.</li>
      </ul>
      <p class="indent">In  addition, you are skilled at navigating the wilderness. You gain the following benefits when traveling for an our    or more:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Difficult terrain doesn’t slow your group’s travel.</li>
        <li>Your group can’t become lost except by magical means.</li>
        <li>Even when you are engaged in another activity while traveling (such as foraging, navigating, or tracking), you remain alert to danger.</li>
        <li>If you are traveling alone, you can move stealthily at a normal pace.</li>
        <li>When you forage, you find twice as much food as you normally would.</li>
        <li>While tracking other creatures, you also learn their exact number, their sizes, and how long ago they passed through the area.</li>
      </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
    </element>
    <element name="Fighting Style" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_FIGHTING_STYLE">
    <description>
      <p>At 2nd level, you adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options. You can’t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</p>
      <h5>ARCHERY</h5>
      <p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</p>
      <h5>DEFENSE</h5>
      <p>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</p>
      <h5>DUELING</h5>
      <p>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</p>
      <h5>TWO-WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
      <p>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description></description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style" supports="Fighting Style,Ranger" level="2"/>
    </rules>
  </element>
    <element name="Spellcasting" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_SPELLCASTING">
    <description>
      <p>By the time you reach 2nd level, you have learned to use the magical essence of nature to cast spells, much as a druid does. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the ranger spell list.</p>
      <h5>SPELL SLOTS</h5>
      <p>The Ranger table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</p>
      <p class="indent">For example, if you know the 1st-level spell animal friendship and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast animal friendship using either slot.</p>
      <h5>SPELLS KNOWN OF 1ST LEVEL AND HIGHER</h5>
      <p>You know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the ranger spell list.</p>
      <p class="indent">The Spells Known column of the Ranger table shows when you learn more ranger spells of your choice. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 5th level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.</p>
      <p class="indent">Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the ranger spells you know and replace it with another spell from the ranger spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
      <h5>SPELLCASTING ABILITY</h5>
      <p>Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your ranger spells, since your magic draws on your attunement to nature. You use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a ranger spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
      <p class="indent">
        <b>Spell save DC = 8</b> + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier
      </p>
      <p class="indent">
        <b>Spell attack modifier =</b> your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier
      </p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false">
      <description></description>
    </sheet>
    <spellcasting name="The Ranger, Revised" ability="Wisdom" allowReplace="true">
      <list>The Ranger, Revised</list>
    </spellcasting>
    <rules>
        <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_HALF" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS"/>

        <stat name="ranger:spellcasting:slots:1" value="+2" level="2" />
        <stat name="ranger:spellcasting:slots:1" value="+1" level="3" />
        <stat name="ranger:spellcasting:slots:1" value="+1" level="5" />
        <stat name="ranger:spellcasting:slots:2" value="+2" level="5" />
        <stat name="ranger:spellcasting:slots:2" value="+1" level="7" />
        <stat name="ranger:spellcasting:slots:3" value="+2" level="9" />
        <stat name="ranger:spellcasting:slots:3" value="+1" level="11" />
        <stat name="ranger:spellcasting:slots:4" value="+1" level="13" />
        <stat name="ranger:spellcasting:slots:4" value="+1" level="15" />
        <stat name="ranger:spellcasting:slots:4" value="+1" level="17" />
        <stat name="ranger:spellcasting:slots:5" value="+1" level="17" />
        <stat name="ranger:spellcasting:slots:5" value="+1" level="19" />

        <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (THE RANGER, REVISED)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="2" number="2" spellcasting="Ranger"/>
        <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (THE RANGER, REVISED)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="3" spellcasting="Ranger" />
        <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (THE RANGER, REVISED)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="5" spellcasting="Ranger" />
        <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (THE RANGER, REVISED)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="7" spellcasting="Ranger" />
        <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (THE RANGER, REVISED)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="9" spellcasting="Ranger" />
        <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (THE RANGER, REVISED)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="11" spellcasting="Ranger" />
        <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (THE RANGER, REVISED)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="13" spellcasting="Ranger" />
        <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (THE RANGER, REVISED)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="15" spellcasting="Ranger" />
        <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (THE RANGER, REVISED)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="17" spellcasting="Ranger" />
        <select type="Spell" name="Spellcasting (THE RANGER, REVISED)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="19" spellcasting="Ranger" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Primeval Awareness" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_PRIMEVAL_AWARENESS">
    <sheet>
    <description>
      <p>Beginning at 3rd level, your mastery of ranger lore allows you to establish a powerful link to beasts and to the land around you.</p> 
        <p class="indent">You have an innate ability to communicate with beasts, and they recognize you as a kindred spirit. Through sounds and gestures, you can communicate simple ideas to a beast as an action, and can read its basic mood and intent. You learn its emotional state, whether it is affected by magic of any sort, its short-term needs (such as food or safety), and actions you can take (if any) to persuade it to not attack.</p> 
        <p class="indent">You cannot use this ability against a creature that you have attacked within the past 10 minutes.</p> 
        <p class="indent">Additionally, you can attune your senses to determine if any of your favored enemies lurk nearby. By spending 1 uninterrupted minute in concentration (as if you were concentrating on a spell), you can sense whether any of your favored enemies are present within 5 miles of you. This feature reveals which of your favored enemies are present, their numbers, and the creatures’ general direction and distance (in miles) from you.</p> 
        <p class="indent">If there are multiple groups of your favored enemies within range, you learn this information for each group.</p>
    </description>
    </sheet>
    <rules />
  </element>
    <element name="Ability Score Improvement (The Ranger, Revised)" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT_The_Ranger,_Revised">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (The Ranger, Revised 4)" supports="Improvement Option,The Ranger, Revised,4" default="ID_INTERNAL_CLASS_FEATURE_ASI_4_The Ranger, Revised" level="4" requirements=""/>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (The Ranger, Revised 8)" supports="Improvement Option,The Ranger, Revised,8" default="ID_INTERNAL_CLASS_FEATURE_ASI_8_The Ranger, Revised" level="8" requirements=""/>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (The Ranger, Revised 12)" supports="Improvement Option,The Ranger, Revised,12" default="ID_INTERNAL_CLASS_FEATURE_ASI_12_The Ranger, Revised" level="12" requirements=""/>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (The Ranger, Revised 16)" supports="Improvement Option,The Ranger, Revised,16" default="ID_INTERNAL_CLASS_FEATURE_ASI_16_The Ranger, Revised" level="16" requirements=""/>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (The Ranger, Revised 19)" supports="Improvement Option,The Ranger, Revised,19" default="ID_INTERNAL_CLASS_FEATURE_ASI_19_The Ranger, Revised" level="19" requirements=""/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Greater Favored Enemy" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_GREATER_FAVORED_ENEMY">
    <description>
      <p>At 6th level, you are ready to hunt even deadlier game.</p>
      <p class="indent">Choose a type of greater favored enemy: aberrations, celestials, constructs, dragons, elementals, fiends, or giants. You gain all the benefits against this chosen enemy that you normally gain against your favored enemy, including an additional language. Your bonus to damage rolls against all your favored enemies increases to +4.</p>
      <p class="indent">Additionally, you have advantage on saving throws against the spells and abilities used by a greater favored enemy</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
    <rules>
      <select type="Class Feature" name="Greater Favored Enemy" supports="Greater Favored Enemy" level="6" />
      <select type="Language" name="Language (Greater Favored Enemy)" level="6" />
  </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Fleet of Foot" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_FLEET_OF_FOOT">
        <sheet>
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 8th level, you can use the Dash action as a bonus action on your turn.</p>
        </description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Hide in Plain Sight" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_HIDE_IN_PLAIN_SIGHT">
    <description>
      <p>Starting at 10th level, you can remain perfectly still for long periods of time to set up ambushes.</p>
      <p class="indent">When you attempt to hide on your turn, you can opt to not move on that turn. If you avoid moving, creatures that attempt to detect you take a −10 penalty to their Wisdom (Perception) checks until the start of your next turn. You lose this benefit if you move or fall prone, either voluntarily or because of some external effect. You are still automatically detected if any effect or action causes you to no longer be hidden. If you are still hidden on your next turn, you can continue to remain motionless and gain this benefit until you are detected.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You can avoid moving to better hide yourself. You impose a -10 to enemy Perception checks as long as you remain there without moving or taking actions.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules></rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Vanish" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_VANISH">
    <description>
      <p>Starting at 14th level, you can use the Hide action as a bonus action on your turn. Also, you can’t be tracked by nonmagical means, unless you choose to leave a trail.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You can use the Hide action as a bonus action on your turn. Also, you can’t be tracked by nonmagical means, unless you choose to leave a trail.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules />
  </element>
  <element name="Feral Senses" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_FERAL_SENSES">
    <description>
      <p>At 18th level, you gain preternatural senses that help you fight creatures you can’t see. When you attack a creature you can’t see, your inability to see it doesn’t impose disadvantage on your attack rolls against it.</p>
      <p class="indent">You are also aware of the location of any invisible creature within 30 feet of you, provided that the creature isn’t hidden from you and you aren’t blinded or deafened.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When you attack a creature you can’t see, your inability to see it doesn’t impose disadvantage on your attack rolls against it. You are also aware of the location of any invisible creature within 30 feet of you, provided that the creature isn’t hidden from you and you aren’t blinded or deafened.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules />
  </element>
  <element name="Foe Slayer" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_FOE_SLAYER">
    <description>
      <p>At 20th level, you become an unparalleled hunter of your enemies. Once on each of your turns, you can add your Wisdom modifier to the attack roll or the damage roll of an attack you make against one of your favored enemies. You can choose to use this feature before or after the roll, but before any effects of the roll are applied.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Once on each of your turns, you can add your Wisdom modifier to the attack roll or the damage roll of an attack you make against one of your favored enemies. You can choose to use this feature before or after the roll, but before any effects of the roll are applied.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <stat name="foe slayer:attack" value="Wisdom Modifier" />
      <stat name="foe slayer:damage" value="Wisdom Modifier" />
    </rules>
  </element>
        
    <!-- Hunter Conclave -->
  <element name="Hunter Conclave" type="Archetype" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_The_Ranger,_Revised_HUNTER">
    <supports>Ranger Conclave</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Emulating the Hunter archetype means accepting your place as a bulwark between civilization and the terrors of the wilderness. As you walk the Hunter’s path, you learn specialized techniques for fighting the threats you face, from rampaging ogres and hordes of orcs to towering giants and terrifying dragons.</p>
      <div element="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_HUNTERS_PREY" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_DEFENSIVE_TACTICS" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_MULTIATTACK" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_SUPERIOR_HUNTERS_DEFENSE" />
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Emulating the Hunter archetype means accepting your place as a bulwark between civilization and the terrors of the wilderness.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_HUNTERS_PREY" level="3" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_DEFENSIVE_TACTICS" level="7" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_MULTIATTACK" level="11" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_SUPERIOR_HUNTERS_DEFENSE" level="15" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Hunter’s Prey" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_HUNTERS_PREY">
    <description>
      <p>At 3rd level, you gain one of the following features of your choice.</p>
      <p>
        <span class="feature">Colossus Slayer.</span>Your tenacity can wear down the most potent foes. When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, the creature takes an extra 1d8 damage if it’s below its hit point maximum. You can deal this extra damage only once per turn.
        <br/>
        <span class="feature">Giant Killer.</span>When a Large or larger creature within 5 feet of you hits or misses you with an attack, you can use your reaction to attack that creature immediately after its attack, provided that you can see the creature.
        <br/>
        <span class="feature">Horde Breaker.</span>Once on each of your turns when you make a w eapon attack, you can make another attack with the same weapon against a different creature that is within 5 feet of the original target and within range of your weapon.
        <br/>
      </p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description></description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Hunter’s Prey" supports="Hunters Pray" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Extra Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_EXTRA_ATTACK">
    <description>
      <p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Extra Attack" supports="Extra Attack" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Defensive Tactics" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_DEFENSIVE_TACTICS">
    <description>
      <p>At 7th level, you gain one of the following features of your choice.</p>
      <p>
        <span class="feature">Escape the Horde.</span>Opportunity attacks against you are made with disadvantage.
        <br/>
        <span class="feature">Multiattack Defense.</span>When a creature hits you with an attack, you gain a +4 bonus to AC against all subsequent attacks made by that creature for the rest of the turn.
        <br/>
        <span class="feature">Steel Will.</span>You have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.
        <br/>
      </p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description></description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Defensive Tactics" supports="Defensive Tactics" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Multiattack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_MULTIATTACK">
    <description>
      <p>At 11th level, you gain one of the following features of your choice.</p>
      <p>
        <span class="feature">Volley.</span>You can use your action to make a ranged attack against any number of creatures within 10 feet of a point you can see within your w eapon’s range. You must have ammunition for each target, as normal, and you make a separate attack roll for each target.
        <br/>
        <span class="feature">Whirlwind Attack.</span>You can use your action to make a melee attack against any number of creatures within 5 feet of you, with a separate attack roll for each target.
        <br/>
      </p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description></description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Multiattack" supports="Multiattack" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Superior Hunter’s Defense" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_SUPERIOR_HUNTERS_DEFENSE">
    <description>
      <p>At 15th level, you gain one of the following features of your choice.</p>
      <p>
        <span class="feature">Evasion.</span>You can nimbly dodge out of the way of certain area effects, such as a red dragon’s fiery breath or a lightning bolt spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.
        <br/>
        <span class="feature">Stand Against the Tide.</span>When a hostile creature misses you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to force that creature to repeat the same attack against another creature (other than itself) of your choice.
        <br/>
        <span class="feature">Uncanny Dodge.</span>When an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack’s damage against you.
        <br/>
      </p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description></description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Superior Hunter’s Defense" supports="Superior Hunters Defense" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  <!-- Hunter’s Prey Options -->
  <element name="Colossus Slayer" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_HUNTERS_PREY_COLOSSUS_SLAYER">
    <supports>Hunters Pray</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Your tenacity can wear down the most potent foes. When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, the creature takes an extra 1d8 damage if it’s below its hit point maximum. You can deal this extra damage only once per turn.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Your tenacity can wear down the most potent foes. When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, the creature takes an extra 1d8 damage if it’s below its hit point maximum. You can deal this extra damage only once per turn.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules></rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Giant Killer" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_HUNTERS_PREY_GIANT_KILLER">
    <supports>Hunters Pray</supports>
    <description>
      <p>When a Large or larger creature within 5 feet of you hits or misses you with an attack, you can use your reaction to attack that creature immediately after its attack, provided that you can see the creature.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When a Large or larger creature within 5 feet of you hits or misses you with an attack, you can use your reaction to attack that creature immediately after its attack, provided that you can see the creature.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules></rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Horde Breaker" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_HUNTERS_PREY_HORDE_BREAKER">
    <supports>Hunters Pray</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Once on each of your turns when you make a w eapon attack, you can make another attack with the same weapon against a different creature that is within 5 feet of the original target and within range of your weapon.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Once on each of your turns when you make a w eapon attack, you can make another attack with the same weapon against a different creature that is within 5 feet of the original target and within range of your weapon.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules></rules>
  </element>
  <!-- Defensive Tactics -->
  <element name="Escape the Horde" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_DEFENSIVE_TACTICS_ESCAPE_THE_HORDE">
    <supports>Defensive Tactics</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Opportunity attacks against you are made with disadvantage.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Opportunity attacks against you are made with disadvantage.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules></rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Multiattack Defense" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_DEFENSIVE_TACTICS_MULTIATTACK_DEFENSE">
    <supports>Defensive Tactics</supports>
    <description>
      <p>When a creature hits you with an attack, you gain a +4 bonus to AC against all subsequent attacks made by that creature for the rest of the turn.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When a creature hits you with an attack, you gain a +4 bonus to AC against all subsequent attacks made by that creature for the rest of the turn.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules></rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Steel Will" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_DEFENSIVE_TACTICS_STEEL_WILL">
    <supports>Defensive Tactics</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules></rules>
  </element>
  <!-- Multiattack -->
  <element name="Volley" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_MULTIATTACK_VOLLEY">
    <supports>Multiattack</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You can use your action to make a ranged attack against any number of creatures within 10 feet of a point you can see within your weapon’s range. You must have ammunition for each target, as normal, and you make a separate attack roll for each target.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You can use your action to make a ranged attack against any number of creatures within 10 feet of a point you can see within your weapon’s range. You must have ammunition for each target, as normal, and you make a separate attack roll for each target.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules></rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Whirlwind Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_MULTIATTACK_WHIRLWIND_ATTACK">
    <supports>Multiattack</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You can use your action to make a melee attack against any number of creatures within 5 feet of you, with a separate attack roll for each target.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You can use your action to make a melee attack against any number of creatures within 5 feet of you, with a separate attack roll for each target.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules></rules>
  </element>
  <!-- Superior Hunter’s Defense -->
  <element name="Evasion" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_SUPERIOR_HUNTERS_DEFENSE_EVASION">
    <supports>Superior Hunters Defense</supports>
    <description>
      <p>You can nimbly dodge out of the way of certain area effects, such as a red dragon’s fiery breath or a lightning bolt spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You can nimbly dodge out of the way of certain area effects, such as a red dragon’s fiery breath or a lightning bolt spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules></rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Stand Against the Tide" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_SUPERIOR_HUNTERS_DEFENSE_STAND_AGAINST_THE_TIDE">
    <supports>Superior Hunters Defense</supports>
    <description>
      <p>When a hostile creature misses you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to force that creature to repeat the same attack against another creature (other than itself) of your choice.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When a hostile creature misses you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to force that creature to repeat the same attack against another creature (other than itself) of your choice.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules></rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Uncanny Dodge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_SUPERIOR_HUNTERS_DEFENSE_UNCANNY_DODGE">
    <supports>Superior Hunters Defense</supports>
    <description>
      <p>When an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack’s damage against you.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack’s damage against you.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules></rules>
  </element>
    
    <!-- Beast Conclave -->
  <element name="Beast Conclave" type="Archetype" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_The_Ranger,_Revised_BEAST">
    <supports>Ranger Conclave</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Many rangers are more at home in the wilds than in civilization, to the point where animals consider them kin. Rangers of the Beast Conclave develop a close bond with a beast, then further strengthen that bond through the use of magic</p>
      <div element="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_ANIMAL_COMPANION" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_COMPANIONS_BOND" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_COORDINATED_ATTACK" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_BEASTS_DEFENSE" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_STORM_OF_CLAWS_AND_FANGS" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_SUPERIOR_BEASTS_DEFENSE" />
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>The Beast Conclave archetype embodies a friendship between the civilized races and the beasts of the world.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_ANIMAL_COMPANION" level="3" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_COMPANIONS_BOND" level="3" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_COORDINATED_ATTACK" level="5" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_BEASTS_DEFENSE" level="7" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_STORM_OF_CLAWS_AND_FANGS" level="11" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_RANGER_SUPERIOR_BEASTS_DEFENSE" level="15" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Animal Companion" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_ANIMAL_COMPANION">
    <description>
      <p>At 3rd level, you learn to use your magic to create a powerful bond with a creature of the natural world.</p>
      <p class="indent">With 8 hours of work and the expenditure of 50 gp worth of rare herbs and fine food, you call forth an animal from the wilderness to serve as your faithful companion. You normally select your companion from among the following animals: an ape, a black bear, a boar, a giant badger, a giant weasel, a mule, a panther, or a wolf. However, your DM might pick one of these animals for you, based on the surrounding terrain and on what types of creatures would logically be present in the area.</p>
      <p class="indent"> At the end of the 8 hours, your animal companion appears and gains all the benefits of your Companion’s Bond ability. You can have only one animal companion at a time. If your animal companion is ever slain, the magical bond you share allows you to return it to life. With 8 hours of work and the expenditure of 25 gp worth of rare herbs and fine food, you call forth your companion’s spirit and use your magic to create a new body for it. You can return an animal companion to life in this manner even if you do not possess any part of its body.</p>
      <p class="indent">If you use this ability to return a former animal companion to life while you have a current animal companion, your current companion leaves you and is replaced by the restored companion.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You gain a beast companion that accompanies you on your adventures and is trained to fight alongside you.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <!-- COMPANION -->
      <select type="Companion" name="Animal Companion" supports="" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Companion’s Bond" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_COMPANIONS_BOND">
    <description>
      <p>Your animal companion gains a variety of benefits while it is linked to you. The animal companion loses its Multiattack action, if it has one. The companion obeys your commands as best it can. It rolls for initiative like any other creature, but you determine its actions, decisions, attitudes, and so on. If you are incapacitated or absent, your companion acts on its own. When using your Natural Explorer feature, you and your animal companion can both move stealthily at a normal pace.</p>
      <p class="indent"> Your animal companion has abilities and game statistics determined in part by your level. Your companion uses your proficiency bonus rather than its own. In addition to the areas where it normally uses its proficiency bonus, an animal companion also adds its proficiency bonus to its AC and to its damage rolls. Your animal companion gains proficiency in two skills of your choice. It also becomes proficient with all saving throws. For each level you gain after 3rd, your animal companion gains an additional hit die and increases its hit points accordingly.</p>
      <p class="indent"> Whenever you gain the Ability Score Improvement Class feature, your companion’s abilities also improve. Your companion can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or it can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, your companion can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature unless its description specifies otherwise. Your companion shares your alignment, and has a personality trait and a flaw that you can roll for or select from the tables below. Your companion shares your ideal, and its bond is always, “The ranger who travels with me is a beloved companion for whom I would gladly give my life.”</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Your Animal Companion functions like a seperate character that can act independently if it's Ranger is not nearby It gains a new hit die and ability score improvements as the Ranger it is bonded to does it benefits from the Ranger's ability of Natural explorer and can add the proficiency bonus you two share to the following areas: Armor Class, skills, Saving Throws, Attack bonus, and damage rolls.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules />
  </element>
  </element>
  <element name="Coordinated Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_COORDINATED_ATTACK">
    <description>
      <p>Beginning at 5th level, you and your animal companion form a more potent fighting team. When you use the Attack action on your turn, if your companion can see you, it can use its reaction to make a melee attack.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When you use the Attack action on your turn, if your companion can see you, it can use its reaction to make a melee attack.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules />
  </element>
  <element name="Beast's Defense" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_BEASTS_DEFENSE">
    <description>
      <p>At 7th level, while your companion can see you, it has advantage on all saving throws.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>While your companion can see you, it has advantage on all saving throws.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules />
  </element>
  <element name="Storm of CLaw and Fangs" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_STORM_OF_CLAW_AND_FANGS">
    <description>
      <p>At 11th level, your companion can use its action to make a melee attack against each creature of its choice within 5 feet of it, with a separate attack roll for each target. </p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Your companion can use its action to make a melee attack against each creature of its choice within 5 feet of it, with a separate attack roll for each target.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules />
  </element>
  <element name="Superior Beast's Defense" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPEFEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_SUPERIOR_BEASTS_DEFENSE">
    <description>
      <p>At 15th level, whenever an attacker that your companion can see hits it with an attack, it can use its reaction to halve the attack’s damage against it.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Whenever an attacker that your companion can see hits it with an attack, it can use its reaction to halve the attack’s damage against it.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules />
  </element>
  <!-- Favored Enemies-->
  <element name="Beasts" type="Class Feature" stype="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_FAVORED_ENEMY_BEAST">
    <supports>Monster Type, Favored Enemy</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Beasts are nonhumanoid creatures that are a natural part of the fantasy ecology. Some of them have magical powers, but most are unintelligent and lack any society or language. Beasts include all varieties of ordinary animals, dinosaurs, and giant versions of animals.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description></description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <element name="Fey" type="Class Feature" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_FAVORED_ENEMY_FEY">
    <supports>Monster Type, Favored Enemy</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Fey are magical creatures closely tied to the forces of nature. They dwell in twilight groves and misty forests. In some worlds, they are closely tied to the Feywild, also called the Plane of Faerie. Some are also found in the Outer Planes, particularly the planes of Arborea and the Beastlands. Fey include dryads, pixies, and satyrs.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description></description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <element name="Monstrosities" type="Class Feature" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_FAVORED_ENEMY_BEAST_MONSTROSITIES">
    <supports>Monster Type, Favored Enemy</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Monstrosities are monsters in the strictest sensefrightening creatures that are not ordinary, not truly natural, and almost never benign. Some are the results of magical experimentation gone awry (such as owl bears), and others ,are the product-of terrible curses (including minotaurs and yuan-ti). They defy categorization, and in some sense serve as a catch-all category for creatures that don't fit into any other type.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description></description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <element name="Undead" type="Class Feature" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_FAVORED_ENEMY_UNDEAD">
    <supports>Monster Type, Favored Enemy</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Undead are once-living creatures brought to a horrifying state of undeath through the practice of necromantic magic or some unholy curse. Undead include walking corpses, such as vampires and zombies, as well as bodiless spirits, such as ghosts and specters.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description></description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <element name="Humanoids" type="Class Feature" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOIDS">
    <supports>Monster Type</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Humanoids are the main peoples of the D&amp;D world, both civilized and savage, including humans and a tremendous variety of other species. They have language and culture, few if any innate magical abilities (though most humanoids can learn spellcasting), and a bipedal form. The most common humanoid races are the ones most suitable as player characters: humans, dwarves, elves, and halflings. Almost as numerous but far more savage and brutal, and almost uniformly evil, are the races of goblinoids (golblins, hobgoblins, and bugbears), orcs, gnolls, lizardfolk, and kobolds. A variety of humanoids appear throughout this book, but the races detailed in the Player's Handbook- with the exception of drow-are dealt with in appendix B. That appendix gives you a number of stat blocks that you·can use to make various members of those races.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description></description>
    </sheet>
</element>
<!-- Greater Favored Enemies-->
<element name="Aberrations" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_GREATER_FAVORED_ENEMY_ABERRATIONS">
    <supports>Monster Type, Greater Favored Enemy</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Aberrations are utterly alien beings. Many of them have innate magical abilities drawn from the creature's alien mind rather than the mystical forces of the world. The quintessential aberrations are aboleths, beholders, mind fiayers, and slaadi.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description></description>
    </sheet>
    </element>
  <element name="Celestials" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_GREATER_FAVORED_ENEMY_CELESTIALS">
    <supports>Monster Type, Greater Favored Enemy</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Celestials are creatures native to the Upper Planes. Many of them are the servants of deities, employed as messengers or agents in the mortal realm and throughout the planes. Celestials are good by nature, so the exceptional celestial who strays from a good alignment is a horrifying rarity. Celestials include angels, couatls, and pegasi.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description></description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <element name="Constructs" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_GREATER_FAVORED_ENEMY_CONSTRUCTS">
    <supports>Monster Type, Greater Favored Enemy</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Constructs are made, not born. Some are programmed by their creators to'follow a simple set of instructions, while others are imbued with sentience and capable of independent thought. Golems are the iconic constructs. Many creatures native to the outer plane of Mechanus, such as modrons, are constructs shaped from the raw material of the plane by the will of more powerful creatures.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description></description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <element name="Dragons" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_GREATER_FAVORED_ENEMY_DRAGONS">
    <supports>Monster Type, Greater Favored Enemy</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Dragons are large reptilian creatures of ancient origin and tremendous power. True dragons, including the good metallic dragons and the evil chromatic dragons, are highly intelligent and have innate magic. Also in this category are creatures distantly related to true dragons, but less powerful, less intelligent, and less magical, such as wyverns and pseudodragons.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description></description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <element name="Elementals" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_GREATER_FAVORED_ENEMY_ELEMENTALS">
    <supports>Monster Type, Greater Favored Enemy</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Elementals are creatures native to the elemental planes. Some creatures of this type are little more than animate masses of their respective elements, including the creatures simply called elementals. Others have biological forms infused with elemental energy. The races of genies, including djinn and efreet, form the most important civilizations on the elemental planes. Other elemental creatures include azers, invisible stalkers, and water weirds.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description></description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <element name="Fiends" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_GREATER_FAVORED_ENEMY_FIENDS">
    <supports>Monster Type, Greater Favored Enemy</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Fiends are creatures of wickedness that are native to the Lower Planes. A few are the servants of deities, but many more labor under the leadership of archdevils and demon princes. Evil priests and mages sometimes summon fiends to tne' material world to do their bidding. If an evil celestial is a rarity, a good fiend is almost inconceivable. Fiends include demons, devils, hell hounds, rakshasas, and yugoloths.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description></description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <element name="Giants" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_The_Ranger,_Revised_GREATER_FAVORED_ENEMY_GIANTS">
    <supports>Monster Type, Greater Favored Enemy</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Giants tower over humans and their kind. They are humanlike in shape, though some have multiple heads (ettins) or deformities (fomorians). The six varieties of true giant are hill giants, stone giants, frost giants, fire giants, cloud giants, and storm giants. Besides these, creatures such as ogres and trolls are giants.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description></description>
    </sheet>
  </element>  
</elements>
