<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
 <elements>
  <info>
    <name>Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old</name>
    <description>These character options were introduced in The Complete Fighter’s Handbook, and became a mainstay of the rest of the books in the Player’s Handbook Rules Supplement series. Though kits were notorious for providing wildly uneven benefits (some offered all-but-unnoticeable improvements, while others turned characters into walking engines of destruction), they did add depth and customization to a game that had previously offered few character choices after 1st level.</description>
    <author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/articles/unearthed-arcana/kits-old">Wizards of the Coast</author>
    <update version="0.0.1">
      <file name="20160104.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/unearthed-arcana/2016/20160104.xml" />
    </update>
  </info>
    
  <element name="Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_UNEARTHED_ARCANA_20160104">
    <description>
      <p>These character options were introduced in The Complete Fighter’s Handbook, and became a mainstay of the rest of the books in the Player’s Handbook Rules Supplement series. Though kits were notorious for providing wildly uneven benefits (some offered all-but-unnoticeable improvements, while others turned characters into walking engines of destruction), they did add depth and customization to a game that had previously offered few character choices after 1st level.</p>
    </description>
    <setters>
      <set name="abbreviation">UA20160104</set>
      <set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/articles/unearthed-arcana/kits-old</set>
      <set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
      <set name="official">true</set>
      <set name="playtest">true</set>
      <set name="release">20160104</set>
    </setters>
  </element>

  <element name="College of Satire" type="Archetype" source="Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old" id="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_COLLEGE_OF_SATIRE">
    <supports>Bard College</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Bards of the College of Satire are called jesters. They use lowbrow stories, daring acrobatics, and cutting jokes to entertain audiences, ranging from the crowds in a rundown dockside pub to the nobles of a king’s royal court. Where other bards seek forgotten lore or tales of epic bravery, jesters ferret out embarrassing and hilarious stories of all kinds. Whether telling the ribald tale of a brawny stable hand’s affair with an aged duchess or a mocking satire of a paladin of Helm’s cloying innocence, a jester never lets taste, social decorum, or shame get in the way of a good laugh.</p> 
      <p class="indent">While jesters are masters of puns, jokes, and verbal barbs, they are much more than just comic relief. They are expected to mock and provoke, taking advantage of how even the most powerful folk are expected by tradition to endure a jester’s barbs with good humor. This expectation allows a jester to serve as a critic or a voice of reason when others are too intimidated to speak the truth.</p>
      <p class="indent">For the duchess with a taste for strapping young laborers, such tales might serve to warn the targets of her affections and force her to change her ways for lack of willing partners. Striking back at the jester only ruins her already damaged reputation, and might provide the best evidence that the jester’s satires have hit their mark. But if she is kind and generous to her conquests, the jokes and stories cast her as a kind of folk hero, while drawing even more potential partners to her.</p> 
      <p class="indent">Jesters are loyal to only one cause: the pursuit and propagation of the truth. They use their comedy and innocuous appearance to break down social barriers and expose corruption, incompetence, and stupidity among the rich and powerful. Whether revealing a con artist’s treachery or exposing a baron’s plans for war as driven by greed and bloodlust, a jester serves as the conscience of a realm.</p> 
      <p class="indent">Jesters adventure to safeguard the common folk and to undermine the plans of the rich, powerful, and arrogant. Their magic bolsters allies’ spirits while casting doubt into foes’ minds. Among bards, jesters are unmatched acrobats, and their ability to tumble, dodge, leap, and climb makes them slippery opponents in battle.</p>
      <div element="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SATIRE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SATIRE_TUMBLING_FOOL" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SATIRE_FOOLS_INSIGHT" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SATIRE_FOOLS_LUCK" />
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Jesters use lowbrow stories, daring acrobatics, and cutting jokes to entertain audiences, ranging from the crowds in a rundown dockside pub to the nobles of a king’s royal court.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SATIRE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="3" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SATIRE_TUMBLING_FOOL" level="3" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SATIRE_FOOLS_INSIGHT" level="6" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SATIRE_FOOLS_LUCK" level="14" />
    </rules>
  </element>

  <element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old" id="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SATIRE_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
    <description>
      <p>When you join the College of Satire at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with thieves’ tools. You also gain proficiency in Sleight of Hand and one additional skill of your choice. If you are already proficient with thieves’ tools or in Sleight of Hand, choose another skill proficiency for each proficiency you already have.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_THIEVES_TOOLS" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND" />
      <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (College of Satire)" supports="Skill" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Tumbling Fool" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old" id="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SATIRE_TUMBLING_FOOL">
    <description>
      <p>At 3rd level, you master a variety of acrobatic techniques that allow you to evade danger. As a bonus action, you can tumble. When you tumble, you gain the following benefits for the rest of your turn:</p> 
      <ul>
        <li>You gain the benefits of taking the Dash and Disengage actions.</li> 
        <li>You gain a climbing speed equal to your current speed.</li> 
        <li>You take half damage from falling.</li>
      </ul>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>As a bonus action, you can tumble. 
	  When you do so you gain the befits of taking the Dash and Disengage actions, as well as gaining a climbing speed equal to your current speed, and you only take half damage from falling until the end of your turn.</description>  
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <element name="Fool’s Insight" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old" id="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SATIRE_FOOLS_INSIGHT">
    <description>
      <p>At 6th level, your ability to gather stories and lore gains a supernatural edge. You can cast detect thoughts up to a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier. You regain any expended uses of this ability after completing a long rest.</p> 
      <p class="indent">If a creature resists your attempt to probe deeper and succeeds at its saving throw against your detect thoughts, it immediately suffers an embarrassing social gaffe. It might loudly pass gas, 
      unleash a thunderous burp, trip and fall, or be compelled to tell a tasteless joke.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet usage="{{charisma:modifier}}/Long Rest">
      <description>Cast detect thoughts without using a spell slot. If a creature succeeds its save against it, it suffers an embarrassing social gaffe.</description>  
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_THOUGHTS" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Fool’s Luck" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old" id="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SATIRE_FOOLS_LUCK">
    <description>
      <p>Jesters seem to have a knack for pulling themselves out of tight situations, transforming what looks like sure failure into an embarrassing but effective success. At 14th level, you can expend one use of Bardic Inspiration after you fail an ability check, fail a saving throw, or miss with an attack roll. Roll a Bardic Inspiration die and add the number rolled to your attack, saving throw, or ability check, using the new result in place of the failed one.</p>  
      <p class="indent">If using this ability grants you a success on the attack, saving throw, or ability check, note the number you rolled on the Bardic Inspiration die. The DM can then apply that result as a penalty to an attack or check you make, and you cannot use this ability again until you suffer this drawback. When the DM invokes this penalty, describe an embarrassing gaffe or mistake you make as part of the affected die roll.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Expend one use of Bardic Inspiration after you fail a check, saving throw, or attack roll. Roll a d{{bardic-inspiration:dice}} and add it to the number rolled.
	  If this causes you to succeed, write down the number you rolled. You cannot use this ability again until the DM applies that number as a penalty to an attack or check you make. If this causes you to miss a roll, describe an embarrasing gaffe or mistake you make as part of the action you were trying to do.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
      
  <element name="Scout" type="Archetype" source="Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old" id="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FIGHTER_SCOUT">
    <supports>Martial Archetype</supports>
    <description>
      <p>The archetypal Scout excels at finding safe passage through dangerous regions. Scouts usually favor light armor and ranged weapons, but they are comfortable using heavier gear when faced with intense fighting.</p>
      <div element="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUT_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES"/>
      <div element="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUT_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY"/>
      <div element="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUT_NATURAL_EXPLORER"/>
      <div element="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUT_IMPROVED_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY"/>
      <div element="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUT_RELENTLESS"/>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Scouts excels at finding safe passage through dangerous regions.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUT_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="3"/>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUT_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY" level="3"/>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUT_NATURAL_EXPLORER" level="3"/>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUT_IMPROVED_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY" level="10"/>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUT_RELENTLESS" level="15"/>
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Bonus Profciencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old" id="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUT_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
    <description>
      <p>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in three of the following skills of your choice: Acrobatics, Athletics, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Stealth, or Survival. You can choose to gain proficiency with thieves’ tools in place of one skill choice.</p>
    </description>
      <sheet display="false"/>
      <rules>
        <select type="Proficiency" name="Bonus Proficiencies (Scout)" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_MEDICINE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL|ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_THIEVES_TOOLS" number="3"/>
      </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Combat Superiority" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old" id="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUT_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY">
    <description>
      <p>At 3rd level, you gain a set of abilities that are fueled by special dice called superiority dice.</p>
      <p class="indent"><b><em>Superiority Dice.</em></b> You have four superiority dice, which are d8s. A superiority die is expended when you use it. You regain all of your expended superiority dice when you finish a long or short rest.</p>
      <p class="indent">You gain another superiority die at 7th level and one more at 15th level.</p>
      <p class="indent"><b><em>Using Superiority Dice.</em></b> You can expend superiority dice to gain a number of different benefits:</p>
      <ul>
		<li>When you make a check that allows you to apply your proficiency in Athletics, Nature, Perception, Stealth, or Survival, you can expend one superiority die to bolster the check. Add half the number rolled on the superiority die (rounding up) to your check. You apply this bonus after making the check but before learning if it was successful.</li>
		<li>When you make a weapon attack against a creature, you can expend one superiority die to add it to the attack roll. You can use this ability before or after making the attack roll, but before any of the effects of the attack are applied.</li> 
		<li>If you are hit by an attack while wearing light or medium armor, you can expend one superiority die as a reaction, adding the number rolled to your AC. If the attack still hits, you take half damage from it.</li>
	  </ul>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You have {{superiority dice:amount}}d{{superiority dice:size}}s superiority dice. You can expend them to choose between following effects: Roll one superiority die and add half the rolled number to a Athletics, Nature, Perception, Stealth, or Survival check that allows you to apply your proficiency (before learning if successful or not). Or, roll a superiority die and add the number to an attack roll. Or, When hit while wearing light or medium armor, roll a superiority die and add the number rolled to your AC, if that attack still hits, you take half damage.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <stat name="superiority dice:amount" value="4" />
      <stat name="superiority dice:amount" value="1" level="7" />
      <stat name="superiority dice:amount" value="1" level="15" />      
      <stat name="superiority dice:size" value="8" bonus="size"/>
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Natural Explorer" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old" id="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUT_NATURAL_EXPLORER">
    <description>
      <p>At 3rd level, you gain the ranger class feature of the same name, with the following alteration: You choose additional favored terrain types at 7th and 15th level.</p>
      <p>You are particularly familiar with one type of natural environment and are adept at traveling and surviving in such regions. Choose one type of favored terrain: arctic, coast, desert, forest, grassland, mountain, swamp, or the Underdark. When you make an Intelligence or Wisdom check related to your favored terrain, your proficiency bonus is doubled if you are using a skill that you’re proficient in.</p>
      <p class="indent">While traveling for an hour or more in your favored terrain, you gain the following benefits:</p>
	    <ul>
		  <li>Difficult terrain doesn’t slow your group’s travel.</li>
		  <li>Your group can’t become lost except by magical means.</li>
		  <li>Even when you are engaged in another activity while traveling (such as foraging, navigating, or tracking), you remain alert to danger.</li>
		  <li>If you are traveling alone, you can move stealthily at a normal pace.</li>
		  <li>When you forage, you find twice as much food as you normally would.</li>
		  <li>While tracking other creatures, you also learn their exact number, their sizes, and how long ago they passed through the area.</li>
	    </ul>
    </description>
    <sheet>
     <description>When you make an Intelligence or Wisdom check related to your favored terrain, your proficiency bonus is doubled if you are using a skill that you’re proficient in. While traveling for an hour or more in your favored terrain, your group wont be slowed by difficult terrain, or become lost by magical means. You remain alert to danger even when foraging, navigating, or tracking, and find twice as much food when foraging, and when tracking learn the number, size and how long ago the creatures passed.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <select type="Class Feature" name="Favored Terrain" supports="Favored Terrain" level="3" />
      <select type="Class Feature" name="Favored Terrain" supports="Favored Terrain" level="7" />
      <select type="Class Feature" name="Favored Terrain" supports="Favored Terrain" level="15" />  
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Improved Combat Superiority" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old" id="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUT_IMPROVED_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY">
    <description>
      <p>At 10th level, your superiority dice turn into d10s. At 18th level, they turn into d12s.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false"/>
    <rules>
        <stat name="superiority dice:size" value="10" level="10" bonus="size"/>
        <stat name="superiority dice:size" value="12" level="18" bonus="size"/>
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Relentless" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old" id="ID_WOTC_UA20160104_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SCOUT_RELENTLESS">
    <description>
      <p>Starting at 15th level, when you roll initiative and have no superiority dice remaining, you regain 1 superiority die.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When you roll initiative and have no superiority dice remaining, you regain 1 superiority die.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

</elements>