<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Gate Urchin</name>
		<description>The Gate Urchin background from Out of the Abyss</description>
		<author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/outoftheabyss">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.1.2">
			<file name="background-gateurchin.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/supplements/out-of-the-abyss/backgrounds/background-gateurchin.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Gate Urchin" type="Background" source="Adventurers League: Rage of Demons" id="ID_WOTC_ROD_BACKGROUND_GATE_URCHIN">
		<description>
			<p>All traffic into and out of the City of Trade passes through the Hillsfar Gate, making it the ideal place for the destitute to gather to panhandle, busk, gossip, and pick pockets. You grew up on the streets in the shadow of that great steel edifice, which houses both Red Plumes and Guild Mages. Though you may have moved on, you still have friends among them, and that life has had a lasting impact on you.</p>
			<p>
				<b>Skill Proficiencies: </b>Deception, Sleight of Hand<br/>
				<b>Tool Proficiencies: </b>Thieves’ tools, one type of musical instrument<br/>
				<b>Equipment: </b>A battered alms box, a musical instrument, a cast-off military jacket, cap, or scarf, a set of common clothes, a belt pouch, and 10 gp
			</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_ROD_BACKGROUND_GATE_URCHIN_FEATURE_RED_PLUME_AND_MAGE_GUILD_CONTACTS" />
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">Deception, Sleight of Hand, Thieves’ Tools, Instrument</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Musical Instrument (Gate Urchin)" supports="Musical Instrument"/>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_THIEVES_TOOLS" />
			<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ROD_BACKGROUND_GATE_URCHIN_FEATURE_RED_PLUME_AND_MAGE_GUILD_CONTACTS" />
			<select name="Personality Trait" type="List" number="2">
				<item id="1">I appreciate the simple things in life: a song, a warm meal, a sunny day. I don’t need any more.</item>
				<item id="2">My problems are always caused by others. I’m never to blame.</item>
				<item id="3">I am afraid I could wind up back on the streets any day.</item>
				<item id="4">I get along with everyone.</item>
				<item id="5">I see people as marks for a con and have difficulty feeling true empathy for them.</item>
				<item id="6">I have a real flair for matchmaking. I can find anyone a spouse!</item>
				<item id="7">I think money is the true measure of appreciation and affection. Everything else is talk or an act.</item>
				<item id="8">I don’t like having a lot of stuff, just a few simple things I need. I don’t like being tied down and tend to leave things behind when I don’t need them anymore.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Ideal" type="List">
				<item id="1">Loyal: I never rat out any of my friends, even when the Red Plumes or the Rogues Guild ask. (Lawful)</item>
				<item id="2">Adventurous: I don’t like doing the same thing every day. I crave variety. (Chaotic)</item>
				<item id="3">Strong: Only the strong survive. I respect those who are strong and powerful. (Any)</item>
				<item id="4">Witty: Brains are better than brawn. I rely on my wits and respect others who do the same. (Any)</item>
				<item id="5">Honest: Others can do what they want, but I won’t lie or steal, even to feed my family. (Good)</item>
				<item id="6">Ungrateful: Those who give, only do it to make themselves feel better. I steal from them. (Evil)</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Bond" type="List">
				<item id="1">The Joydancers of Lliira gave me my instrument when I really needed food. I hate them for that.</item>
				<item id="2">Busking has taught me to love music above all else.</item>
				<item id="3">The Rogues Guild spared me when I did a job without cutting them in. I owe them a great debt.</item>
				<item id="4">I know people hate the Red Plumes, but some of them were really good to me. I help Red Plumes whenever I can, and I respect them. They’re just doing what they have to do to get by in this world.</item>
				<item id="5">I will be wealthy some day. My descendants will live in comfort and style.</item>
				<item id="6">I know how hard life on the streets is. I do everything I can for those who have less than me.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Flaw" type="List">
				<item id="1">Though I no longer live at the Gate, I am still always concerned about where I will get my next meal.</item>
				<item id="2">Years of thieving have become habit. I sometimes steal from strangers without thinking about it.</item>
				<item id="3">I am ashamed of my origins. I pretend I am higher- born and fear others will find out the truth.</item>
				<item id="4">I think people who grew up in houses are soft, spoiled, and ungrateful. I frequently tell them so.</item>
				<item id="5">I am still very uncomfortable wearing nice clothes, sleeping in a warm bed, and eating fine food.</item>
				<item id="6">I do not trust anyone who has not had a hard life.</item>
			</select>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Feature: Red Plume and Mage Guild Contacts" type="Background Feature" source="Adventurers League: Rage of Demons" id="ID_WOTC_ROD_BACKGROUND_GATE_URCHIN_FEATURE_RED_PLUME_AND_MAGE_GUILD_CONTACTS">
		<supports>Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You made a number of friends among the Red Plumes and the Mage’s Guild when you lived at the Hillsfar Gate. They remember you fondly and help you in little ways when they can. You can invoke their assistance in and around Hillsfar to obtain food, as well as simple equipment for temporary use. You can also invoke it to gain access to the low-security areas of their garrisons, halls, and encampments.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Red Plume and Mage Guild Contacts" />
	</element>
</elements>