<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Hillsfar Smuggler</name>
		<description>The Hillsfar Smuggler background from Out of the Abyss</description>
		<author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/outoftheabyss">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.1.2">
			<file name="background-hillsfarsmuggler.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/supplements/out-of-the-abyss/backgrounds/background-hillsfarsmuggler.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Hillsfar Smuggler" type="Background" source="Adventurers League: Rage of Demons" id="ID_WOTC_ROD_BACKGROUND_HILLSFAR_SMUGGLER">
		<description>
			<p>Hillsfar is the City of Trade. However, the Great Law of Trade only protects "legitimate" trade, trade that passes through the city's sole gate, which the Red Plumes monitor and tax. And the Great Law of Humanity banishes non- humans from the city altogether. The two Great Laws create great demand and great risk for smugglers, who shepherd illicit goods and non-humans into and out of the city by secret routes. The Rogues Guild tightly controls all of this activity, taking its cut from sanctioned jobs and exacting punishment for independent jobs.</p>
			<p class="indent">Perhaps you trafficked Dragon's Breath (a brandy-like liquor) to avoid tariffs or contraband to avoid seizure, or maybe you are a human who sympathizes with the non- humans and worked as part of the network of secret routes and safe houses that helps them pass through Hillsfar. Either way, you have contacts in the smuggling community who can help you slip into and out of the city unnoticed, for a price.</p>
			<p>
				<b>Skill Proficiencies: </b>Perception, Stealth<br/>
				<b>Tool Proficiencies: </b>Forgery kit<br/>
				<b>Languages: </b>One racial language<br/>
				<b>Equipment: </b> A forgery kit, a set of common clothes, a belt pouch, and 5 gp
			</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_ROD_BACKGROUND_HILLSFAR_SMUGGLER_FEATURE_SECRET_PASSAGE" />
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">Perception, Stealth, Forgery Kit, Language</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_FORGERY_KIT" />
			<select type="Language" name="Language (Hillsfar Smuggler)" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
			<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ROD_BACKGROUND_HILLSFAR_SMUGGLER_FEATURE_SECRET_PASSAGE" />
			<select name="Personality Trait" type="List" number="2">
				<item id="1">When I'm not smuggling, I gamble.</item>
				<item id="2">I just love Halfling cooking and baking!</item>
				<item id="3">I party with dwarves whenever I can.</item>
				<item id="4">I'm a terrible singer, but I love to do it.</item>
				<item id="5">I was raised to honor Chauntea and still do.</item>
				<item id="6">The blood sports of the Arena sicken me.</item>
				<item id="7">I think non-humans are really interesting.</item>
				<item id="8">I exaggerate the tales of my exploits.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Ideal" type="List">
				<item id="1">Fair: I think everyone deserves to be treated fairly. I don't play favorites. (Lawful)</item>
				<item id="2">Impulsive: Planning is often a waste of time. No plan survives contact with reality. It's easier to dive in and deal with the consequences. (Chaotic)</item>
				<item id="3">Curious: I want to learn as much as I can about the people and places I encounter. (Any)</item>
				<item id="4">Prepared: I think success depends on preparing as much as possible in advance. (Any)</item>
				<item id="5">Respectful: I think everyone deserves to be treated with respect and dignity, regardless of their race, creed, color, or origin. (Good)</item>
				<item id="6">Corrupt: I will break the law or act dishonestly if the money is right. (Evil)</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Bond" type="List">
				<item id="1">I am loyal to the Rogues Guild and would do anything for them.</item>
				<item id="2">I love the city of Hillsfar and my fellow Hillsfarians, despite the recent problems.</item>
				<item id="3">I admire the elves. I help them whenever I can.</item>
				<item id="4">A gnome helped me once. I pay the favor forward.</item>
				<item id="5">I enjoy tricking the Red Plumes at every opportunity.</item>
				<item id="6">I smuggled agricultural goods for non-human farmers. I try to help them when I can.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Flaw" type="List">
				<item id="1">My hatred for the Red Plumes burns so brightly that I have difficulty suppressing It around them.</item>
				<item id="2">The Red Plumes caught me once before, and I was branded for my crime. If they catch me again, for any offense, the punishment will be dire.</item>
				<item id="3">I treat all Hillsfarans poorly. I am disgusted with their failure to revolt against the Great Law of Humanity.</item>
				<item id="4">I have difficulty trusting strangers. Anyone could be a spy for the authorities.</item>
				<item id="5">I am greedy. There isn't much I won't do for money.</item>
				<item id="6">I'm an informant for the Red Plumes. They let me continue my activities, so long as I pass them information about illegal activity in Hillsfar.</item>
			</select>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Feature: Secret Passage" type="Background Feature" source="Adventurers League: Rage of Demons" id="ID_WOTC_ROD_BACKGROUND_HILLSFAR_SMUGGLER_FEATURE_SECRET_PASSAGE">
		<supports>Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You can call on your contacts within the smuggling community to secure secret passage into or out of Hillsfar for yourself and your adventuring companions, no questions asked, and no Red Plume entanglements. Because you’re calling in a favor, you can’t be certain they will be able to help on your timetable or at all. Your Dungeon Master will determine whether you can be smuggled into or out of the city. In return for your passage, you and your companions may owe the Rouges Guild a favor and/or may have to pay bribes.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Secret Passage" />
	</element>
</elements>