<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Secret Identity</name>
		<description>The Secret Identity background from Out of the Abyss</description>
		<author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/outoftheabyss">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.1.2">
			<file name="background-secretidentity.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/supplements/out-of-the-abyss/backgrounds/background-secretidentity.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Secret Identity" type="Background" source="Adventurers League: Rage of Demons" id="ID_WOTC_ROD_BACKGROUND_SECRET_IDENTITY">
		<description>
			<p>Even though you are a non-human, despite Hillfar's Great Law of Humanity, you continue to live in the City of Trade. You do so by maintaining a secret identity, forging documents, and wearing a disguise. Few, if any, know you aren't human. If you're a halfling or gnome, you pass as a little person or a child. If you're a half-elf, half-orc, or genasi, you disguise your non-human features. Other races use a combination of disguise and concealing clothing to hide. Your reasons for doing so are your own. Perhaps you're a dissident or the agent of a foreign power. Maybe you have a relationship with someone you cannot bear to leave. Regardless, this way of life has taken a heavy toll on you.</p>
			<p>
				<b>Skill Proficiencies: </b>Deception, Stealth<br/>
				<b>Tool Proficiencies: </b>Disguise kit, forgery kit<br/>
				<b>Equipment: </b>A disguise kit, a forgery kit, a set of common clothes, a belt pouch, 5 gp
			</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_ROD_BACKGROUND_SECRET_IDENTITY_FEATURE_SECRET_IDENTITY" />
			<h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">Deception, Stealth, Disguise Kit, Forgery Kit</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_DISGUISE_KIT" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_FORGERY_KIT" />
			<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_WOTC_ROD_BACKGROUND_SECRET_IDENTITY_FEATURE_SECRET_IDENTITY" />
			<select name="Personality Trait" type="List" number="2">
				<item id="1">Despite its problems, I love Hillsfar, it's the greatest city in the world. The only one for me.</item>
				<item id="2">I move from place to place, never staying anywhere long and leaving nothing behind.</item>
				<item id="3">I think flattery is the best way to direct attention away from me.</item>
				<item id="4">I don't make friends easily. They're a liability I cannot afford.</item>
				<item id="5">Risk and danger exhilarate me. Pulling off schemes and deceptions is a rush.</item>
				<item id="6">The First Lord is right, humans are superior. I really admire them, despite the atrocities.</item>
				<item id="7">I avoid people of my own race, as well as things associated with my race, lest they give me away.</item>
				<item id="8">I live for the Arena. I admire gladiators and enjoy the thrill of blood on the sands!</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Ideal" type="List">
				<item id="1">Quisling: Supporting the rulers of the land and following the laws is the road to salvation. (Lawful)</item>
				<item id="2">Scoflaw: The laws and lawmakers are corrupt. I follow laws only when it suits me. (Chaotic)</item>
				<item id="3">Optimist: Everyone is basically good. Though the government is misguided it will all be okay. (Any)</item>
				<item id="4">Secretive: I am in the habit of not talking about myself. My business is none of yours. (Any)</item>
				<item id="5">Heroic: I do everything I can to help non-humans, regardless of the personal cost to me. (Good)</item>
				<item id="6">Depraved: I have lost my moral compass. The ends justify most any means. (Evil)</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Bond" type="List">
				<item id="1">The humans of Hillsfar have inflicted terrible harm on me, my family, and my race. I will have revenge.</item>
				<item id="2">I am part of an underground network that smuggles non-humans into and out of the city.</item>
				<item id="3">I am a partisan. I commit minor acts of defiance against the First Lord and Red Plumes when I can.</item>
				<item id="4">I am a spy. I report on events in and around Hillfar.</item>
				<item id="5">My secret identity is the only thing protecting me from the Arena. I will stop at nothing to maintain it.</item>
				<item id="6">I am madly in love with a human who does not know my true identity, and I fear rejection if I reveal it.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Flaw" type="List">
				<item id="1">After years of denying who I am, I now despise myself and other members of my pathetic race.</item>
				<item id="2">Years of hiding have made me somewhat paranoid. I trust no one.</item>
				<item id="3">I've been lying so often and for so long that I can't help it anymore. I frequently lie for no reason at all.</item>
				<item id="4">I am ashamed. I failed to protect a member of my family who was seized and thrown into the Area.</item>
				<item id="5">I am struggling with maintaining my secret identity. I subconsciously want to get caught and therefore sometimes let my secret identity slip.</item>
				<item id="6">Years of successfully deceiving others have made me cocky. I think no one can see through my lies.</item>
			</select>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Feature: Secret Identity" type="Background Feature" source="Adventurers League: Rage of Demons" id="ID_WOTC_ROD_BACKGROUND_SECRET_IDENTITY_FEATURE_SECRET_IDENTITY">
		<supports>Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have created a secret identity that you use to conceal your true race and that offers a covering explanation for your presence in Hillsfar. In addition, you can forge documents, including official papers and personal letters, as long as you have seen an example of the kind of document or the handwriting you are trying to copy.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Secret Identity" />
	</element>
</elements>