<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Anthropologist</name>
		<description>Anthropologist Background</description>
		<author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/tomb-annihilation">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.0.5">
			<file name="background-anthropologist.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/supplements/tomb-of-annihilation/backgrounds/background-anthropologist.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<element name="Anthropologist" type="Background" source="Tomb of Annihilation" id="ID_WOTC_TOA_BACKGROUND_ANTHROPOLOGIST">
		<description>
			<p>You have always been fascinated by other cultures, from the most ancient and primeval lost lands to the most modern civilizations. By studying other cultures' customs, philosophies, laws, rituals, religious beliefs, languages, and art, you have learned how tribes, empires, and all forms of society in between craft their own destinies and doom. This knowledge came to you not only through books and scrolls, but also through firsthand observation- by visiting far-flung settlements and exploring local histories and customs.</p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Insight, Religion</li>
				<li><strong>Languages:</strong> Two of your choice</li>
				<li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A leather-bound diary, a bottle of ink, an ink pen, a set of traveler's clothes, one trinket of special significance, and a pouch containing 10 gp</li>
			</ul>
			<h5>CULTURAL CHAMELEON</h5>
			<p>Before becoming an adventurer, you spent much of your adult life away from your homeland, living among people different from your kin. You came to understand these foreign cultures and the ways of their people, who eventually treated you as one of their own. One culture had more of an influence on you than any other, shaping your beliefs and customs. Choose a race whose culture you've adopted, or roll on the Adopted Culture table.</p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d8</td><td>Adopted Culture</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>Aarakocra</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>Dwarf</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>Elf</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>Goblin</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>Halfling</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>Human</td></tr>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>Lizardfolk</td></tr>
				<tr><td>8</td><td>Orc</td></tr>
			</table>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_TOA_BACKGROUND_ANTHROPOLOGIST_FEATURE_ADEPT_LINGUIST" />
			<h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
			<p>Anthropologists leave behind the societies into which they were born to discover what life ls like in other parts of the world. They seek to see how other races and civilizations survive-or why they did not. Some anthropologists are driven by intellectual curiosity, while others want the fame and recognition that comes with being the first to discover a new people, a lost tribe, or the truth about an ancient empire's downfall.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">Insight, Religion, 2 Languages</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION" />
			<select type="Language" name="Language (Anthropologist)" supports="Standard||Exotic" number="2" />
			<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_WOTC_TOA_BACKGROUND_ANTHROPOLOGIST_FEATURE_ADEPT_LINGUIST" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE" />
			<select type="Background Feature" name="Variant Feature" supports="Optional Background Feature" optional="true" />
			<select name="Adopted Culture" type="List" optional="true">
				<item id="1">Aarakocra</item>
				<item id="2">Dwarf</item>
				<item id="3">Elf</item>
				<item id="4">Goblin</item>
				<item id="5">Halfling</item>
				<item id="6">Human</item>
				<item id="7">Lizardfolk</item>
				<item id="8">Orc</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Personality Trait" type="List" number="2">
				<item id="1">I prefer the company of those who aren't like me, including people of other races.</item>
				<item id="2">I'm a stickler when it comes to observing proper etiquette and local customs.</item>
				<item id="3">I would rather observe than meddle.</item>
				<item id="4">By living among violent people, I have become desensitized to violence.</item>
				<item id="5">I would risk life and limb to discover a new culture or unravel the secrets of a dead one.</item>
				<item id="6">When I arrive at a new settlement for the first time, I must learn all its customs.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Ideal" type="List">
				<item id="1">Discovery. I want to be the first person to discover a lost culture. (Any)</item>
				<item id="2">Distance. One must not interfere with the affairs of another culture-even one in need of aid. (Lawful)</item>
				<item id="3">Knowledge. By understanding other races and cultures, we learn to understand ourselves. (Any)</item>
				<item id="4">Power. Common people crave strong leadership, and I do my utmost to provide it. (lawful)</item>
				<item id="5">Protection. I must do everything possible to save a society facing extinction. (Good)</item>
				<item id="6">Indifferent. Life is cruel. What's the point in saving people if they're going to die anyway? (Chaotic)</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Bond" type="List">
				<item id="1">My mentor gave me a journal filled with lore and wisdom. Losing it would devastate me.</item>
				<item id="2">Having lived among the people of a primeval tribe or clan, I long to return and see how they are faring.</item>
				<item id="3">Years ago, tragedy struck the members of an isolated society I befriended, and I will honor them.</item>
				<item id="4">I want to learn more about a particular humanoid culture that fascinates me.</item>
				<item id="5">I seek to avenge a clan, tribe, kingdom, or empire that was wiped out.</item>
				<item id="6">I have a trinket that I believe is the key to finding a long-lost society.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Flaw" type="List">
				<item id="1">Boats make me seasick.</item>
				<item id="2">I talk to myself, and I don't make friends easily.</item>
				<item id="3">I believe that I'm intellectually superior to people from other cultures and have much to teach them.</item>
				<item id="4">I've picked up some unpleasant habits living among goblins, lizardfolk, or orcs.</item>
				<item id="5">I complain about everything.</item>
				<item id="6">I wear a tribal mask and never take it off.</item>
			</select>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Feature: Adept Linguist" type="Background Feature" source="Tomb of Annihilation" id="ID_WOTC_TOA_BACKGROUND_ANTHROPOLOGIST_FEATURE_ADEPT_LINGUIST">
		<supports>Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You can communicate with humanoids who don't speak any language you know. You must observe the humanoids interacting with one another for at least 1 day, after which you learn a handful of important words, expressions, and gestures-enough to communicate on a rudimentary level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Adept Linguist" />
	</element>
</elements>