<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Unearthed Arcana: Sorcerer</name>
        <description>The sorcerer unearths new magical possibilities this week. The class receives four playtest options for the Sorcerous Origin feature: Favored Soul, Phoenix Sorcery, Sea Sorcery, and Stone Sorcery.</description>
        <author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/articles/unearthed-arcana/sorcerer">Wizards of the Coast</author>
        <update version="0.1.1">
            <file name="20170206.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/unearthed-arcana/2017/20170206.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

    <!-- placeholder:Favored Soul -->

	<element name="Phoenix Sorcery" type="Archetype" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_PHOENIX_SORCERY">
		<supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your power draws from the immortal flame that fuels the legendary phoenix. You or your ancestors perhaps rendered a phoenix a great service, or you were born in its presence. Whatever the cause, a shard of the phoenix’s power dwells within you.</p>
			<p class="indent">That power is a mixed blessing. Like the mythical creature, you can invoke fiery energy and gain the ability to cheat death itself. This power comes at a cost. The fire within you seethes, demanding to be unleashed. You sometimes find yourself absentmindedly feeding fires. You can’t bear to allow a fire to sputter out. You feel most comfortable while holding a lit torch or sitting in front of a campfire.</p>
			<p class="indent">More importantly, this gift comes with no special protection from fire. You are as vulnerable as any other creature to fiery magic, including your own. Phoenix sorcerers can use their powers to pull themselves back from the brink of death, and all too often their own, rash nature or relianc e on destructive magic is what puts them there in the first place.</p>
			<p class="indent">Such sorcerers are wanderers by necessity. The volatile nature of their magic makes other folk nervous. If a fire breaks out in town, a phoenix sorcerer had best flee, whether guilty or not. Fire is a dangerous force, and phoenix sorcerers have a reputation (deserved or not) for reckless behavior, confident that the essence of the phoenix can save them.</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHOENIX_SORCERY_IGNITE" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHOENIX_SORCERY_MANTLEOFFLAME" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHOENIX_SORCERY_PHOENIXSPARK" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHOENIX_SORCERY_NOURISHINGFIRE" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHOENIX_SORCERY_FORMOFTHEPHOENIX" />
		</description>
        <setters>
            <set name="sourceUrl">http://dnd.wizards.com/articles/unearthed-arcana/sorcerer</set>
        </setters>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your power draws from the immortal flame that fuels the legendary phoenix.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHOENIX_SORCERY_IGNITE" level="1" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHOENIX_SORCERY_MANTLEOFFLAME" level="1" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHOENIX_SORCERY_PHOENIXSPARK" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHOENIX_SORCERY_NOURISHINGFIRE" level="14" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHOENIX_SORCERY_FORMOFTHEPHOENIX" level="18" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Ignite" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHOENIX_SORCERY_IGNITE">
		<description>
			<p>At 1st level, you gain the ability to start fires with a touch. As an action, you can magically ignite a flammable object you touch with your hand—an object such as a torch, a piece of tinder, or the hem of drapes.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>As an action, you can magically ignite a flammable object you touch with your hand—an object such as a torch, a piece of tinder, or the hem of drapes.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Mantle of Flame" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHOENIX_SORCERY_MANTLEOFFLAME">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 1st level, you can unleash the phoenix fire that blazes within you.</p>
			<p class="indent">As a bonus action, you magically wreathe yourself in swirling fire, as your eyes glow like hot coals. For 1 minute, you gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You shed bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet.</li>
				<li>Any creature takes fire damage equal to your Charisma modifier if it hits you with a melee attack from within 5 feet of you or if it touches you.</li>
				<li>Whenever you roll fire damage on your turn, the roll gains a bonus to equal to your Charisma modifier.</li>
			</ul>
			<p>Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest. </p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Bonus Action (1 minute): You shed bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet. Any creature takes $(Charisma Modifier)fire damage if it hits you with a melee attack from within 5 feet of you or if it touches you. Whenever you roll fire damage on your turn, the roll gains a +$(Charisma Modifier) bonus.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Phoenix Spark" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHOENIX_SORCERY_PHOENIXSPARK">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 6th level, the fiery energy within you grows restless and vengeful. In the face of defeat, it surges outward to preserve you in a fiery roar.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you are reduced to 0 hit points, you can use your reaction to draw on the spark of the phoenix. You are instead reduced to 1 hit point, and each creature within 10 feet of you takes fire damage equal to half your sorcerer level + your Charisma modifier.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you use this feature while under the effects of your Mantle of Flame, this feature instead deals fire damage equal to your sorcerer level + double your Charisma modifier, and your Mantle of Flame immediately ends.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>If you are reduced to 0 hit points, you can use your reaction to draw on the spark of the phoenix. You are instead reduced to 1 hit point, and each creature within 10 feet of you takes $(phoenix spark:damage) fire damage. If you use this feature while under the effects of your Mantle of Flame, this feature instead deals $(phoenix spark:damage:alt) fire damage, and your Mantle of Flame immediately ends.(1/LR)</description>
		</sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="phoenix spark:damage" value="level:sorcerer:half" />
            <stat name="phoenix spark:damage" value="Charisma Modifier" />

            <stat name="phoenix spark:damage:alt" value="level:sorcerer" />
            <stat name="phoenix spark:damage:alt" value="Charisma Modifier" />
            <stat name="phoenix spark:damage:alt" value="Charisma Modifier" />
        </rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Nourishing Fire" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHOENIX_SORCERY_NOURISHINGFIRE">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 14th level, your fire spells soothe and restore you. When you expend a spell slot to cast a spell that includes a fire damage roll, you regain hit points equal to the slot’s level + your Charisma modifier.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you expend a spell slot to cast a spell that includes a fire damage roll, you regain hit points equal to the slot’s level + $(Charisma Modifier).</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Form of the Phoenix" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PHOENIX_SORCERY_FORMOFTHEPHOENIX">
		<description>
			<p>At 18th level, you finally master the spark of fire that dances within you. While under the effect of your Mantle of Flame feature, you gain additional benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You have a flying speed of 40 feet and can hover.</li>
				<li>You have resistance to all damage.</li>
				<li>If you use your Phoenix Spark, that feature deals an extra 20 fire damage to each creature.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>While under the effect of your Mantle of Flame feature, you gain additional benefits: You have a flying speed of 40 feet and can hover. You have resistance to all damage. If you use your Phoenix Spark, that feature deals an extra 20 fire damage to each creature.</description>
		</sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="speed:fly" value="40" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="phoenix spark:damage" value="20" />
            <stat name="phoenix spark:damage:alt" value="20" />
        </rules>
	</element>

    <!-- Sea Sorcery -->
      <element name="Sea Sorcerer" type="Archetype" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_SEA_SORCERER">
          <supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
          <requirements />
          <description>
            <p>The power of water is the strength of flexibility, resilience, and a relentless nature. Water parts to allow a ship to sail over it or a diver to plunge into it, but their passing leaves no mark. Water flowing down a mountain reaches the sea. It might bend and turn across valleys and down hillsides, but it slowly and steadily returns to the waves. Those whose souls are touched by the power of elemental water command a similar power.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your heritage ties to powerful creatures of the sea, such as nereids, the lords of the merfolk, and elemental powers. Like a river, you feel the call of the ocean. The call is ever present in your heart, and you are never completely at peace until you are near the sea.</p>
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_SOUL_OF_THE_SEA" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_CURSE_OF_THE_SEA" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_WATERY_DEFENSE" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_SHIFTING_FORM" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_WATER_SOUL" />
          </description>
          <sheet>
            <description>Your heritage ties to powerful creatures of the sea.</description>
          </sheet>
          <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" name="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_SOUL_OF_THE_SEA" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" name="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_CURSE_OF_THE_SEA" level="1" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" name="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_WATERY_DEFENSE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" name="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_SHIFTING_FORM" level="14" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" name="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_WATER_SOUL" level="18" />
          </rules>
      </element>

      <element name="Soul of the Sea" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_SOUL_OF_THE_SEA">
        <supports />
        <description>
          <p>At 1st level, your tie to the sea grants you the ability to breathe underwater, and you have a swim speed equal to your walking speed.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
          <description>
            <p>You can breathe underwater and you have a swimming speed of %speed:swim% feet.</p>
          </description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
          <stat name="speed:swim" value="Speed" bonus="base" />
        </rules>
      </element>

      <element name="Curse of the Sea" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_CURSE_OF_THE_SEA">
        <supports />
        <description>
          <p>When you choose this origin at 1st level, you learn the secret of infusing your spells with a watery curse.</p>
          <p class="indent">When you hit a creature with a cantrip's attack or when a creature fails a saving throw against your cantrip, you can curse the target until the end of your next turn or until you curse a different creature with this feature.</p>
          <p class="indent">Once per turn when you cast a spell, you can trigger the curse if that spell deals cold or lightning damage to the cursed target or forces it to move. Doing so subjects the target to the appropriate additional effect below, and then the curse ends if the spell isn't a cantrip (you choose the effect to use if more than one effect applies):</p>
          <ul>
            <li><p class="emphasis">Cold Damage: </p><p>If the affected target takes cold damage from your spell, the target's speed is also reduced by 15 feet until the end of your next turn. If the spell already reduces the target's speed, use whichever reduction is greater.</p></li>
            <li><p class="emphasis">Lightning Damage: </p><p>If the affected target takes lightning damage from your spell, the target takes additional lightning damage equal to your Charisma modifier.</p></li>
            <li><p class="emphasis">Forced Movement: </p><p>If the target is moved by your spell, increase the distance it is moved by 15 feet.</p></li>
          </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
          <description>
            <p>At 1st level,when you hit a creature with a cantrip's attack or when a creature fails a saving throw against your cantrip, you can curse the target until the end of your next turn or until you curse a different creature.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once per turn when you cast a spell, you can trigger the curse if that spell deals cold or lightning damage to the cursed target or forces it to move. Doing so subjects the target to the appropriate additional effect below, and then the curse ends if the spell isn't a cantrip (you choose the effect to use if more than one effect applies):</p>
            <ul>
              <li><p class="emphasis">Cold Damage: </p><p>If the affected target takes cold damage from your spell, the target's speed is also reduced by 15 feet until the end of your next turn. If the spell already reduces the target's speed, use whichever reduction is greater.</p></li>
              <li><p class="emphasis">Lightning Damage: </p><p>If the affected target takes lightning damage from your spell, the target takes an additional %Charisma Modifier% lightning damage.</p></li>
              <li><p class="emphasis">Forced Movement: </p><p>If the target is moved by your spell, increase the distance it is moved by 15 feet.</p></li>
            </ul>
          </description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>

        </rules>
      </element>
      <element name="Watery Defense" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_WATERY_DEFENSE">
        <supports />
        <description>
          <p>At 6th level, you gain resistance to fire damage. You also gain the ability to defend yourself by momentarily assuming a watery form. As a reaction when you are hit by an attack and take bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage from the attack, you can reduce that damage by an amount equal to your sorcerer level plus your Charisma score, and then you can move up to 30 feet without provoking opportunity attacks. Once you use this special reaction, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
          <description>
            At 6th level, you gain resistance to fire damage. You also gain the ability to defend yourself by momentarily assuming a watery form. As a reaction when you are hit by an attack and take bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage from the attack, you can reduce that damage by an amount equal to your sorcerer level plus your Charisma score, and then you can move up to 30 feet without provoking opportunity attacks. Once you use this special reaction, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.
          </description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
      </element>

      <element name="Shifting Form" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_SHIFTING_FORM">
        <supports />
        <description>
          <p>Starting at 14th level, when you move on your turn, you take only half damage from opportunity attacks, and you can move through any enemy's space but can't willingly end your move there.</p>
          <p>On your turn, you can move through any space that is at least 3 inches in diameter and do so without squeezing. When you stop moving, the regular squeezing rules apply if you're in a space one size smaller than you. You can't willingly stop in a space smaller than that, and if you're forced to do so, you immediately flow to the nearest space that can fit you, back along the path of your movement.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
          <description>
            <p>Starting at 14th level, when you move on your turn, you take only half damage from opportunity attacks, and you can move through any enemy's space but can't willingly end your move there.</p>
            <p>On your turn, you can move through any space that is at least 3 inches in diameter and do so without squeezing. When you stop moving, the regular squeezing rules apply if you're in a space one size smaller than you. You can't willingly stop in a space smaller than that, and if you're forced to do so, you immediately flow to the nearest space that can fit you, back along the path of your movement.</p>
          </description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
      </element>

      <element name="Water Soul" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SEA_SORCERER_WATER_SOUL">
        <supports />
        <description>
          <p>Starting at 18th level, you gain the following benefits:</p>
          <ul>
            <li>You no longer need to eat, drink, or sleep.</li>
            <li>A critical hit against you becomes a normal hit.</li>
            <li>You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage.</li>
          </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
          <description>
            <p>Starting at 18th level, you gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
              <li>You no longer need to eat, drink, or sleep.</li>
              <li>A critical hit against you becomes a normal hit.</li>
              <li>You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage.</li>
            </ul>
          </description>
        </sheet>
      </element>
    <!-- placeholder: Stone Sorcery -->
</elements>
