<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Unearthed Arcana: Warlock and Wizard</name>
        <description>The warlock and the wizard reach new arcane horizons this week. The warlock receives two playtest options for the Otherworldly Patron feature: the Hexblade and the Raven Queen. That class also gets a collection of playtest options for its Eldritch Invocations feature. Meanwhile, the wizard receives a playtest option for the Arcane Tradition feature: Lore Mastery.</description>
        <author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/articles/unearthed-arcana/warlock-and-wizard">Wizards of the Coast</author>
        <update version="0.0.6">
            <file name="20170213.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/unearthed-arcana/2017/20170213.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

	<element name="Unearthed Arcana: Warlock and Wizard" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_UNEARTHED_ARCANA_20170213">
		<description>
			<p>The warlock and the wizard reach new arcane horizons this week. The warlock receives two playtest options for the Otherworldly Patron feature: the Hexblade and the Raven Queen. That class also gets a collection of playtest options for its Eldritch Invocations feature. Meanwhile, the wizard receives a playtest option for the Arcane Tradition feature: Lore Mastery.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">UA20170213</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/articles/unearthed-arcana/warlock-and-wizard</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="playtest">true</set>
			<set name="release">20170213</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

    <element name="The Raven Queen" type="Deity" source="Unearthed Arcana: Warlock and Wizard" id="ID_WOTC_UA20170213_DEITY_THE_RAVEN_QUEEN">
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">goddess of death, fate, and winter</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="alignment">UN</set>
            <set name="domains">Death, Fate, Winter</set>
            <set name="symbol">The head of a raven</set>
            <set name="gender">female</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet>
            <description>goddess of death, fate, and winter</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <!-- The Raven Queen -->
    <element name="The Raven Queen" type="Archetype" source="Unearthed Arcana: Warlock and Wizard" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_RAVEN_QUEEN">
        <supports>Otherworldly Patron</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You patron is the Raven Queen, a mysterious being who rules the Shadowfell from a palace of ice deep within that dread realm. The Raven Queen watches over the world, anticipating each creature’s death and ensuring that it meets its end at the proscribed time and place. As the ruler of the Shadowfell, she dwells in a decayed, dark reflection of the world. Her ability to reach into the world is limited. Thus, she turns to mortal warlocks to serve her will. Warlocks sworn to the Raven Queen receive visions and whispers from her in their dreams, sending them on quests and warning them of impending dangers.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Raven Queen’s followers are expected to serve her will in the world. She concerns herself with ensuring that those fated to die pass from the world as expected, and bids her agents to defeat those who seek to cheat death through undeath or other imitations of immortality. She hates intelligent undead and expects her followers to strike them down, whereas mindless undead such as skeletons and zombies are little more than stumbling automatons in her eyes.</p>
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RAVEN_QUEEN_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RAVEN_QUEEN_SENTINEL_RAVEN" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RAVEN_QUEEN_SOUL_OF_THE_RAVEN" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RAVEN_QUEEN_RAVENS_SHIELD" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RAVEN_QUEEN_QUEENS_RIGHT_HAND" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You patron is the Raven Queen, a mysterious being who rules the Shadowfell from a palace of ice deep within that dread realm.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RAVEN_QUEEN_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST" level="1"/>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RAVEN_QUEEN_SENTINEL_RAVEN" level="1"/>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RAVEN_QUEEN_SOUL_OF_THE_RAVEN" level="6"/>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RAVEN_QUEEN_RAVENS_SHIELD" level="10"/>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RAVEN_QUEEN_QUEENS_RIGHT_HAND" level="14"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Expanded Spell List" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Warlock and Wizard" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RAVEN_QUEEN_EXPANDED_SPELL_LIST">
        <supports>Warlock</supports>
        <requirements />
        <description>
            <p>The Raven Queen lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell. The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you.</p>
            <h5>Raven Queen Expanded Spells</h5>
            <table>
                <thead><tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr></thead>
                <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>false life, sanctuary</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>2nd</td><td><em>silence, spiritual weapon</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>feign death, speak with dead</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>4th</td><td><em>ice storm, locate creature</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>commune, cone of cold</em></td></tr>
            </table>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description>The Raven Queen lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell.</description>
        </sheet>
        <spellcasting name="Warlock" extend="true">
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FALSE_LIFE</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SANCTUARY</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SILENCE</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRITUAL_WEAPON</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FEIGN_DEATH</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_ICE_STORM</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE</extend>
            <extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_CONE_OF_COLD</extend>
        </spellcasting>
    </element>
    <element name="Sentinel Raven" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Warlock and Wizard" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RAVEN_QUEEN_SENTINEL_RAVEN">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 1st level, you gain the service of a spirit sent by the Raven Queen to watch over you. The spirit assumes the form and game statistics of a raven, and it always obeys your commands, which you can give telepathically while it is within 100 feet of you.</p>
            <p class="indent">While the raven is perched on your shoulder, you gain darkvision with a range of 30 feet and a bonus to your passive Wisdom (Perception) score and to Wisdom (Perception) checks. The bonus equals your Charisma modifier. While perched on your shoulder, the raven can’t be targeted by any attack or other harmful effect; only you can cast spells on it; it can’t take damage; and it is incapacitated.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can see through the raven’s eyes and hear what it hears while it is within 100 feet of you.</p>
            <p class="indent">In combat, you roll initiative for the raven and control how it acts. If it is slain by a creature, you gain advantage on all attack rolls against the killer for the next 24 hours.</p>
            <p class="indent">The raven doesn’t require sleep. While it is within 100 feet of you, it can awaken you from sleep as a bonus action.</p>
            <p class="indent">The raven vanishes when it dies, if you die, or if the two of you are separated by more than 5 miles.</p>
            <p class="indent">At the end of a short or long rest, you can call the raven back to you—no matter where it is or whether it died—and it reappears within 5 feet of you.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>While the raven is perched on your shoulder, you gain darkvision with a range of 30 feet and a +{{seninel raven:perception}} bonus to your passive Perception score and to Perception checks.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="seninel raven:perception" value="charisma:modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Soul of the Raven" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Warlock and Wizard" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RAVEN_QUEEN_SOUL_OF_THE_RAVEN">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level, you gain the ability to merge with your raven spirit. As a bonus action when your raven is perched on your shoulder, your body merges with your raven’s form. While merged, you become Tiny, you replace your speed with the raven’s, and you can use your action only to Dash, Disengage, Dodge, Help, Hide, or Search. During this time, you gain the benefits of your raven being perched on your shoulder. As an action, you and the raven return to normal.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As a bonus action when your raven is perched on your shoulder, your body merges with your raven’s form. While merged, you become Tiny, you replace your speed with the raven’s, and you can use your action only to Dash, Disengage, Dodge, Help, Hide, or Search. During this time, you gain the benefits of your raven being perched on your shoulder. As an action, you and the raven return to normal.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules />
    </element>
    <element name="Raven’s Shield" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Warlock and Wizard" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RAVEN_QUEEN_RAVENS_SHIELD">
        <description>
            <p>At 10th level, the Raven Queen grants you a protective blessing. You gain advantage on death saving throws, immunity to the frightened condition, and resistance to necrotic damage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain advantage on death saving throws, immunity to the frightened condition, and resistance to necrotic damage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
		    <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC" />
	    </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Queen’s Right Hand" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Warlock and Wizard" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_RAVEN_QUEEN_QUEENS_RIGHT_HAND">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 14th level, you can channel the Raven Queen’s power to slay a creature. You can cast finger of death. After you cast the spell with this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can cast finger of death. After you cast the spell with this feature, you can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules />
    </element>

    <!-- Invocations related to the Raven Queen -->
    <element name="Chronicle of the Raven Queen" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Warlock and Wizard" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_CHRONICLE_OF_THE_RAVEN_QUEEN">
        <supports>Eldritch Invocation, Pact of the Tome</supports>
        <prerequisite>Raven Queen patron, Pact of the Tome feature</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_RAVEN_QUEEN,ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_WARLOCK_PACT_BOON_PACT_OF_THE_TOME</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: Raven Queen patron, Pact of the Tome feature</p>
            <p>You can place a corpse’s hand or similar appendage on your Book of Shadows and ask one question aloud. After 1 minute, the answer appears written in blood in your book. The answer is provided by the dead creature’s spirit to the best of its knowledge and is translated into a language of your choice. You must use this ability within 1 minute of a creature’s death, and a given creature can only be asked one question in this manner.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can place a corpse’s hand or similar appendage on your Book of Shadows and ask one question aloud. After 1 minute, the answer appears written in blood in your book. The answer is provided by the dead creature’s spirit to the best of its knowledge and is translated into a language of your choice. You must use this ability within 1 minute of a creature’s death, and a given creature can only be asked one question in this manner.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules />
    </element>
    <element name="Raven Queen’s Blessing" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Warlock and Wizard" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_ELDRITCH_INVOCATION_RAVEN_QUEENS_BLESSING">
        <supports>Eldritch Invocation</supports>
        <prerequisite>Raven Queen patron, eldritch blast cantrip</prerequisite>
        <requirements>ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_RAVEN_QUEEN, ID_PHB_SPELL_ELDRITCH_BLAST</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Raven Queen patron, eldritch blast cantrip</p>
            <p>When you score a critical hit with your eldritch blast cantrip, pick yourself or an ally you can see within 30 feet of you. The chosen creature can immediately expend a Hit Die to regain hit points equal to the roll + the creature’s Constitution modifier (minimum of 1 hit point).</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you score a critical hit with your eldritch blast cantrip, pick yourself or an ally you can see within 30 feet of you. The chosen creature can immediately expend a Hit Die to regain hit points equal to the roll + the creature’s Constitution modifier (minimum of 1 hit point).</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules />
    </element>
    <!-- Lore Mastery -->
    <element name="Lore Mastery" type="Archetype" source="Unearthed Arcana: Warlock and Wizard" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_LORE_MASTERY">
        <supports>Arcane Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Lore Mastery is an arcane tradition fixated on understanding the underlying mechanics of magic. It is the most academic of all arcane traditions. The promise of uncovering new knowledge or proving (or discrediting) a theory of magic is usually required to rouse its practitioners from their laboratories, academies, and archives to persue a life of adventure.</p>
    			<p class="indent">Known as savants, followers of this tradition are a bookish lot who see beauty and mystery in the application of magic. The results of a spell are less interesting to them than the process that creates it. Some savants take haughty attitude toward those who follow a tradition focused on a single school of magic, seeing them as provincial and lacking the sophistication needed to master true magic. Other savants are generous teachers, countering ignorance and deception with deep knowledge and good humor.</p>
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_LORE_MASTERY_LORE_MASTER" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_LORE_MASTERY_SPELL_SECRETS" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_LORE_MASTERY_ALCHEMICAL_CASTING" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_LORE_MASTERY_PRODIGIOUS_MEMORY" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_LORE_MASTERY_MASTER_OF_MAGIC" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Lore Mastery is an arcane tradition fixated on understanding the underlying mechnanics of magic. The promise of uncovering new knowledge or proving (or discrediting) a theory of magic is usually required to rouse its practitioners from their laboratories, academies, and archives to persue a life of adventure.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_LORE_MASTERY_LORE_MASTER" level="2"/>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_LORE_MASTERY_SPELL_SECRETS" level="2"/>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_LORE_MASTERY_ALCHEMICAL_CASTING" level="6"/>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_LORE_MASTERY_PRODIGIOUS_MEMORY" level="10"/>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_LORE_MASTERY_MASTER_OF_MAGIC" level="14"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Lore Master" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Warlock and Wizard" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_LORE_MASTERY_LORE_MASTER">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 2nd level, you become a compendium of knowledge on a vast array of topics. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses the Arcana, History, Nature, or Religion skill if you are proficient in that skill.</p>
    			<p class="indent">In addition, your analytical abilities are so well-honed that your initiative in combat can be driven by mental agility, rather than physical ability. When you roll initiative, you choose either an Intelligence check or a Dexterity check.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you roll initiative, you choose either an Intelligence check or a Dexterity check.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
		<stat name="arcana:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" requirements="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA" />
		<stat name="history:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" requirements="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY" />
		<stat name="nature:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" requirements="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_NATURE" />
		<stat name="religion:proficiency" value="proficiency" bonus="double" requirements="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION" />
		<stat name="initiative" value="intelligence:modifier" bonus="ability" />
        </rules> 
    </element>
    <element name="Spell Secrets" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Warlock and Wizard" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_LORE_MASTERY_SPELL_SECRETS">
        <description>
            <p>At 2nd level, you master the first in a series of arcane secrets uncovered by your extensive studies.</p>
    			<p class="indent">When you cast a spell with a spell slot and the spell deals acid, cold, fire, force, lightning, necrotic, radiant, or thunder damage, you can substitute that damage type with one other type from that list (you can change only one damage type per casting of a spell). You replace one energy type for another by altering the spell's formula as you cast it.</p>
    			<p class="indent">When you cast a spell with a spell slot and the spell requires a saving throw, you can change saving throw from one ability score to another of your choice. Once you change a saving throw in this way, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you cast a spell with a spell slot that deals acid, cold, fire, force, lightning, necrotic, radiant, or thunder damage, you can substitute that damage type with one other type from that list (you can change only one damage type per casting of a spell). When you cast a spell that requires a saving throw, you can change saving throw from one ability score to another of your choice. Once you change a saving throw in this way, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Alchemical Casting" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Warlock and Wizard" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_LORE_MASTERY_ALCHEMICAL_CASTING">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level, you learn to augment spells in a variety of ways. When you cast a spell with a spell slot, you can expend one additional spell slot to augment its effects for this casting, mixing the raw stuff of magic into your spell slot you expend.</p>
    			<p class="indent">An additional 1st-level spell slot can increase the spell's raw force. If you roll damage for the spell when you cast it, increase the damage against every target by 2d10 force damage. If the spell can deal damage on more than one turn, it deals this extra force damage only on the turn you cast the spell.</p>
    			<p class="indent">An additional 2nd-level spell slot can increase the spell's range. If the spell's range is at least 30 feet, it becomes 1 miles.</p>
    			<p class="indent">An additional 3rd-level spell slot can increase the spell's potency. Increase the spell's save DC by 2.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can expend one additional spell slot to augment your casting. An additional 1st-level increases damage of the spell by 2d10 force damage once on the turn you cast the spell. An additional 2nd-level spell slot increases range to a 1 mile. An additional 3rd-level spell slot increases spell's save DC by 2.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Prodigious Memory" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Warlock and Wizard" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_LORE_MASTERY_PRODIGIOUS_MEMORY">
        <description>
            <p>At 10th level, you have attained greater mastery of spell preparation. As a bonus action you can replace one spell you have prepared with another spell from your spellbook. You can't use this feature again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As a bonus action you can replace one spell you have prepared with another spell from your spellbook. You can't use this feature again until you finish a short or long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Master of Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Warlock and Wizard" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_LORE_MASTERY_MASTER_OF_MAGIC">
        <description>
            <p>At 14th level, your knowledge of magic allows you to duplicate almost any spell. As a bonus action, you can call to mind the ability to cast spell of your choice from any class's spell list. The spell must be of a level for which you have spell slots, you mustn't have it prepared, and you follow normal rules for casting it, including expending a spell slot. If the spell isn't a wizard spell, it counts as a wizard spell when you cast it. The ability to cast the spell vanishes from your mind when you cast it or when current turn ends.</p>
    			<p class="indent">You can't use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As a bonus action, you can call to mind the ability to cast spell of your choice from any class's spell list. The spell must be of a level for which you have spell slots, you mustn't have it prepared, and you follow normal rules for casting it, including expending a spell slot. You can't use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
        </rules>
    </element>
</elements>
