<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Unearthed Arcana: Light, Dark, Underdark!</name>
		<description>Two new fighting styles for fighters, paladins, and rangers; the Deep Stalker ranger archetype; the shadow sorcerer; and the warlock pact of the Undying Light all offer exciting options for adventuring in the endless gloom of the Underdark.</description>
		<author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/articles/unearthed-arcana/light-dark-underdark">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.0.4">
			<file name="20151102.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/unearthed-arcana/2015/20151102.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Unearthed Arcana: Light, Dark, Underdark!" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_UNEARTHED_ARCANA_20151102">
		<description>
			<p>Two new fighting styles for fighters, paladins, and rangers; the Deep Stalker ranger archetype; the shadow sorcerer; and the warlock pact of the Undying Light all offer exciting options for adventuring in the endless gloom of the Underdark.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">UA20151102</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/articles/unearthed-arcana/light-dark-underdark</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="playtest">true</set>
			<set name="release">20151102</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!-- fighting styles -->
	<element name="Close Quarters Shooter" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Light, Dark, Underdark!" id="ID_WOTC_UA2015_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_CLOSE_QUARTERS_SHOOTER">
		<supports>Fighting Style, Fighter, Paladin, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You are trained in making ranged attacks at close quarters. When making a ranged attack while you are within 5 feet of a hostile creature, you do not have disadvantage on the attack roll. Your ranged attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover against targets within 30 feet of you. Finally, you have a +1 bonus to attack rolls on ranged attacks.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When making a ranged attack while you are within 5 feet of a hostile creature, you do not have disadvantage on the attack roll. Your ranged attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover against targets within 30 feet of you.
			Finally, you have a +1 bonus to attack rolls on ranged attacks.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ranged:attack" value="1" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Tunnel Fighter" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Light, Dark, Underdark!" id="ID_WOTC_UA2015_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_TUNNEL_FIGHTER">
		<supports>Fighting Style, Fighter, Paladin, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You excel at defending narrow passages, doorways, and other tight spaces. As a bonus action, you can enter a defensive stance that lasts until the start of your next turn. While in your defensive stance, you can make opportunity attacks without using your reaction, and you can use your reaction to make a melee attack against a creature that moves more than 5 feet while within your reach.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>As a bonus action, you can enter a defensive stance that lasts until the start of your next turn. While in your defensive stance, you can make opportunity attacks without using your reaction, and you can use your reaction to make a melee attack against a creature that moves more than 5 feet while within your reach.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!-- deep stalker (gloom stalker in XGTE) -->

	<!-- shadow sorcerer (shadow magic in XGTE) -->

	<!-- the undying light (the undying in SCAG) -->

</elements>