<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes</name>
		<description>Sometimes a campaign will have special needs for archetypes or character options not found in the existing official material. If you’re in this situation, you might want to modify one or more of the classes in the game in order to provide options for players looking for a unique twist on their characters’ abilities. However, modifying a class is not something that should be undertaken lightly, and the job requires some serious effort, playtesting, and revision to get it right. The two best ways to modify a class are to swap out some class features for different ones, and to add new to an existing class. This article presents methods that will help you to use existing mechanics as a model, while drawing upon features of other classes for inspiration.</description>
		<author url="https://dnd.wizards.com/articles/unearthed-arcana/modifying-classes">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="20150406.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/unearthed-arcana/2015/20150406.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<element name="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_UNEARTHED_ARCANA_20150406">
		<description>
			<p>Sometimes a campaign will have special needs for archetypes or character options not found in the existing official material. If you’re in this situation, you might want to modify one or more of the classes in the game in order to provide options for players looking for a unique twist on their characters’ abilities. However, modifying a class is not something that should be undertaken lightly, and the job requires some serious effort, playtesting, and revision to get it right. The two best ways to modify a class are to swap out some class features for different ones, and to add new to an existing class. This article presents methods that will help you to use existing mechanics as a model, while drawing upon features of other classes for inspiration.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">UA20150406</set>
			<set name="url">https://dnd.wizards.com/articles/unearthed-arcana/modifying-classes</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="playtest">true</set>
			<set name="release">20150406</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!-- Rule Element-->
	<element name="Favored Soul" type="Rule" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RULE_FAVORED_SOUL">
		<description>
			<p>As an example of how creating a new class option could work, let’s examine a design that was a full-fledged class in the third edition supplement <i>Complete Divine</i>: the favored soul. This might be an appealing archetype if you are running a game where the gods are going to have a big impact on the world, and where the Chosen of those gods (individuals bestowed with a fragment of a god’s divine power) are prominent players in the campaign. To reflect this tone, let’s create the Favored Soul as anew origin for the sorcerer class. This decision reflects the idea that the character is someone who is fundamentally changed by the touch of his or her deity, which awakens powerful magical abilities.</p>
			<p class="indent">Looking at the existing sorcerous origins, we can determine that, at 1st level, an origin provides not only the explanation for the source of the sorcerer’s power, but also a flourish on the way that character plays. Since this sorcerer is going to be gaining its magic by being imbued with divine power, we decide to give the Favored Soul access to some spells normally gained by the cleric. Any time we expand the known spells of the sorcerer, we run the risk of overshadowing the other sorcerous origins, since the limitation on the number of spells the sorcerer knows has a big impact on how the class plays. This indicates that the other class features probably shouldn’t all tie closely to the sorcerer’s spellcasting, since that aspect of the sorcerer is already getting quite a boost. Since the favored soul class was a little more martial in its previous incarnation, we decide to give our sorcerer some better armor and access to simple weapons, similar to the defensive bonuses gained by the Draconic Bloodline sorcerer at 1st level.</p>
			<p class="indent">At 6th level, the other sorcerous origins provide features that have an impact on the character’s combat abilities. Looking at the bard class, we can see that the College of Valor gains the Extra Attack class feature at the same level, and we decide to give that to the Favored Soul to further enhance its martial bent.</p>
			<p class="indent">At 14th level, the sorcerous origins provide some measure of utility, with little direct impact on spellcasting or combat capabilities. Here, we choose to model the Favored Soul’s feature after the Draconic Bloodline’s feature at the same level, reflecting the touch of the divine with some imagery typically associated with divinity: wings.</p>
			<p class="indent">At 18th level, the sorcerous origins provide options that are both potent and strongly linked to the origin’s central theme. Since the sorcerer will have access to higher-level spells at this level, and the feature we gave it at 1st level to provide some cleric spells won’t have as much of an impact, we decide to tie this class feature to those cleric spells, both to incentivize the continued use of those spells, and to give the Favored Soul a little more resilience in the face of high-level threats.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">favored, soul, origin, sorcerous</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!-- Favored Soul -->
	<element name="Favored Soul" type="Archetype" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL">
		<supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
		<description>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RULE_FAVORED_SOUL" />
			<p class="indent">When we are done with this initial design, here’s what the Favored Soul sorcerous origin looks like:</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_CHOSEN_OF_THE_GODS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_DIVINE_WINGS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_POWER_OF_THE_CHOSEN" />
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Sometimes the spark of magic that fuels a sorcerer comes from a divine source that glimmers within the soul.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_CHOSEN_OF_THE_GODS" level="1" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="1" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_DIVINE_WINGS" level="14" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_POWER_OF_THE_CHOSEN" level="18" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Chosen of the Gods" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_CHOSEN_OF_THE_GODS">
		<description>
			<p>At 1st level, you choose one of the cleric class’s divine domains. You add that domain’s spells for 1st-level clerics to your known spells. These spells do not count against the number of spells you can know, and they are considered to be sorcerer spells for you. When you reach 3rd, 5th, 7th, and 9th levels in the sorcerer class, you likewise learn your domain’s spells that become available at those levels.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Divine Domain (Favored Soul)" supports="Favored Soul Divine Domain" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
		<description>
			<p>At 1st level, you gain proficiency in light armor, medium armor, shields, and simple weapons.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description></description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Extra Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_EXTRA_ATTACK">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 6th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" bonus="extra attack" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Divine Wings" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_DIVINE_WINGS">
		<description>
			<p>At 14th level, you gain the ability to sprout a pair of wings from your back (feathered or bat-like, your choice), gaining a flying speed equal to your current walking speed. You can create these wings as a bonus action on your turn. They last until you dismiss them as a bonus action on your turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can’t manifest your wings while wearing armor unless the armor is made to accommodate them, and clothing not made to accommodate your wings might be destroyed when you manifest them.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>You can sprout a pair of wings from your back (feathered or bat-like, your choice), gaining a flying speed equal to your current walking speed. They last until you dismiss them as a bonus action on your turn. You can’t manifest your wings while wearing armor unless the armor is made to accommodate them, and clothing not made to accommodate your wings might be destroyed when you manifest them.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Power of the Chosen" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_POWER_OF_THE_CHOSEN">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 18th level, when you cast one of the spells you learned from your Chosen of the Gods class feature, you regain hit points equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum +1) + the spell’s level.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>When you cast one of the spells you learned from your Chosen of the Gods class feature, you regain hit points equal to your {{power of the chosen}} + the spell’s level.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="power of the chosen" value="1" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="power of the chosen" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- Favored Soul Divine Domain elements-->
	<element name="Knowledge Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_KNOWLEDGE_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The gods of knowledge—including Oghma, Boccob, Gilean, Aureon, and Thoth—value learning and understanding above all. Some teach that knowledge is to be gathered and shared in libraries and universities, or promote the practical knowledge of craft and invention. Some deities hoard knowledge and keep its secrets to themselves. And some promise their followers that they will gain tremendous power if they unlock the secrets of the multiverse. Followers of these gods study esoteric lore, collect old tomes, delve into the secret places of the earth, and learn all they can. Some gods of knowledge promote the practical knowledge of craft and invention, including smith deities like Gond, Reorx, Onatar, Moradin, Hephaestus, and Goibhniu.</p>
			<h5>Knowledge Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1rd</td><td><em>command, identify</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>augury, suggestion</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>nondetection, speak with dead</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>arcane eye, confusion</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>legend lore, scrying</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The gods of knowledge value learning and understanding above all.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMAND" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_IDENTIFY" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AUGURY" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_NONDETECTION" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_EYE" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEGEND_LORE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCRYING" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Life Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_LIFE_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The Life domain focuses on the vibrant positive energy— one of the fundamental forces of the universe—that sustains all life. The gods of life promote vitality and health through healing the sick and wounded, caring for those in need, and driving away the forces of death and undeath. Almost any non-evil deity can claim influence over this domain, particularly agricultural deities (such as Chauntea, Arawai, and Demeter), sun gods (such as Lathander, Pelor, and Re-Horakhty), gods of healing or endurance (such as Ilmater, Mishakal, Apollo, and Diancecht), and gods of home and community (such as Hestia, Hathor, and Boldrei).</p>
			<h5>Life Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1rd</td><td><em>bless, cure wounds</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>lesser restoration, spiritual weapon</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>beacon of hope, revivify</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>death ward, guardian of faith</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>mass cure wounds, raise dead</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The Life domain focuses on the vibrant positive energy— one of the fundamental forces of the universe—that sustains all life.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLESS" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CURE_WOUNDS" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRITUAL_WEAPON" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BEACON_OF_HOPE" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REVIVIFY" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUARDIAN_OF_FAITH" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_CURE_WOUNDS" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAISE_DEAD" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Light Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_LIGHT_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Gods of light—including Helm, Lathander, Pholtus, Branchala, the Silver Flame, Belenus, Apollo, and Re-Horakhty—promote the ideals of rebirth and renewal, truth, vigilance, and beauty, often using the symbol of the sun. Some of these gods are portrayed as the sun itself or as a charioteer who guides the sun across the sky. Others are tireless sentinels whose eyes pierce every shadow and see through every deception. Some are deities of beauty and artistry, who teach that art is a vehicle for the soul's improvement. Clerics of a god of light are enlightened souls infused with radiance and the power of their gods’ discerning vision, charged with chasing away lies and burning away darkness.</p>
			<h5>Light Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1rd</td><td><em>burning hands, faerie fire</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>flaming sphere, scorching ray</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>daylight, fireball</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>guardian of faith, wall of fire</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>flame strike, scrying</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Gods of light promote the ideals of rebirth and renewal, truth, vigilance, and beauty, often using the symbol of the sun.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BURNING_HANDS" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FAERIE_FIRE" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAMING_SPHERE" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCORCHING_RAY" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DAYLIGHT" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIREBALL" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUARDIAN_OF_FAITH" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FIRE" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAME_STRIKE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCRYING" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Nature Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_NATURE_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Gods of nature are as varied as the natural world itself, from inscrutable gods of the deep forests (such as Silvanus, Obad-Hai, Chislev, Balinor, and Pan) to friendly deities associated with particular springs and groves (such as Eldath). Druids revere nature as a whole and might serve one of these deities, practicing mysterious rites and reciting all-but-forgotten prayers in their own secret tongue. But many of these gods have clerics as well, champions who take a more active role in advancing the interests of a particular nature god. These clerics might hunt the evil monstrosities that despoil the woodlands, bless the harvest of the faithful, or wither the crops of those who anger their gods.</p>
			<h5>Nature Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1rd</td><td><em>animal friendship, speak with animals</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>barkskin, spike growth</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>plant growth, wind wall</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>dominate beast, grasping vine</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>insect plague, tree stride</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Gods of nature are as varied as the natural world itself, from inscrutable gods of the deep forests to friendly deities associated with particular springs and groves.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMAL_FRIENDSHIP" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_ANIMALS" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BARKSKIN" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIKE_GROWTH" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANT_GROWTH" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WIND_WALL" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_BEAST" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GRASPING_VINE" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INSECT_PLAGUE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TREE_STRIDE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Tempest Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_TEMPEST_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Gods whose portfolios include the Tempest domain - including Talos, Umberlee, Kord, Zeboim, the Devourer, Zeus, and Thor—govern storms, sea, and sky. They include gods of lightning and thunder, gods of earthquakes, some fire gods, and certain gods of violence, physical strength, and courage. In some pantheons, a god of this domain rules over other deities and is known for swift justice delivered by thunderbolts. In the pantheons of seafaring people, gods of this domain are ocean deities and the patrons of sailors. Tempest gods send their clerics to inspire fear in the common folk, either to keep those folk on the path of righteousness or to encourage them to offer sacrifices of propitiation to ward off divine wrath.</p>
			<h5>Tempest Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1rd</td><td><em>fog cloud, thunderwave</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>gust of wind, shatter</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>call lightning, sleet storm</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>control water, ice storm</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>destructive wave, insect plague</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Gods whose portfolios include the Tempest domain govern storms, sea, and sky.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMAL_FOG_CLOUD" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THUNDERWAVE" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUST_OF_WIND" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHATTER" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CALL_LIGHTNING" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEET_STORM" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTROL_WATER" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ICE_STORM" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DESTRUCTIVE_WAVE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INSECT_PLAGUE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Trickery Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_TRICKERY_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Gods of trickery—such as Tymora, Beshaba, Olidammara, the Traveler, Garl Glittergold, and Loki—are mischief-makers and instigators who stand as a constant challenge to the accepted order among both gods and mortals. They’re patrons of thieves, scoundrels, gamblers, rebels, and liberators. Their clerics are a disruptive force in the world, puncturing pride, mocking tyrants, stealing from the rich, freeing captives, and flouting hollow traditions. They prefer subterfuge, pranks, deception, and theft rather than direct confrontation.</p>
			<h5>Trickery Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1rd</td><td><em>charm person, disguise self</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>mirror image, pass without trace</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>blink, dispel magic</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>dimension door, polymorph</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>dominate person, modify memory</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Clerics of Trickery Domain are a disruptive force in the world, puncturing pride, mocking tyrants, stealing from the rich, freeing captives, and flouting hollow traditions.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PASS_WITHOUT_TRACE" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINK" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIMENSION_DOOR" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MODIFY_MEMORY" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="War Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_WAR_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>War has many manifestations. It can make heroes of ordinary people. It can be desperate and horrific, with acts of cruelty and cowardice eclipsing instances of excellence and courage. In either case, the gods of war watch over warriors and reward them for their great deeds. The clerics of such gods excel in battle, inspiring others to fight the good fight or offering acts of violence as prayers. Gods of war include champions of honor and chivalry (such as Torm, Heironeous, and Kiri- Jolith) as well as gods of destruction and pillage (such as Erythnul, the Fury, Gruumsh, and Ares) and gods of conquest and domination (such as Bane, Hextor, and Maglubiyet). Other war gods (such as Tempus, Nike, and Nuada) take a more neutral stance, promoting war in all its manifestations and supporting warriors in any circumstance.</p>
			<h5>War Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1rd</td><td><em>divine favor, shield of faith</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>magic weapon, spiritual weapon</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>crusader’s mantle, spirit guardians</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>freedom of movement, stoneskin</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>flame strike, hold monster</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The clerics of War Domain excel in battle, inspiring others to fight the good fight or offering acts of violence as prayers.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINE_FAVOR" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD_OF_FAITH" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_WEAPON" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRITUAL_WEAPON" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CRUSADERS_MANTLE" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRIT_GUARDIANS" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONESKIN" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAME_STRIKE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_MONSTER" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

</elements>