<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Unearthed Arcana: Waterborne Adventures</name>
		<description>The new character options presented in this month’s Unearthed Arcana showcase a simple design approach to adventure on the high seas. These rules include new options for the Fighting Style, Roguish Archetype, and Sorcerous Origin class features, as well as a playable minotaur race from Dragonlance’s world of Krynn. Created to be specifically useful for nautical D&amp;D campaigns, these rules are general enough that they can be useful in any campaign.</description>
		<author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/articles/unearthed-arcana/unearthed-arcana-waterborne-adventures">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.1.5">
			<file name="20150504.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/unearthed-arcana/2015/20150504.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Unearthed Arcana: Waterborne Adventures" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_UNEARTHED_ARCANA_20150504">
		<description>
			<p>The new character options presented in this month’s Unearthed Arcana showcase a simple design approach to adventure on the high seas. These rules include new options for the Fighting Style, Roguish Archetype, and Sorcerous Origin class features, as well as a playable minotaur race from Dragonlance’s world of Krynn. Created to be specifically useful for nautical D&amp;D campaigns, these rules are general enough that they can be useful in any campaign.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">UA20150504</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/articles/unearthed-arcana/unearthed-arcana-waterborne-adventures</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="playtest">true</set>
			<set name="release">20150504</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!-- Minotaur -->
	<element name="Minotaur" type="Race" source="Unearthed Arcana: Waterborne Adventures" id="ID_WOTC_UA_RACE_MINOTAUR">
		<description>
			<p class="flavor">In the world of Krynn, the setting of the Dragonlance saga, minotaurs live in an honor‐based society where strength determines power in both the gladiatorial arenas and in daily life. At home on both land and sea, the minotaurs of Krynn are ferocious sea raiders who rank as the ablest and most dangerous sailors in the world</p>
			<h4>ARROGANT CONQUERORS</h4>
			<p>Minotaurs embrace the notion that the weak should perish and that the strong must rule—and that they themselves are the strongest and most powerful race on Krynn. They believe their destiny is to rule the world, and that their dominion will be one of conquest and military might. To that end, all minotaurs are trained in weapons, armor, and tactics from a young age.</p>
			<p class="indent">The minotaurs’ arrogance stems from a combination of strength, cunning, and intellect—three virtues they hold dear, and which they deem the foundation of their greatness. They believe that this combination of traits is what sets them apart from their rivals.</p>
			<h4>TRIAL BY COMBAT</h4>
			<p>Minotaur society is built on the principle that might makes right, and that considerations of justice are unnecessary. The minotaurs are led by an emperor served by a council of eight minotaurs called the Supreme Circle. All posts within the government, including the emperor’s, are won by the strongest and cleverest minotaurs, as proved by combat in the Circus.</p>
			<p class="indent">The Circus is the only means by which a minotaur can rise in society. It is a grand, annual display of single combat in which minotaurs battle each other for supremacy. Minotaur youths must prove themselves in the Circus to earn their passage to adulthood.</p>
			<p class="indent">Participation in the Circus is yet another reason why minotaurs look down on other folk. To the minotaurs, death and glory in battle are a natural process. Combat is the key to ensuring that the strong survive, and that the weak are set aside before they can undermine their superiors’ grand schemes of conquest.</p>
			<h4>HONOR ABOVE ALL</h4>
			<p>For all their cruelty, minotaurs are bound by a powerful sense of honor. Each victory brings greater honor to both individual minotaurs and their families. Defeat invokes a stain that only death can fully wash away.</p>
			<p class="indent">Honor demands that minotaurs keep their word once it is offered, and each minotaur remains faithful to friends and clan above all else. Minotaurs rarely befriend folk of other races, as they all too often encounter them only in battle. If a minotaur does strike up a friendship, it is typically with other creatures that display the minotaurs’ virtues and love of battle. To such friends, a minotaur becomes an ally whose support will never waver.</p>
			<h4>SEA REAVERS</h4>
			<p>In the world of Krynn, the minotaurs rule a chain of islands dominated by the isles of Mithas and Kothas. Bound by the sea on all sides, the minotaurs focused their tenacity, strength, and cunning to become some of the most skilled and ferocious mariners in the world. They range across the water in their ships, raiding and pillaging as they wish. Minotaurs sometimes engage in trade, but they much prefer to take what they want by force. After all, as the strongest of all folk, they deserve the treasures and goods that lesser creatures have gathered.</p>
			<h4>MINOTAUR NAMES</h4>
			<p>Minotaur clan names originate with a great hero whose descendants take on that name as their own, doing their best to live up to the ideals of their ancestor. On Krynn, clan names are always preceded by the prefix “es‐” for minotaurs from lands controlled by the island of Mithas, or “de‐” for minotaurs from areas under the sway of Kothas.</p>
			<p><span class="emphasis">Male Names:</span>Beliminorgath, Cinmac, Dastrun, Edder, Galdar, Ganthirogani, Hecariverani, Kyris, Tosher, Zurgas<br/>
				<span class="emphasis">Female Names:</span>Ayasha, Calina, Fliara, Helati, Keeli, Kyri, Mogara, Sekra, Tariki, Telia<br/>
				<span class="emphasis">Clan Names:</span>Athak, Bregan, Entragath, Kaziganthi, Lagrangli, Mascun, Orilg, Sumarr, Teskos, Zhakan<br/>
			</p>
			<h4>MINOTAUR TRAITS</h4>
			<p>Your minotaur character possesses a number of traits that reflect the power and superiority of your kind.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Ability Score Increase. </i></b>Your Strength score increases by 1. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Conqueror’s Virtue. </i></b>From a young age, you focused on one of the three virtues of strength, cunning, or intellect. Your choice of your Strength, Intelligence, or Wisdom score increases by 1. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Age. </i></b> Minotaurs enter adulthood at around the age of 17 and can live up to 150 years. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Alignment. </i></b> Minotaurs believe in a strict code of honor, and thus tend toward law. They are loyal to the death and make implacable enemies, even as their brutal culture and disdain for weakness push them toward evil. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Size. </i></b>Minotaurs typically stand well over 6 feet tall and weigh an average of 300 pounds. Your size is Medium. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Speed. </i></b>Your base walking speed is 30 feet. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Horns. </i></b>You are never unarmed. You are proficient with your horns, which are a melee weapon that deals 1d10 piercing damage. Your horns grant you advantage on all checks made to shove a creature, but not to avoid being shoved yourself. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Goring Rush. </i></b>When you use the Dash action during your turn, you can make a melee attack with your horns as a bonus action. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Hammering Horns. </i></b>When you use the Attack action during your turn to make a melee attack, you can attempt to shove a creature with your horns as a bonus action. You cannot use this shove attempt to knock a creature prone. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Labyrinthine Recall. </i></b>You can perfectly recall any path you have traveled. </p>
			<p class="indent"><b><i>Sea Reaver. </i></b>You gain proficiency with navigator’s tools and vehicles (water). </p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="names" type="male">Beliminorgath, Cinmac, Dastrun, Edder, Galdar, Ganthirogani, Hecariverani, Kyris, Tosher, Zurgas</set>
			<set name="names" type="female">Ayasha, Calina, Fliara, Helati, Keeli, Kyri, Mogara, Sekra, Tariki, Telia</set>
			<set name="names" type="clan">Athak, Bregan, Entragath, Kaziganthi, Lagrangli, Mascun, Orilg, Sumarr, Teskos, Zhakan</set>
			<set name="names-format">{{name}} of clan {{clan}}</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="strength" value="1" />
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Conqueror’s Virtue (Minotaur)" supports="ID_INTERNAL_ASI_STRENGTH|ID_INTERNAL_ASI_INTELLIGENCE|ID_INTERNAL_ASI_WISDOM" />
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_UA_RACIAL_TRAIT_MINOTAUR_HORNS" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_UA_RACIAL_TRAIT_MINOTAUR_GORING_RUSH"/>
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_UA_RACIAL_TRAIT_MINOTAUR_HAMMERING_HORNS"/>
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_UA_RACIAL_TRAIT_MINOTAUR_LABYRINTHINE_RECALL"/>
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_UA_RACIAL_TRAIT_MINOTAUR_SEA_REAVER"/>
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Horns" type="Racial Trait" source="Unearthed Arcana: Waterborne Adventures" id="ID_WOTC_UA_RACIAL_TRAIT_MINOTAUR_HORNS">
		<description>
			<p>You are never unarmed. You are proficient with your horns, which are a melee weapon that deals 1d10 piercing damage. Your horns grant you advantage on all checks made to shove a creature, but not to avoid being shoved yourself.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You are proficient with your horns, which are a melee weapon that deals 1d10 piercing damage. Your horns grant you advantage on all checks made to shove a creature, but not to avoid being shoved yourself.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Goring Rush" type="Racial Trait" source="Unearthed Arcana: Waterborne Adventures" id="ID_WOTC_UA_RACIAL_TRAIT_MINOTAUR_GORING_RUSH">
		<description>
			<p>When you use the Dash action during your turn, you can make a melee attack with your horns as a bonus action.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you use the Dash action during your turn, you can make a melee attack with your horns as a bonus action.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Hammering Horns" type="Racial Trait" source="Unearthed Arcana: Waterborne Adventures" id="ID_WOTC_UA_RACIAL_TRAIT_MINOTAUR_HAMMERING_HORNS">
		<description>
			<p>When you use the Attack action during your turn to make a melee attack, you can attempt to shove a creature with your horns as a bonus action. You cannot use this shove attempt to knock a creature prone.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you use the Attack action during your turn to make a melee attack, you can attempt to shove a creature with your horns as a bonus action. You cannot use this shove attempt to knock a creature prone.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Labyrinthine Recall" type="Racial Trait" source="Unearthed Arcana: Waterborne Adventures" id="ID_WOTC_UA_RACIAL_TRAIT_MINOTAUR_LABYRINTHINE_RECALL">
		<description>
			<p>You can perfectly recall any path you have traveled.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can perfectly recall any path you have traveled.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Sea Reaver" type="Racial Trait" source="Unearthed Arcana: Waterborne Adventures" id="ID_WOTC_UA_RACIAL_TRAIT_MINOTAUR_SEA_REAVER">
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency with navigator’s tools and vehicles (water).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You gain proficiency with navigator’s tools and vehicles (water).</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_NAVIGATORS_TOOLS" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_VEHICLES_WATER" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<!-- Fighting Style: Mariner -->
	<element name="Mariner" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Waterborne Adventures" id="ID_WOTC_UA_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_MARINER">
		<supports>Fighting Style, Fighter, Paladin, Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As long as you are not wearing heavy armor or using a shield, you have a swimming speed and a climbing speed equal to your normal speed, and you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>As long as you are not wearing heavy armor or using a shield, you have a swimming speed and a climbing speed equal to your normal speed, and you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="speed:swim" value="speed" bonus="base" equipped="!([armor:heavy]||[shield:any])" />
			<stat name="speed:climb" value="speed" bonus="base" equipped="!([armor:heavy]||[shield:any])" />
			<stat name="ac:misc" value="1" bonus="fighting style" equipped="!([armor:heavy]||[shield:any])" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>