<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Human</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="https://media.wizards.com/2018/downloads/magic/Plane_Shift_Dominaria.pdf">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.0.4">
			<file name="race-keldon-human.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/unearthed-arcana/planeshift/dominaria/race-keldon-human.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

  <element name="Keldon Human" type="Race Variant" source="Plane Shift: Dominaria" id="ID_WOTC_PSD_RACE_VARIANT_KELDON_HUMAN">
    <supports>Human</supports>
    <description>
      <p>The people of Keld are human, but they are like no other humans anywhere. Nearly all adults stand over six feet tall, and heights above seven feet are not uncommon. They are massively muscled and have gray skin, ranging from an ashy gray-white to a deeper bluegray. The typical Keldon’s hairline points sharply down in the middle of the forehead and at either temple, but recedes elsewhere—sometimes dramatically. Keldons are remarkably resistant to the cold of their homeland, baring skin even in near-freezing temperatures without discomfort.</p>
      <p>Keldons value self-reliance, strength, and courage above all else. Anything that is the product of their own labor is a fine thing. Anything else is treated with a healthy dose of skepticism. At best, they are a proud, pragmatic, passionate people, and their loyalty is fierce once earned. At worst, they can be reckless, hot-tempered, and violent—and no small number of Keldons still consider these qualities virtues rather than vices.</p>
      <p>Because of their many exploits as both conquerors and mercenaries, Keldons appear in the legends and histories of other peoples across the world. Sometimes these tales are exaggerated—but many that sound exaggerated are not.</p>
      <p>
        <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase. </span> Your Strength score increases by 2, and your Constitution score increases by 1.<br />
        <span class="feature">Age. </span>Keldons reach adulthood in their late teens and live less than a century. <br />
        <span class="feature">Alignment. </span>Keldons tend toward chaotic alignments, and many walk a fine line between good and evil.<br />
        <span class="feature">Size. </span>Keldons are taller and heavier than the human norms of other cultures, standing almost universally above 6 feet tall and reaching heights above 7 feet. Your size is Medium.<br />
        <span class="feature">Speed. </span>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.<br />
        <span class="feature">Languages. </span>You can speak, read, and write Common and Keldon.<br />
        <span class="feature">Natural Athelete. </span>You have proficiency in the Athletics skill.<br />
        <span class="feature">Keldon Resilience. </span>You have proficiency in Strength saving throws.<br />
        <span class="feature">Icehaven Born. </span>You are naturally adapted to cold climates.<br />
      </p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false"/>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Grants" id="ID_UA_PS_GRANTS_HUMAN_VARIANT" />
      <stat name="strength" value="2" />
      <stat name="constitution" value="1" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS" />
      <grant type="Language" id="ID_WOTC_PSD_LANGUAGE_KELDON" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" name="Icehaven Born" id="ID_WOTC_PSD_HUMAN_RACIAL_ICEHAVEN_BORN" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  
  <element name="Icehaven Born" type="Racial Trait" source="Plane Shift: Dominaria" id="ID_WOTC_PSD_HUMAN_RACIAL_ICEHAVEN_BORN">
    <description>
      <p>You are immune to the effects of cold temperatures.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You are immune to the effects of cold temperatures.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>

  <!-- Languages -->
  <element name="Keldon" type="Language" source="Plane Shift: Dominaria" id="ID_WOTC_PSD_LANGUAGE_KELDON">
        <description>
            <p>A language common to the land of Keld used mostly by the Keldon Humans.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="exotic">true</set>
            <set name="speakers">Humans</set>
            <set name="script">Humans</set>
        </setters>
   </element>



  
  
</elements>