<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Plane Shift: Amonkhet</name>
        <description>Plane Shift: Amonkhet</description>
        <author url="https://media.wizards.com/2017/downloads/magic/plane-shift_amonkhet.pdf">Wizards of the Coast</author>
        <update version="0.0.3">
            <file name="background-initiate.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/unearthed-arcana/planeshift/amonkhet/background-initiate.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>

	<element name="Initiate" type="Background" source="Plane Shift: Amonkhet" id="ID_WOTC_PSA_BACKGROUND_INITIATE">
		<description>
			<p>You are an initiate, on the path to completing the trials of the five gods in the hope of earning a glorified death in the final Trial of Zeal. Some combination of your natural aptitude, your crop’s needs, and your teachers’ assessment while you were an acolyte led you to focus your training in one particular area of specialization— hand-to-hand combat, long-range combat, or spellcasting. But only a well-rounded initiate can be called truly worthy of the afterlife.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you are a hand-to-hand specialist, consider the barbarian, fighter, monk, paladin, or rogue classes. As a long-range combat specialist, you might be a fighter, a ranger, or a rogue. If you are a spellcasting specialist, you might be a bard, sorcerer, or wizard. And beyond this initial choice, you might consider multiclassing or using feats to round out your skills in all three areas.</p>
			<p>
                <span class="emphasis">Skill Proficiencies:</span>Athletics, Intimidation<br />
                <span class="emphasis">Tool Proficiencies:</span>One type of gaming set, vehicles (land)<br />
                <span class="emphasis">Equipment:</span>A simple puzzle box, a scroll containing the basic teachings of the five gods, a gaming set, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 15 gp. If you have completed any trials before the start of the campaign, you also have any cartouches you have earned.
			</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_PSA_BACKGROUND_INITIATE_FEATURE_TRIAL_OF_THE_FIVE_GODS" />
			<h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
			<p>An initiate’s life is focused on the trials, but it doesn’t need to be all about the trials. Though some initiates are highly focused on their training, most undergo that training while also experiencing joy, sorrow, love, loss, anger, jealousy, hope, faith, delight—the whole range of mortal emotions and experience. The afterlife might be a constant presence in every initiate’s mind, but it is the culmination of a life well-lived—not a replacement for it.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">Athletics, Intimidation, Gaming Set, Vehicles (Land)</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Gaming Set (Initiate)" supports="Gaming Set" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_VEHICLES_LAND" />
			<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_WOTC_PSA_BACKGROUND_INITIATE_FEATURE_TRIAL_OF_THE_FIVE_GODS" requirements="!ID_WOCT_PSA_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_DISSENTER_SHELTER_OF_DISSENTERS"/>
			<select type="Background Variant" name="Variant Initiate" supports="Background Variant, Vizier" optional="true" />
			<select name="Personality Trait" type="List" number="2">
				<item id="1">I always have a joke on hand when the mood gets too serious.</item>
				<item id="2">I use sarcasm and insults to keep a distance between myself and my crop-mates, because I don’t want to get attached to them.</item>
				<item id="3">I’ll settle for nothing less than perfection—in myself, in my crop- mates, in everything.</item>
				<item id="4">I’m so focused on the glorious afterlife that nothing in this life can shake my calm resolve.</item>
				<item id="5">I enjoy using my skills to help those who lack those same skills.</item>
				<item id="6">I train hard so that I can play hard at the end of the day. I fully expect to play even harder in the glorious afterlife, but I’m not in a hurry to get there.</item>
				<item id="7">I’m perfectly happy letting others pick up the slack for me while I take it easy.</item>
				<item id="8">I’m constantly sizing up everyone around me, thinking about what kind of opponent they’ll be in the final trial.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Ideal" type="List">
				<item id="1">Solidarity. The thing that matters most of all is that we’re there for each other. (Lawful)</item>
				<item id="2">Knowledge. The world is a puzzle—a mystery waiting to be solved. (Neutral)</item>
				<item id="3">Strength. All that matters to me is my own perfection. Let everyone else seek that perfection in their own way. (Any)</item>
				<item id="4">Ambition. I’m going to prove that I deserve only the best—of everything. (Evil)</item>
				<item id="5">Zeal. Anything worth doing is worth throwing my whole self into. (Any)</item>
				<item id="6">Redemption. I will train all the harder to make up for the doubt I entertained when I was younger. (Any)</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Bond" type="List">
				<item id="1">One of my crop-mates is my dearest friend, and I hope we will face each other in the final trial.</item>
				<item id="2">I am in love with a vizier.</item>
				<item id="3">I am particularly drawn to one of the five gods, and I want nothing more than to win that god’s particular favor.</item>
				<item id="4">I am more devoted to Naktamun and its people than I am to any of the ideals of the gods.</item>
				<item id="5">My weapon was a gift from a beloved trainer who died in an accident.</item>
				<item id="6">I carry a memento of my time as an acolyte, and I treasure it above all other things.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Flaw" type="List">
				<item id="1">I’m easily distracted by an attractive person, which could be the death of me in the trials.</item>
				<item id="2">I really wanted to be a vizier, and I’m angry at the god who didn’t choose me.</item>
				<item id="3">Training for a lifetime to die in the end seems like a big waste of energy.</item>
				<item id="4">I’m not at all sure I’ll be able to grant a glorified death to any of my crop-mates.</item>
				<item id="5">I have a lasting grudge against one of my crop-mates, and each of us wants to see the other fail.</item>
				<item id="6">I think I’ve figured out that this world is not what it seems. Something dark is going on here.</item>
			</select>
		</rules>       
	</element>
	<element name="Feature: Trial of the Five Gods" type="Background Feature" source="Plane Shift: Amonkhet" id="ID_WOTC_PSA_BACKGROUND_INITIATE_FEATURE_TRIAL_OF_THE_FIVE_GODS">
		<supports>Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your life is oriented around your participation in the five trials that will determine your worthiness in the afterlife. While you prepare for and undergo those tri- als, you have constant access to training. A comfortable place to live and regular meals are provided to you by servitor mummies (the anointed) under the supervision of viziers. You can enjoy these benefits only as long as you obey the societal norms of Naktamun—training for the trials (with or without your crop), obeying the orders of the gods, and following the instructions of their viziers. If you violate these norms, you risk being treated as a dissenter. See “Trials of the Five Gods” for more information about undertaking the trials and their rewards.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Trial of the Five Gods" />
	</element>
</elements>
