<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Character Backgrounds</name>
        <update version="0.0.1">
            <file name="background-options.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/supplements/descent-into-avernus/backgrounds/background-options.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>	
	<element name="Baldur’s Gate Feature: Religious Community" type="Background Feature" source="Baldur’s Gate: Descent into Avernus" id="ID_WOCT_BGDIA_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_RELIGIOUS_COMMUNITY">
		<requirements>ID_BACKGROUND_ACOLYTE</requirements>
		<supports>Background Feature, Optional Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You’re tightly connected with the religious community of Baldur’s Gate. You know if a deity has a following in the city and any places that faith openly congregates and the neighborhoods those faithful typically inhabit. While this isn’t remarkable for most of the city’s larger faiths, keeping track of the hundreds of religions newcomers bring with them is no mean feat.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Religious Community" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Baldur’s Gate Feature: Long-Lost Heir" type="Background Feature" source="Baldur’s Gate: Descent into Avernus" id="ID_WOCT_BGDIA_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_LONG_LOST_HEIR">
		<requirements>ID_BACKGROUND_CHARLATAN</requirements>	
		<supports>Background Feature, Optional Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You’re well-versed in the mannerisms and idiosyncrasies of Baldurian patriars and other nobles, imitating them smoothly enough to convince even the snootiest family heads of your authenticity. You’re skilled at posing as the long-lost heir to some imaginary or extinguished patriar lineage.</p>
			<p class="indent">Because of your skill in passing yourself off as a patriar, you have a Watch token that allows you alone into the Upper City of Baldur’s Gate. You might be able to bluff others through with you, or even convince members of the Watch that you’re patriar. However, any true test of your authenticity is likely to reveal your deception.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Long-Lost Heir" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Baldur’s Gate Feature: Criminal Connections" type="Background Feature" source="Baldur’s Gate: Descent into Avernus" id="ID_WOCT_BGDIA_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_CRIMINAL_CONNECTIONS">
		<requirements>ID_BACKGROUND_CRIMINAL</requirements>	
		<supports>Background Feature, Optional Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>In Baldur’s Gate, crime is just another business. As a result, you can arrange a meeting with a low ranking operative of nearly any business, patriar family, crew, government institution, or—certainly— the Guild. This operative will hear you out and, at their discretion take your information on request up their chain of command. These meetings almost always occur in shady venues.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Criminal Connections" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Baldur’s Gate Feature: Backstage Pass" type="Background Feature" source="Baldur’s Gate: Descent into Avernus" id="ID_WOCT_BGDIA_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_BACKSTAGE_PASS">
		<requirements>ID_BACKGROUND_ENTERTAINER</requirements>
		<supports>Background Feature, Optional Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You’ve learned that most of the real business of entertainment (or any other venture) happens behind the scenes. It’s easy for you to case what sorts of audiences attend what venue—like how toughs gather at the Blushing Mermaid or how brash patriars congregate at the Helm and Cloak. After a successful performance, you may meet an enthusiastic member of the crowd—someone of an occupation or social class that frequents the establishment. This contact is delighted to talk with you, and to listen.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Backstage Pass" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Baldur’s Gate Feature: Patriar" type="Background Feature" source="Baldur’s Gate: Descent into Avernus" id="ID_WOCT_BGDIA_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_PATRIAR">
		<requirements>ID_BACKGROUND_NOBLE</requirements>
		<supports>Background Feature, Optional Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>As a member of one of the elite families of Baldur’s Gate, you may pass through city gates without paying tolls, mingle among the Gate’s nobility unquestioned, and impress those on the lookout for wealthy patrons. You are welcome in the Upper City and may stay there after dark without being harassed or evicted. Your word is accepted over others’ without question, and any corruption among guards or government officials tends to work in your favor, not against you—at least until you make some effort to expose it.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Patriar" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>