<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="deities.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/supplements/eberron-rising-from-the-last-war/deities.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
    <element name="Arawai" type="Deity" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_DEITY_ARAWAI">
        <description>
            <p>Arawai is the Sovereign of Life and Love. She is the patron of fertility and of the benevolent aspects of nature, bringing good harvest and gentle rain.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="alignment"></set>
            <set name="domains">Life, Nature</set>
            <set name="symbol">Sheaf of wheat tied with green ribbon or bronze dragon</set>
            <set name="gender">female</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Aureon" type="Deity" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_DEITY_AUREON">
        <description>
            <p>Aureon is the Sovereign of Law and Lore. He is considered the first wizard, who shared the secrets of wizardry with the world.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="alignment"></set>
            <set name="domains">Knowledge, Order</set>
            <set name="symbol">Open tome or blue dragon</set>
            <set name="gender">male</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Balinor" type="Deity" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_DEITY_BALINOR">
        <description>
            <p>Balinor is the Sovereign of Horn and Hunt. He guides both the beast and the hunter, and he is the patron of those who walk on the edge of civilization and the natural world.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="alignment"></set>
            <set name="domains">Nature, War</set>
            <set name="symbol">Pair of antlers or green dragon</set>
            <set name="gender">male</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Boldrei" type="Deity" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_DEITY_BOLDREI">
        <description>
            <p>Boldrei is the Sovereign of Hall and Hearth. She guides and protects communities and families, inspiring people to work together for the common good.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="alignment"></set>
            <set name="domains">Life</set>
            <set name="symbol">Fire in a stone hearth or copper dragon</set>
            <set name="gender">female</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Dol Arrah" type="Deity" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_DEITY_DOL_ARRAH">
        <description>
            <p>Doi Arrah is the sun that drives away the darkness. She stands for wisdom in war and for those who fight with honor, pursue justice, and make sacrifices for the greater good.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="alignment"></set>
            <set name="domains">Light, War</set>
            <set name="symbol">Rising sun or red dragon</set>
            <set name="gender">female</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Dol Dorn" type="Deity" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_DEITY_DOL_DORN">
        <description>
            <p>Doi Dorn is the Sovereign of Strength and Steel. He is the patron of the common soldier, and he guides the hands of anyone who holds a weapon. He embodies courage, strength, and martial skill.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="alignment"></set>
            <set name="domains">War</set>
            <set name="symbol">Longsword crossed over a shield or silver dragon</set>
            <set name="gender">male</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Kol Korran" type="Deity" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_DEITY_KOL_KORRAN">
        <description>
            <p>Kol Korran is the Sovereign of World and Wealth. He guards travelers and guides traders. Although the Trickery domain is suggested for his clerics, Kol Korran guides fair negotiation; those driven solely by greed prefer the Keeper of the Dark Six.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="alignment"></set>
            <set name="domains">Trickery</set>
            <set name="symbol">Nine-sided gold coin or white dragon</set>
            <set name="gender">male</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Olladra" type="Deity" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_DEITY_OLLADRA">
        <description>
            <p>Olladra is the Sovereign of Feast and Fortune. She is the giver of joy and the granter of luck, patron to entertainers, gamblers, and anyone who takes a chance.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="alignment"></set>
            <set name="domains">Life, Trickery</set>
            <set name="symbol">Domino or black dragon</set>
            <set name="gender">female</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Onatar" type="Deity" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_DEITY_ONATAR">
        <description>
            <p>Onatar is the Sovereign of Fire and Forge. He guides both mundane smiths and artificers, inspiring anyone who performs an act of creation.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="alignment"></set>
            <set name="domains">Forge, Knowledge</set>
            <set name="symbol">Crossed hammer and tongs or brass dragon</set>
            <set name="gender">male</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
	
    <element name="The Devourer" type="Deity" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_DEITY_THE_DEVOURER">
        <description>
            <p>The Devourer governs the destructive power of nature, both pure elemental force and savagery in beasts.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="alignment"></set>
            <set name="domains">Tempest</set>
            <set name="symbol">Bundle of five sharpened bones or dragon turtle</set>
            <set name="gender">male</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="The Fury" type="Deity" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_DEITY_THE_FURY">
        <description>
            <p>The Fury governs both passion and revenge, rage and despair. She offers revenge to those who have been wronged, but her vengeance often leads to suffering.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="alignment"></set>
            <set name="domains">War</set>
            <set name="symbol">Winged wyrm with woman’s head and arms</set>
            <set name="gender">female</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="The Keeper" type="Deity" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_DEITY_THE_KEEPER">
        <description>
            <p>The Keeper snatches souls before they can reach Dolurrh and hoards them along with his vast wealth. Those driven by greed call him their patron, and his priests often act as criminal fixers.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="alignment"></set>
            <set name="domains">Death</set>
            <set name="symbol">Dragonshard in the shape of a fang or dracolich</set>
            <set name="gender">male</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="The Mockery" type="Deity" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_DEITY_THE_MOCKERY">
        <description>
            <p>The Mockery is the patron of treachery and of terror in battle. He guides those who seek victory through guile, both warriors and assassins. He was once the brother of Doi Dorn and Doi Arrah, but he was stripped of his skin and his name after betraying them.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="alignment"></set>
            <set name="domains">Trickery, War</set>
            <set name="symbol">Five blood-spattered blades or flayed dragon</set>
            <set name="gender">male</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="The Shadow" type="Deity" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_DEITY_THE_SHADOW">
        <description>
            <p>The Shadow is the dark side of knowledge and ambition. It’s said to be Aureon’s shadow, given malign life when Aureon mastered magic. The Shadow is the maker of monsters and the keeper of forbidden secrets, and it offers malevolent spells to warlocks and wizards.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="alignment"></set>
            <set name="domains">Knowledge</set>
            <set name="symbol">Obsidian tower</set>
            <set name="gender">male</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="The Traveler" type="Deity" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_DEITY_THE_TRAVELER">
        <description>
            <p>The Traveler asserts that chaos drives evolution and that change makes us stronger. The Traveler is a trickster and the giver of dangerous gifts. Some artificers worship the Traveler, seeing it as the lord of innovation, but the gifts of the Traveler always have unexpected consequences.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="alignment"></set>
            <set name="domains">Forge, Knowledge, Trickery</set>
            <set name="symbol">Four crossed, rune-inscribed bones</set>
            <set name="gender">male</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
	
    <element name="The Silver Flame" type="Deity" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_DEITY_THE_SILVER_FLAME">
        <description>
			<ul>
				<li>The Silver Flame is force of light that holds fiends at bay. Those who seek to defend the innocent from evil can draw on the power of the Flame.</li>
				<li>Every mortal soul can find the light. Inspire and guide others to virtuous behavior; force is a last resort.</li>
				<li>Listen to the Voice of the Flame; beware the deceiving whispers of the Shadow in the Flame.</li>
			</ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="alignment"></set>
            <set name="domains">Life, Light, War</set>
            <set name="symbol">Flame drawn on silver or molded from silver</set>
            <set name="gender">male</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="The Blood of Vol" type="Deity" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_DEITY_THE_BLOOD_OF_VOL">
        <description>
            <ul>
				<li>Everyone has a spark of divinity. Find that power within.</li>
				<li>Death is the end, Dolurrh is oblivion, and if the gods exist, they are cruel. Stand with those you care for; all we have is this life and each other.</li>
			</ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="alignment"></set>
            <set name="domains">Death, Life</set>
            <set name="symbol">Red teardrop gem</set>
            <set name="gender">male</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="Cults of the Dragon Below" type="Deity" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_DEITY_CULTS_OF_THE_DRAGON_BELOW">
        <description>
            <ul>
				<li>A paradise exists within the world, a vale bathed in the light of the Inner Sun. Earn your passage with the blood of worthy foes.</li>
				<li>Our existence is a chrysalis state, preparing us for transcendent immortality within the bowels of the gibbering mouther.</li>
				<li>The Lord of Eyes sees all secrets. Its gaze elevates the worthy and slays the unbeliever. Drive doubt from your heart, and you will see reality through new eyes.</li>
			</ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="alignment"></set>
            <set name="domains">Trickery</set>
            <set name="symbol">Varies</set>
            <set name="gender">male</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="The Path of Light" type="Deity" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_DEITY_THE_PATH_OF_LIGHT">
        <description>
            <ul>
				<li>We live in an age of darkness. We must find the path that leads to the light.</li>
				<li>Act with compassion and courage. Each noble act is a step on the path.</li>
				<li>Hone your body and your mind. You are the tool you will use to change reality.</li>
			</ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="alignment"></set>
            <set name="domains">Life, Light</set>
            <set name="symbol">Brilliant crystal</set>
            <set name="gender">male</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="The Spirits of the Past" type="Deity" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_DEITY_THE_SPIRITS_OF_THE_PAST">
        <description>
            <ul>
				<li>We are the spiritual anchors of the greatest champions of our people. Through our faith, we keep their spirits from being lost to oblivion.</li>
				<li>You have been chosen by a hero. Live your life as they lived theirs, letting their instincts guide you.</li>
				<li>Treasure our past and the stories of our people. You are the vessel through which new legends will arise.</li>
			</ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="alignment"></set>
            <set name="domains">Nature, War</set>
            <set name="symbol">Varies</set>
            <set name="gender">male</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
    <element name="The Undying Court" type="Deity" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_DEITY_THE_UNDYING_COURT">
        <description>
            <ul>
				<li>Our greatest champions and sages will never be lost to us. Their wisdom guides us, and their power protects us all.</li>
				<li>Honor our past. Respect our traditions. Perfect your skills and you may earn your place among the Deathless.</li>
				<li>Destroy those foul creatures that channel the power of Mahar, for they consume the essence of our world.</li>
			</ul>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="alignment"></set>
            <set name="domains">Grave, Knowledge, Life</set>
            <set name="symbol">Golden mask</set>
            <set name="gender">male</set>
        </setters>
    </element>
</elements>