<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.0.3">
			<file name="items.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/supplements/eberron-rising-from-the-last-war/items.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Eberron Dragonshard" type="Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ITEM_EBERRON_DRAGONSHARD">
		<description>
			<p>Eberron dragonshards are found in shallow soil and often encased in geode-like stone shells. Eberron dragonshards can be found almost anywhere, but the most significant deposits have been discovered in jungle environments, notably Q’barra and Xen’drik. In their raw form, Eberron dragonshards are rosy crystals with crimson swirls fl.owing in their depths and are typically refined into a glowing powder. This dragonshard dust can be used to fuel almost any act of magic. When casting a spell, you can use Eberron dragonshard dust in place of any spell component that has a cost, unless the DM says otherwise (the dust’s market value is the same as the replaced component). Eberron dragonshard dust is used in the creation of some magic items, and many powerful tools-such as the lightning rail and elemental airships-require an ongoing expenditure of Eberron dragonshards to maintain their enchantments.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Khyber Dragonshard" type="Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ITEM_KHYBER_DRAGONSHARD">
		<description>
			<p>Khyber dragonshards are found deep in the earth, often near layers of magma. These crystals typically grow on cavern walls, and superstition says they flourish in areas with significant fiendish activity. Khyber dragonshards are deep blue or dark violet, laced with gleaming veins. Khyber dragonshards have an affinity for binding magics. Elemental binding-which is behind airships, the lightning rail, and elemental galleonsrequires a Khyber dragonshard to hold the elemental. Khyber shards are used for phylacteries, planar binding, and other effects that trap or manipulate spirits. Khyber dragonshards can also be used for necromantic rites.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Siberys Dragonshard" type="Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ITEM_SIBERYS_DRAGONSHARD">
		<description>
			<p>Siberys dragonshards fall from the Ring of Siberys, the ring of crystals that encircles the world. While rare in Khorvaire, there are significant Siberys dragonshard fields in the continent of Xen’drik, and this is a potential source of great wealth for explorers. Siberys dragonshards are amber in color, with swirling golden veins gleaming within. These dragonshards are used in the crafting of magic items that require dragonmarks for attunement. Larger ones may be required for eldritch machines or the creation of legendary items or artifacts.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Signet Ring, House Cannith" type="Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ITEM_SIGNET_RING_HOUSE_CANNITH">
		<description>
			<p>A signet ring of the dragonmarked House Cannith.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Signet Ring, House Deneith" type="Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ITEM_SIGNET_RING_HOUSE_DENEITH">
		<description>
			<p>A signet ring of the dragonmarked House Deneith.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Signet Ring, House Ghallanda" type="Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ITEM_SIGNET_RING_HOUSE_GHALLANDA">
		<description>
			<p>A signet ring of the dragonmarked House Ghallanda.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Signet Ring, House Jorasco" type="Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ITEM_SIGNET_RING_HOUSE_JORASCO">
		<description>
			<p>A signet ring of the dragonmarked House Jorasco.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Signet Ring, House Kundarak" type="Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ITEM_SIGNET_RING_HOUSE_KUNDARAK">
		<description>
			<p>A signet ring of the dragonmarked House Kundarak.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Signet Ring, House Lyrandar" type="Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ITEM_SIGNET_RING_HOUSE_LYRANDAR">
		<description>
			<p>A signet ring of the dragonmarked House Lyrandar.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Signet Ring, House Medani" type="Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ITEM_SIGNET_RING_HOUSE_MEDANI">
		<description>
			<p>A signet ring of the dragonmarked House Medani.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Signet Ring, House Orien" type="Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ITEM_SIGNET_RING_HOUSE_ORIEN">
		<description>
			<p>A signet ring of the dragonmarked House Orien.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Signet Ring, House Phiarlan" type="Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ITEM_SIGNET_RING_HOUSE_PHIARLAN">
		<description>
			<p>A signet ring of the dragonmarked House Phiarlan.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Signet Ring, House Sivis" type="Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ITEM_SIGNET_RING_HOUSE_SIVIS">
		<description>
			<p>A signet ring of the dragonmarked House Sivis.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Signet Ring, House Tharashk" type="Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ITEM_SIGNET_RING_HOUSE_THARASHK">
		<description>
			<p>A signet ring of the dragonmarked House Tharashk.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Signet Ring, House Thuranni" type="Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ITEM_SIGNET_RING_HOUSE_THURANNI">
		<description>
			<p>A signet ring of the dragonmarked House Thuranni.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Signet Ring, House Vadalis" type="Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ITEM_SIGNET_RING_HOUSE_VADALIS">
		<description>
			<p>A signet ring of the dragonmarked House Vadalis.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Arcane Propulsion Arm" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_ARCANE_PROPULSION_ARM">
		<description>
			<p>This prosthetic appendage was developed by artificers of House Cannith. To attune to this item, you must attach it to your arm at the wrist, elbow, or shoulder, at which point the prosthetic magically forms a copy of the appendage it’s replacing.</p>
			<p class="indent">While attached, the prosthetic provides these benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>The prosthetic is a fully capable part of your body.</li>
				<li>You can take an action to remove the prosthetic, and it removes itself if your attunement to it ends. It can’t be removed against your will.</li>
				<li>The prosthetic is a magic melee weapon with which you’re proficient. It deals 1d8 force damage on a hit and has the thrown property, with a normal range of 20 feet and a long range of 60 feet. When thrown, the prosthetic detaches and flies at the target of the attack, then immediately returns to you and reattaches.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a creature missing a hand or an arm">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Armblade" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMBLADE">
		<description>
			<p>An armblade is a magic weapon that attaches to your arm, becoming inseparable from you as long as you’re attuned to it. To attune to this item, you must hold it against your forearm for the entire attunement period.</p>
			<p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can retract the armblade into your forearm or extend it from there. While it is extended, you can use the weapon as if you were holding it, and you can’t use that hand for other purposes.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any one-handed melee weapon">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a warforged">true</set>
			<set name="weapon">(ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE||ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE),!ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_TWOHANDED</set>
			<set name="name-format">Armblade, {{parent}}</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Belashyrra’s Beholder Crown" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_BELASHYRRAS_BEHOLDER_CROWN">
		<description>
			<p>This symbiotic crown is carved from dark purple and mauve stone, with ten points like stalks set with gemstones resembling the eyestalks of a beholder. To attune to this item, you must wear it on your head for the entire attunement period, during which the crown’s hidden tendrils burrow into your scalp to bond with your skull.</p>
			<p class="indent">While wearing the crown, you can see normally in darkness, both magical and nonmagical, to a distance of 120 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Spells.</em></strong> The crown has 10 charges. While wearing it, you can use an action to expend some of its charges to cast one of the following spells from it (spell save DC 16): charm person (1 charge), disintegrate (6 charges), fear (3 charges), finger of death (7 charges), flesh to stone (6 charges), hold person (2 charges), ray of enfeeblement (2 charges), sleep (1 charge), slow (3 charges), telekinesis (5 charges).</p>
			<p class="indent">The crown regains 1d6 + 3 expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Symbiotic Nature.</em></strong> The crown can’t be removed from you while you’re attuned to it, and you can’t voluntarily end your attunement to it. If you’re targeted by a spell that ends a curse, your attunement to the crown ends, and it detaches from you.</p>
			<p class="indent">The daelkyr Belashyrra made these crowns. While on the same plane of existence as the crown, Belashyrra can see through its eyestalks.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="charges">10</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Cleansing Stone" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_CLEANSING_STONE">
		<description>
			<p>A cleansing stone is a sphere 1 foot in diameter, engraved with mystic sigils. When touching the stone, you can use an action to activate it and remove dirt and grime from your garments and your person.</p>
			<p class="indent">Such stones are often embedded in pedestals in public squares in Aundair or in high-end Ghallanda inns.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Docent" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_DOCENT">
		<description>
			<p>A docent is a small metal sphere, about 2 inches across, studded with dragonshards. To attune to a docent, you must embed the item somewhere on your body, such as your chest or your eye socket.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Sentience.</em></strong> A docent is a sentient item of any alignment with an Intelligence of 16, a Wisdom of 14, and a Charisma of 14. It perceives the world through your senses. It communicates telepathically with you and can speak, read, and understand any language it knows (see "Random Properties" below).</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Life Support.</em></strong> Whenever you end your turn with 0 hit points, the docent can make a Wisdom (Medicine) check with a +6 bonus. If this check succeeds, the docent stabilizes you.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Random Properties.</em></strong> A docent has the following properties:</p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Languages.</strong> The docent knows Common, Giant, and 1d4 additional languages chosen by the DM. If a docent knows fewer than six languages, it can learn a new language after it hears or reads the language through your senses.</li>
				<li><strong>Skills.</strong> The docent has a +7 bonus to one of the following skills (roll a d4): (1) Arcana, (2) History, (3) Investigation, or (4) Nature.</li>
				<li><strong>Spells.</strong> The docent knows one of the following spells and can cast it at will, requiring no components (roll a d6): (1-2) detect evil and good or (3-6) detect magic. The docent decides when to cast the spell.</li>
			</ul>
			<br/>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Personality.</em></strong> A docent is designed to advise and assist the warforged it’s attached to. One of the simple functions of a docent is to serve as a translator. The docent’s properties are under its control, and if you have a bad relationship with your docent, it might refuse to assist you.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a warforged">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Dyrrn’s Tentacle Whip" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_DYRRNS_TENTACLE_WHIP">
		<description>
			<p>This long, whip-like strand of tough muscle bears a sharp stinger at one end. To attune to this symbiotic weapon, you wrap the whip around your wrist for the entire attunement period, during which time the whip painfully embeds its tendrils into your arm.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic whip, but attack rolls made against aberrations with this weapon have disadvantage. A creature hit by this weapon takes an extra 1d6 psychic damage. When you roll a 20 on the d20 for an attack roll with this weapon, the target is stunned until the end of its next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can sheathe the whip by causing it to retract into your arm, or draw the whip out of your arm again.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Symbiotic Nature.</em></strong> The whip can’t be removed from you while you’re attuned to it, and you can’t voluntarily end your attunement to it. If you’re targeted by a spell that ends a curse, your attunement to the whip ends, and it detaches from you.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="type" addition="whip">Weapon</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="weapon">Whip</set>
			<set name="enhancement">2</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="name-format">Dyrrn’s Tentacle Whip, +2</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Earworm" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_EARWORM">
		<description>
			<p>To attune to this symbiont, you must hold it against the skin behind your ear for the entire attunement period, whereupon it burrows into your head and bonds to your skull. While the earworm is inside you, you can speak, read, and write Deep Speech.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Spells.</em></strong> The earworm has 4 charges. You can cast the following spells from it, expending the necessary number of charges (spell save DC 15): detect thoughts (2 charges) or dissonant whispers (1 charge). Each time you use the earworm to cast the detect thoughts spell, it sends the information gleaned to the nearest daelkyr, or to the next nearest earworm until it reaches a daelkyr.</p>
			<p class="indent">The earworm regains 1d4 expended charges daily at dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Symbiotic Nature.</em></strong> The earworm can’t be removed from you while you’re attuned to it, and you can’t voluntarily end your attunement to it. If you’re targeted by a spell that ends a curse, your attunement to the earworm ends, and it exits your body.</p>
			<!-- todo: add spell references -->
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="charges">4</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_DEEP_SPEECH" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Everbright Lantern" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_EVERBRIGHT_LANTERN">
		<description>
			<p>This bullseye lantern contains an Eberron dragonshard that sheds light comparable to that produced by a continual flame spell. An everbright lantern sheds light in a 120-foot cone; the closest 60 feet is bright light, and the farthest 60 feet is dim light.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Feather Token" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_FEATHER_TOKEN">
		<description>
			<p>This small metal disk is inscribed with the image of a feather. When you fall at least 20 feet while the token is on your person, you descend 60 feet per round and take no damage from falling. The token’s magic is expended after you land, whereupon the disk becomes nonmagical.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Finder’s Goggles" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_FINDERS_GOGGLES">
		<description>
			<p>The lenses of these garish goggles are carved from Siberys dragonshards. While wearing these lenses, you gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>When you make a Wisdom (Insight) check, you can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to the check.</li>
				<li>As an action, you can use the goggles to examine an object to identify the aura of the last creature that touched it. Make a Wisdom (Insight) check against a DC of 13 + the number of days since the last contact occurred. On a success, you learn the creature’s type and can immediately use the goggles to cast locate creature to find that creature. This property can’t be used again until the next dawn.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a creature with the Mark of Finding">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Glamerweave" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_GLAMERWEAVE_COMMON">
		<description>
			<p>Glamerweave is clothing imbued with harmless illusory magic. While wearing the common version of these clothes, you can use a bonus action to create a moving illusory pattern within the cloth.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Glamerweave" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_GLAMERWEAVE_UNCOMMON">
		<description>
			<p>Glamerweave is clothing imbued with harmless illusory magic. While wearing the common version of these clothes, you can use a bonus action to create a moving illusory pattern within the cloth.</p>
			<p class="indent">Uncommon glamerweave can have the pattern rise from the cloth. For example, a glamerweave gown might be wreathed in harmless, illusory flames, while a glamerweave hat might have illusory butterflies fluttering around it.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you make a Charisma (Performance) or Charisma (Persuasion) check while wearing the uncommon version of glamerweave, you can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to the check. Once you use this property, it can’t be used again until the next dawn.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>	
	<element name="Imbued Wood Focus" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_IMBUED_WOOD_FOCUS">
		<description>
			<p>An imbued wood focus is a rod, staff, or wand cut from a tree infused with extraplanar energy. If you’re a spellcaster, you can use this focus as a spellcasting focus.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you cast a damage-dealing spell using this item as your spellcasting focus, you gain a +1 bonus to one damage roll of the spell, provided the damage is of the type associated with the item’s wood. The types of wood and their associated damage types are listed in the Imbued Wood Focus table.</p>
			<p><strong>IMBUED WOOD FOCUS</strong></p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Wood</td><td>Damage Type</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>Fernian Ash</td><td>Fire</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Irian Rosewood</td><td>Radiant</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Kythrian Manchineel</td><td>Acid or poison</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Lamannian Oak</td><td>Lightning or thunder</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Mabaran Ebony</td><td>Necrotic</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Risian Pine</td><td>Cold</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Shavarran Birch</td><td>Force</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Xorian Wenge</td><td>Psychic</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Keycharm" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_KEYCHARM">
		<description>
			<p>This small stylized key plays a vital role in the work of House Kundarak. If you cast the alarm, arcane lock, or glyph of warding spell, you can tie the effect to the keycharm so that whoever holds it receives the notification from the alarm spell, bypasses the lock of the arcane Jock spell, or avoids triggering the glyph placed by the glyph of warding spell. In addition, the holder (who needn’t be attuned to the item) can take an action to end any one spell tied to it, provided the holder knows the command word you set for ending the tied spells. The keycharm can have up to three tied spells at one time.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a creature with the Mark of Warding">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Kyrzin’s Ooze" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_KYRZINS_OOZE">
		<description>
			<p>This opalescent, symbiotic goo comes sealed in a jar and slowly shifts and moves, as if endlessly exploring the jar’s interior. To attune to this item, you must first drink the contents of the jar, unlocking the following properties.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Resistant.</em></strong> While attuned to Kyrzin’s ooze, you have resistance to poison and acid damage, and you’re immune to the poisoned condition.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Amorphous.</em></strong> As an action, you can speak a command word and cause your body to assume the amorphous qualities of an ooze. For the next minute, you (along with any equipment you’re wearing or carrying) can move through a space as narrow as 1 inch wide without squeezing. Once you use this property, it can’t be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Acid Breath.</em></strong> As an action, you can exhale acid in a 30-foot line that is 5 feet wide. Each creature in that line must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw, taking 36 (8d8) acid damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. Once you use this property, it can’t be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Symbiotic Nature.</em></strong> The ooze can’t be removed from you while you’re attuned to it, and you can’t voluntarily end your attunement to it. If you’re targeted by a spell that ends a curse, your attunement to the ooze ends, as it seeps out of you.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you die while the ooze is inside you, it bursts out and engulfs you, turning your corpse into a black pudding allied with the daelkyr (see the Monster Manual for the black pudding’s stat block).</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_POISON" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_ACID" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Living Armor" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_ARMOR_LIVING_ARMOR">
		<description>
			<p>This hideous armor is formed from black chitin, beneath which veins pulse and red sinews glisten. To attune to this item, you must wear it for the entire attunement period, during which tendrils on the inside burrow into you.</p>
			<p class="indent">While wearing this armor, you have a +1 bonus to Armor Class, and you have resistance to the following damage types: necrotic, poison, and psychic.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Symbiotic Nature.</em></strong> The armor can’t be removed from you while you’re attuned to it, and you can’t voluntarily end your attunement to it. If you’re targeted by a spell that ends a curse, your attunement to the armor ends, and it detaches from you.</p>
			<p class="indent">The armor requires fresh blood be fed to it. Immediately after you finish any long rest, you must either feed half of your remaining Hit Dice to the armor (round up) or take 1 level of exhaustion.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Magic Armor</set>
			<set name="type" addition="any">Armor</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="armor">ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_LIGHT|ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_MEDIUM|ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_HEAVY</set>
			<set name="enhancement">1</set>
			<set name="name-format">Living {{parent}}, +1</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:armored:enhancement" value="1" bonus="enhancement" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_NECROTIC" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_POISON" />
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_PSYCHIC" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Living Gloves" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_LIVING_GLOVES">
		<description>
			<p>These symbiotic gloves-made of thin chitin and sinew-pulse with a life of their own. To attune to them, you must wear them for the entire attunement period, during which the gloves bond with your skin.</p>
			<p class="indent">While attuned to these gloves, you gain one of the following proficiencies (your choice when you attune to the gloves):</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Sleight of Hand</li>
				<li>Thieves’ tools</li>
				<li>One kind of artisan’s tools of your choice</li>
				<li>One kind of musical instrument of your choice</li>
			</ul>
			<p>When you make an ability check using the chosen proficiency, you add double your proficiency bonus to the check, instead of your normal proficiency bonus.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Symbiotic Nature.</em></strong> The gloves can’t be removed from you while you’re attuned to them, and you can’t voluntarily end your attunement to them. If you’re targeted by a spell that ends a curse, your attunement to the gloves ends, and they can be removed.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="slot">hands</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Proficiency, Living Gloves" supports="Artisan tools||Musical Instrument||Eberron Living Gloves Proficiency" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Orb of Shielding" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_ORB_OF_SHIELDING">
		<description>
			<p>An orb of shielding is a polished, spherical chunk of crystal or stone aligned to one of the planes of existence. If you’re a spellcaster, you can use this orb as a spellcasting focus.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you’re holding the orb when you take damage of the type associated with the orb’s material, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage by 1d4 (to a minimum of 0). The materials and their associated damage types are listed in the Orb of Shielding table.</p>
			<p><strong>ORB OF SHIELDING</strong></p>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Planar Material</td><td>Damage Type</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>Fernian basalt</td><td>Fire</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Irian quartz</td><td>Radiant</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Kythrian skarn</td><td>Acid and poison</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Lamannian flint</td><td>Lightning and thunder</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Mabaran obsidian</td><td>Necrotic</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Risian shale</td><td>Cold</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Shavarran chert</td><td>Force</td></tr>
				<tr><td>Xorian marble</td><td>Psychic</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Orb of Shielding, Fernian Basalt" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_ORB_OF_SHIELDING_FERNIAN_BASALT">
		<description>
			<p>An orb of shielding is a polished, spherical chunk of fernian basalt. If you’re a spellcaster, you can use this orb as a spellcasting focus.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you’re holding the orb when you take fire damage, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage by 1d4 (to a minimum of 0).</p>				
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Orb of Shielding, Irian Quartz" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_ORB_OF_SHIELDING_IRIAN_QUARTZ">
		<description>
			<p>An orb of shielding is a polished, spherical chunk of irian quartz. If you’re a spellcaster, you can use this orb as a spellcasting focus.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you’re holding the orb when you take radiant damage, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage by 1d4 (to a minimum of 0).</p>				
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Orb of Shielding, Kythrian Skarn" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_ORB_OF_SHIELDING_KYTHRIAN_SKARN">
		<description>
			<p>An orb of shielding is a polished, spherical chunk of kythrian skarn. If you’re a spellcaster, you can use this orb as a spellcasting focus.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you’re holding the orb when you take acid or poison damage, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage by 1d4 (to a minimum of 0).</p>				
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Orb of Shielding, Lamannian Flint" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_ORB_OF_SHIELDING_LAMANNIAN_FLINT">
		<description>
			<p>An orb of shielding is a polished, spherical chunk of lamannian flint. If you’re a spellcaster, you can use this orb as a spellcasting focus.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you’re holding the orb when you take lightning or thunder damage, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage by 1d4 (to a minimum of 0).</p>				
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Orb of Shielding, Mabaran Obsidian" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_ORB_OF_SHIELDING_MABARAN_OBSIDIAN">
		<description>
			<p>An orb of shielding is a polished, spherical chunk of mabaran obsidian. If you’re a spellcaster, you can use this orb as a spellcasting focus.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you’re holding the orb when you take necrotic damage, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage by 1d4 (to a minimum of 0).</p>				
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Orb of Shielding, Risian Shale" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_ORB_OF_SHIELDING_RISIAN_SHALE">
		<description>
			<p>An orb of shielding is a polished, spherical chunk of risian shale. If you’re a spellcaster, you can use this orb as a spellcasting focus.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you’re holding the orb when you take cold damage, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage by 1d4 (to a minimum of 0).</p>				
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Orb of Shielding, Shavarran Chert" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_ORB_OF_SHIELDING_SHAVARRAN_CHERT">
		<description>
			<p>An orb of shielding is a polished, spherical chunk of shavarran chert. If you’re a spellcaster, you can use this orb as a spellcasting focus.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you’re holding the orb when you take force damage, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage by 1d4 (to a minimum of 0).</p>				
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Orb of Shielding, Xorian Marble" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_ORB_OF_SHIELDING_XORIAN_MARBLE">
		<description>
			<p>An orb of shielding is a polished, spherical chunk of xorian marble. If you’re a spellcaster, you can use this orb as a spellcasting focus.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you’re holding the orb when you take psychic damage, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage by 1d4 (to a minimum of 0).</p>				
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Prosthetic Limb" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_PROSTHETIC_LIMB">
		<description>
			<p>This artificial limb replaces a hand, arm, foot, leg, or similar appendage that was lost or removed. While the prosthetic is attached and attuned to you, it functions identically to the body part it is replacing. You can detach or reattach it as an action, and it can’t be removed by anyone else.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you have multiple prosthetic limbs, they count as a single magic item with regard to the number of magic items you can attune to.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a creature missing some or all of a limb">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Scribe’s Pen" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_SCRIBES_PEN">
		<description>
			<p>You can use this pen to write on any surface. You decide whether the writing is visible or invisible, but the writing is always visible to a person with the Mark of Scribing.</p>
			<p class="indent">Any creature with the Mark of Scribing can use an action to touch the invisible writing, making it visible to all.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you use the pen to write on a creature that isn’t a construct, the writing fades after 7 days.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a creature with the Mark of Scribing">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shiftweave" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_SHIFTWEAVE">
		<description>
			<p>When a suit of shiftweave is created, up to five different outfits can be embedded into the cloth. While wearing the clothing, you can speak its command word as a bonus action to transform your outfit into your choice of one of the other designs contained within it. Regardless of its appearance, the outfit can’t be anything but clothing. Although it can duplicate the look of other magical clothing, it doesn’t gain their magical properties.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Speaking Stone" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_SPEAKING_STONE">
		<description>
			<p>The key to long-distance, virtually instantaneous communication across Khorvaire is House Sivis’s network of message stations. Each station contains at least one speaking stone, which is carved from a Siberys dragonshard and inscribed with arcane symbols that uniquely identify it. If you’re a gnome with the Mark of Scribing, you can touch the stone and use an action to cast the sending spell from it. The target is any other speaking stone whose location or unique sequence of symbols you know. A creature within 5 feet of the stone hears the message as if they were the target.</p>
			<p class="indent">In a Sivis message station, a gnome is always on duty by the speaking stone, listening for messages that might come in and transcribing them for delivery to their intended recipients.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Spellshard" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_SPELLSHARD">
		<description>
			<p>This polished Eberron dragonshard fits in the hand and stores information similar to a book. The shard can hold the equivalent of one book that’s no more than 320 pages long. A shard can be created blank or already filled with information. When the shard is created, the creator can set a passphrase that must be spoken to access the information stored within.</p>
			<p class="indent">While holding the shard, you can use an action to open your mind to the shard, seeing its content in your mind. On subsequent rounds, reading the text or scribing new text on blank "pages" in the shard requires concentration (as if concentrating on a spell) and takes the same amount of time it takes you to read and write normally. Thinking of a particular phrase or topic draws you to the first section in the shard that addresses it.</p>
			<p class="indent">A wizard can use a spellshard as a spellbook, with the usual cost in gold and time to "scribe" a spell into the shard.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ventilating Lungs" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_VENTILATING_LUNGS">
		<description>
			<p>These metallic nodules were created in response to the poisonous gases used on the battlefields of the Last War. When you attune to these lungs, they replace the lungs in your chest, which disappear. The lungs allow you to breathe normally, even in an antimagic field, and their breathing function can’t be suppressed by magic.</p>
			<p class="indent">Outside an antimagic field or any other effect that suppresses magic, these lungs allow you to breathe normally in any environment (including a vacuum), and you have advantage on saving throws against harmful gases such as those created by a cloudkill spell, a stinking cloud spell, inhaled poisons, and gaseous breath weapons .</p>
			<p class="indent">As an action, you can use these lungs to exhale a gust of wind, as if you had cast the gust of wind spell (spell save DC 15) with no components. This property of the lungs can’t be used again until the next dawn.</p>
			<p class="indent">If your attunement to the lungs ends, your original lungs reappear.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="attunement">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Wand Sheath" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_WAND_SHEATH">
		<description>
			<p>A wand sheath clamps onto your arm and imparts the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>The wand sheath can’t be removed from you while you’re attuned to it.</li>
				<li>You can insert a wand into the sheath as an action. The sheath can hold only one wand at a time .</li>
				<li>You can retract or extend a wand from the sheath as a bonus action. While the wand is extended, you can use it as if you were holding it, but your hand remains free.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">If a sheathed wand requires attunement, you must attune to the wand before you can use it. However, the wand sheath and the attached wand count as a single magic item with regard to the number of magic items you can attune to. If you remove the wand from the sheath, your attunement to the wand ends.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="slot">arms</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a warforged">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Wheel of Wind and Water" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_WHEEL_OF_WIND_AND_WATER">
		<description>
			<p>When mounted at the helm of an elemental galleon or airship, this wheel allows a creature that possesses the Mark of Storm to telepathically control the elemental bound inside the vessel.</p>
			<p class="indent">If a wheel of wind and water is mounted on a mundane sailing ship, a creature with the Mark of Storm who is using the wheel can create an area of ideal conditions around the vessel, increasing its speed by 5 miles per hour.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Double-Bladed Scimitar" type="Weapon" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_WEAPON_DOUBLE_BLADED_SCIMITAR">
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_SLASHING, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_TWOHANDED, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_SPECIAL, ID_WOTC_ERLW_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_SPECIAL_DOUBLE_BLADED_SCIMITAR</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The double-bladed scimitar is the signature weapon of Valenar elves. A haft of fine wood supports a long, curving blade on either end. Forged with techniques honed over centuries, these blades are strong, sharp, and remarkably light.</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_ERLW_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_SPECIAL_DOUBLE_BLADED_SCIMITAR" />
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">100</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="6">6 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">twohand</set>
			<set name="damage" type="slashing">2d4</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_WOTC_ERLW_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_DOUBLE_BLADED_SCIMITAR</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Special (Double-Bladed Scimitar)" type="Weapon Property" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_SPECIAL_DOUBLE_BLADED_SCIMITAR">
		<description>
			<p>If you attack with a double-bladed scimitar as part of the Attack action on your turn, you can use a bonus action immediately after to make a melee attack with it. This attack deals 1d4 slashing damage on a hit, instead of 2d4.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Weapon Proficiency (Double-Bladed Scimitar)" type="Proficiency" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_DOUBLE_BLADED_SCIMITAR">
		<supports>Weapon, Martial, Melee, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_SLASHING, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_TWOHANDED, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_SPECIAL, ID_WOTC_ERLW_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_SPECIAL_DOUBLE_BLADED_SCIMITAR</supports>
	</element>
	<element name="Kensei Weapon (Double-Bladed Scimitar)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_KENSEI_WEAPON_DOUBLE_BLADED_SCIMITAR">
		<supports>Kensei Weapon, Melee</supports>
        <description>
			<p>You gain proficiency with the Double-Bladed Scimitar if you don’t already have it, and it is a monk weapon for you.</p>
        </description>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_DOUBLE_BLADED_SCIMITAR" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Alchemist Flask" type="Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_ITEM_ALCHEMIST_FLASK">
		<description>
			<p>An empty flask for experimental elixirs.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">artificer,alchemist,experimental elixir</set>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Experimental Elixir, Healing" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_EXPERIMENTAL_ELIXIR_HEALING">
		<description>
			<p>The drinker regains a number of hit points equal to 2d4 + the alchemist’s Intelligence modifier.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">artificer,alchemist,experimental elixir</set>
			<set name="category">Potions</set>
			<set name="type" addition="alchemist">Elixir</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Experimental Elixir, Swiftness" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_EXPERIMENTAL_ELIXIR_SWIFTNESS">
		<description>
			<p>The drinker’s walking speed increases by 10 feet for 1 hour.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">artificer,alchemist,experimental elixir</set>
			<set name="category">Potions</set>
			<set name="type" addition="alchemist">Elixir</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Experimental Elixir, Resilience" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_EXPERIMENTAL_ELIXIR_RESILIENCE">
		<description>
			<p>The drinker gains a +1 bonus to AC for 10 minutes.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">artificer,alchemist,experimental elixir</set>
			<set name="category">Potions</set>
			<set name="type" addition="alchemist">Elixir</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Experimental Elixir, Boldness" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_EXPERIMENTAL_ELIXIR_BOLDNESS">
		<description>
			<p>The drinker can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to every attack roll and saving throw they make for the next minute.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">artificer,alchemist,experimental elixir</set>
			<set name="category">Potions</set>
			<set name="type" addition="alchemist">Elixir</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Experimental Elixir, Flight" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_EXPERIMENTAL_ELIXIR_FLIGHT">
		<description>
			<p>The drinker gains a flying speed of 10 feet for 10 minutes.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">artificer,alchemist,experimental elixir</set>
			<set name="category">Potions</set>
			<set name="type" addition="alchemist">Elixir</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Experimental Elixir, Transformation" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_EXPERIMENTAL_ELIXIR_TRANSFORMATION">
		<description>
			<p>The drinker’s body is transformed as if by the alter self spell. The drinker determines the transformation caused by the spell, the effects of which last for 10 minutes.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">artificer,alchemist,experimental elixir</set>
			<set name="category">Potions</set>
			<set name="type" addition="alchemist">Elixir</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<element name="Arcane Firearm, Wand" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_ARCANE_FIREARM_WAND">
		<description>
			<p>You can use your arcane firearm as a spellcasting focus for your artificer spells. When you cast an artificer spell through the firearm, roll a d8, and you gain a bonus to one of the spell’s damage rolls equal to the number rolled.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">artificer,artillerist</set>
			<set name="category">Wands</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="1">1 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="type" addition="artificer">Wand</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Arcane Firearm, Staff" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_ARCANE_FIREARM_STAFF">
		<description>
			<p>You can use your arcane firearm as a spellcasting focus for your artificer spells. When you cast an artificer spell through the firearm, roll a d8, and you gain a bonus to one of the spell’s damage rolls equal to the number rolled.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">artificer,artillerist</set>
			<set name="category">Staffs</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="weapon">Quarterstaff</set>
			<set name="type" addition="artificer">Staff</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Arcane Firearm, Rod" type="Magic Item" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_MAGIC_ITEM_ARCANE_FIREARM_ROD">
		<description>
			<p>You can use your arcane firearm as a spellcasting focus for your artificer spells. When you cast an artificer spell through the firearm, roll a d8, and you gain a bonus to one of the spell’s damage rolls equal to the number rolled.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">artificer,artillerist</set>
			<set name="category">Rods</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="type" addition="artificer">Rod</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	
	<append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_MELEE_WEAPONS">
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_DOUBLE_BLADED_SCIMITAR" />
		</rules>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SLEIGHTOFHAND">
		<supports>Eberron Living Gloves Proficiency</supports>>
	</append>
	<append id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_THIEVES_TOOLS">
		<supports>Eberron Living Gloves Proficiency</supports>>
	</append>
</elements>