<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Lizardfolk</name>
		<description></description>
		<author url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.1.2">
			<file name="race-lizardfolk.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/supplements/volos-guide-to-monsters/race-lizardfolk.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Lizardfolk" type="Race" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACE_LIZARDFOLK">
		<description>
			<p class="flavor">Only a fool looks at the lizardfolk and sees nothing more than scaly humanoids. Their physical shape notwithstanding, lizardfolk have more in common with iguanas or dragons than they do with humans, dwarves, or elves. Lizardfolk possess an alien and inscrutable mindset, their desires and thoughts driven by a different set of basic principles than those of warm-blooded creatures. Their dismal swamp homes might lie hundreds of miles from the nearest human settlement, but the gap between their way of thinking and that of the smooth-skins is far greater.</p>
			<p class="indent flavor">Despite their alien outlook, some lizardfolk make an effort to understand and, in their own manner, befriend people of other races. Such lizardfolk make faithful and skilled allies.</p>
			<h4>ALIEN MINDS</h4>
			<p>The lizardfolk's reptilian nature comes through not only in their appearance, but also in how they think and act. Lizardfolk experience a more limited emotional life than other humanoids. Like most reptiles, their feelings largely revolve around fear, aggression, and pleasure.</p>
			<p class="indent">Lizardfolk experience most feelings as detached descriptions of creatures and situations. For example, humans confronted by an angry troll experience fear on a basic level. Their limbs shake, their thinking becomes panicked and jumbled, and they react by instinct. The emotion of fear takes hold and controls their actions. In contrast, lizardfolk see emotions as traits assigned to other creatures, objects, and situations. A lizardfolk doesn't think, "I'm scared." Instead, aggressive, stronger creatures register to the lizardfolk as fearsome beings to be avoided if possible. If such creatures attack, lizardfolk flee, fighting only if cornered. Lizardfolk aren't scared of a troll; instead, they understand that a troll is a fearsome, dangerous creature and react accordingly.</p>
			<p class="indent">Lizardfolk never become angry in the way others do, but they act with aggression toward creatures that they could defeat in a fight and that can't be dealt with in some other manner. They are aggressive toward prey they want to eat, creatures that want to harm them, and so on.</p>
			<p class="indent">Pleasurable people and things make life easier for lizardfolk. Pleasurable things should be preserved and protected, sometimes at the cost of the lizardfolk's own safety. The most pleasurable creatures and things are ones that allow lizardfolk to assess more situations as benign rather than fearsome.</p>
			<h4>COLD AND CALCULATING</h4>
			<p>Most humanoids describe cold-blooded people as lacking in emotion and empathy. The same label serves as an apt depiction of lizardfolk.</p>
			<p class="indent">Lacking any internal emotional reactions, lizardfolk behave in a distant manner. They don't mourn fallen comrades or rage against their enemies. They simply observe and react as a situation warrants.</p>
			<p class="indent">Lizardfolk lack meaningful emotional ties to the past. They assess situations based on their current and future utility and importance. Nowhere does this come through as strongly as when lizardfolk deal with the dead. To a lizardfolk, a comrade who dies becomes a potential source of food. That companion might have once been a warrior or hunter, but now the body is just freshly killed meat.</p>
			<p class="indent">A lizard folk who lives among other humanoids can, over time, learn to respect other creatures' emotions. The lizardfolk doesn't share those feelings, but instead assesses them in the same clinical manner. Yes, the fallen dwarf might be most useful as a meal, but hacking the body into steaks provokes aggression in the other humanoids and makes them less helpful in battle.</p>
			<h4>UTILITY AND SURVIVAL</h4>
			<p>The lizardfolk mindset might seem unnecessarily cruel, but it helps them survive in a hostile environment. The swamps they inhabit are filled with a staggering variety of threats. Lizardfolk focus on survival above all, without sentiment.</p>
			<p class="indent">Lizardfolk assess everyone and everything in terms of utility. Art and beauty have little meaning for them. A sharp sword serves a useful and good purpose, while a dull sword is a dead weight without a whetstone.</p>
			<p class="indent">Lizardfolk see little need to plan more than a season or so into the future. This approach allows them to maintain their current level of influence in the world, but it limits their growth. Lizardfolk have no interest in developing writing, making long-term plans, or cultivating other methods to progress beyond their simpie existence as hunters and gatherers.</p>
			<h4>HAPLESS SOFT ONES</h4>
			<p>At their core, lizardfolk view other humanoids with an indifference verging on pity. Born into the world lacking stout scales and sharp teeth, it's a wonder they have managed to survive for so long. The typical human would barely make it through a day in the swamps.</p>
			<p class="indent">Still, if other creatures prove useful to lizardfolk, those creatures can trigger a prote,ctive response made all the stronger by their apparent weakness. The lizardfolk assess such beings as hatchlings, young ones incapable of protecting themselves but who might prove useful in the future if they receive care.</p>
			<h4>LIZARDFOLK PERSONALITY</h4>
			<p>You can use the Lizardfolk Quirks table to determine a personality quirk for a lizardfolk character or to inspire a unique mannerism.</p>
			<h5>LIZARDFOLK QUIRKS</h5>
			<table>
			<thead>
				<tr><td>d8</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
			</thead>
			<tr><td>1</td><td>You hate waste and see no reason not to scavenge fallen enemies. Fingers are tasty and portable!</td></tr>
			<tr><td>2</td><td>You sleep best while mostly submerged in water.</td></tr>
			<tr><td>3</td><td>Money is meaningless to you.</td></tr>
			<tr><td>4</td><td>You think there are only two species of humanoid: lizardfolk and meat.</td></tr>
			<tr><td>5</td><td>You have learned to laugh. You use this talent in response to all emotional situations, to better fit in with your comrades.</td></tr>
			<tr><td>6</td><td>You still don't understand how metaphors work. That doesn't stop you from using them at every opportunity.</td></tr>
			<tr><td>7</td><td>You appreciate the soft humanoids who realize they need chain mail and swords to match the gifts you were born with.</td></tr>
			<tr><td>8</td><td>You enjoy eating your food while it's still wriggling.</td></tr>
			</table>
			<h4>LIZARDFOLK NAMES</h4>
			<p>Lizardfolk take their names from the Draconic language. They use simple descriptives granted by the tribe based on an individual's notable deeds or actions. For example, Garurt translates as "axe," a name given to a lizardfolk warrior who defeated an orc and claimed his foe's weapon. A lizardfolk who likes to hide in a stand of reeds before ambushing an animal might be called Achuak, which means "green" to describe how she blends into the foliage.</p>
			<p class="indent">Lizardfolk make no distinction between male and female in their naming conventions. Each example name includes its translation in parenthesis.</p>
			<p>
			<b>Lizardfolk Names: </b>Achuak (green), Aryte (war), Baeshra (animal), Darastrix (dragon), Garurt (axe), Irhtos (secret), Jhank (hammer), Kepesk (storm), Kethend (gem), Korth (danger), Kosj (small), Kothar (demon), Litrix (armor), Mirik (song), Othokent (smart), Sauriv (eye), Throden (many), Thurkear (night), Usk (iron), Valignat (burn), Vargach (battle), Verthica (mountain), Vutha (black), Vyth (steel)
			</p>
			<h4>LIZARDFOLK TRAITS</h4>
			<p>Your lizardfolk character has the following racial traits.</p>
			<p>
			<span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span>Your Constitution score increases by 2, and your Wisdom score increases by 1.
			<br/>
			<span class="feature">Age.</span>Lizardfolk reach maturity arqund age 14 and rarely live longer than 60 years.
			<br/>
			<span class="feature">Alignment.</span>Most lizardfolk are neutral. They see the world as a place of predators and prey, where life and death are natural processes. They wish only to survive, and prefer to leave other creatures to their own devices.
			<br/>
			<span class="feature">Size.</span>Lizardfolk are a little bulkier and taller than humans, and their colorful frills make them appear even larger. Your size is Medium.
			<br/>
			<span class="feature">Speed.</span>Your base walking speed is 30 feet, and you have a swimming speed of 30 feet.
			<br/>
			<span class="feature">Bite.</span>Your fanged maw is a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with it, you deal piercing damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike.
			<br/>
			<span class="feature">Cunning Artisan.</span>As part of a short rest, you can harvest bone and hide from a slain beast, construct, dragon, monstrosity, or plant creature of size Small or larger to create one of the following items: a shield, a club, a javelin, or 1d4 darts or blowgun needles. To use this trait, you need a blade, such as a dagger, or appropriate artisan's tools, such as leatherworker's tools.
			<br/>
			<span class="feature">Hold Breath.</span>You can hold your breath for up to 15 minutes at a time.
			<br/>
			<span class="feature">Hunter's Lore.</span>You gain proficiency with two of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, Nature, Perception, Stealth, and Survival.
			<br/>
			<span class="feature">Natural Armor.</span>You have tough, scaly skin. When you aren't wearing armor, your AC is 13 + your Dexterity modifier. You can use your natural armor to determine your AC if the armor you wear would leave you with a lower AC. A shield's benefits apply as normal while you use your natural armor.
			<br/>
			<span class="feature">Hungry Jaws.</span>In battle, you can throw yourself into a vicious feeding frenzy. As a bonus action, you can make a special attack with your bite. If the attack hits, it deals its normal damage, and you gain temporary hit points (minimum of 1) equal to your Constitution modifier, and you can't use this trait again until you finish a short or long rest.
			<br/>
			<span class="feature">Languages.</span>You can speak, read, and write Common and Draconic.
			<br/>
			</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<setters>
			<set name="names" type="custom">Achuak, Aryte, Baeshra, Darastrix, Garurt, Irhtos, Jhank, Kepesk, Kethend, Korth, Kosj, Kothar, Litrix, Mirik, Othokent, Sauriv, Throden, Thurkear, Usk, Valignat, Vargach, Verthica, Vutha, Vyth</set>
			<set name="names-format">{{custom}}</set>
			<set name="height" modifier="2d12">4'8"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="2d6">110 lb.</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="constitution" value="2" />
			<stat name="wisdom" value="1" />
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="innate speed:swim" value="30" bonus="base"/>
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_DRACONIC" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_BITE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_CUNNING_ARTISAN" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_HOLD_BREATH" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_HUNTERS_LORE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_NATURAL_ARMOR" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_HUNGRY_JAWS" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Bite" type="Racial Trait" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_BITE">
		<description>
			<p>Your fanged maw is a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with it, you deal piercing damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your fanged maw is a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. 1d6+{{lizardfolk bite:damage}} piercing damage.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="lizardfolk bite:damage" value="strength:modifier" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Cunning Artisan" type="Racial Trait" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_CUNNING_ARTISAN">
		<description>
			<p>As part of a short rest, you can harvest bone and hide from a slain beast, construct, dragon, monstrosity, or plant creature of size Small or larger to create one of the following items: a shield, a club, a javelin, or 1d4 darts or blowgun needles. To use this trait, you need a blade, such as a dagger, or appropriate artisan's tools, such as leatherworker's tools.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>As part of a short rest, you can harvest bone and hide from a slain beast, construct, dragon, monstrosity, or plant creature.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Hold Breath" type="Racial Trait" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_HOLD_BREATH">
		<description>
			<p>You can hold your breath for up to 15 minutes at a time.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can hold your breath for up to 15 minutes at a time.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Hunter's Lore" type="Racial Trait" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_HUNTERS_LORE">
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency with two of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, Nature, Perception, Stealth, and Survival.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You gain proficiency with two of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, Nature, Perception, Stealth, and Survival.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Hunter's Lore" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Natural Armor" type="Racial Trait" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_NATURAL_ARMOR">
		<description>
			<p>You have tough, scaly skin. When you aren't wearing armor, your AC is 13 + your Dexterity modifier. You can use your natural armor to determine your AC if the armor you wear would leave you with a lower AC. A shield's benefits apply as normal while you use your natural armor.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have tough, scaly skin. When you aren't wearing armor, your AC is {{ac:natural armor lizardfolk}}.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:natural armor lizardfolk:base" value="13" />
			<stat name="ac:natural armor lizardfolk:dexterity" value="dexterity:modifier" />
			<stat name="ac:natural armor lizardfolk" value="ac:natural armor lizardfolk:base" />
			<stat name="ac:natural armor lizardfolk" value="ac:natural armor lizardfolk:dexterity" />
			<stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:natural armor lizardfolk" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none]" alt="Natural Armor (Lizardfolk)" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Hungry Jaws" type="Racial Trait" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_HUNGRY_JAWS">
		<description>
			<p>In battle, you can throw yourself into a vicious feeding frenzy. As a bonus action, you can make a special attack with your bite. If the attack hits, it deals its normal damage, and you gain temporary hit points (minimum of 1) equal to your Constitution modifier, and you can't use this trait again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>As a bonus action, you can make a special attack with your bite. If the attack hits, it deals its normal damage, and you gain {{hungry jaws:hp:temp}} temporary hit points. 1/ short rest.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="hungry jaws:hp:temp" value="1" bonus="hungry jaws" />
			<stat name="hungry jaws:hp:temp" value="constitution:modifier" bonus="hungry jaws" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>
