<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Triton</name>
		<update version="0.1.1">
			<file name="race-triton.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/supplements/volos-guide-to-monsters/race-triton.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Triton" type="Race" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACE_TRITON">
		<description>
			<p class="flavor">Tritons guard the ocean depths, building small settlements beside deep trenches, portals to the elemental planes, and other dangerous spots far from the eyes of land-bound folk. Long-established guardians of the deep ocean floor, in recent years the noble tritons have become increasingly active in the world above.</p>
			<h4>AQUATIC CRUSADERS</h4>
			<p>Centuries ago, tritons entered the world in response to the growing threat of evil elementals. Tritons waged many wars against their enemies on the Plane of Water, driving them into the Darkened Depths where they escaped into the crushing pressure and utter darkness. In time, the tritons noticed that their ancient elemental foes had grown quiet. Expeditions to the depths revealed that krakens, sahuagin, and far worse foes had fled the Plane of Water for the Material Plane.</p>
			<p class="indent">The tritons, driven by a sense of duty and responsibility, would not allow their foes to escape so easily. A great conclave of tritons chose volunteers skilled in weapons and magic as part of an expeditionary force to enter the Material Plane and seek out their enemies.</p>
			<p class="indent">Those tritons spread across the world's oceans and established protectorates to watch over deep sea trenches, portals, undersea caves, and other locations where their enemies might lurk. They defeated their foes when they found them and drove the rest into hiding.</p>
			<p class="indent">With their foes banished to the deepest reaches of the sea, tritons settled in to watch for any sign of their return. Over time, the tritons extended their stewardship over the sea floor from their initial settlements and built outposts to create trade with other races. Despite this expansion, few folk know of them. Their settlements are so remote even merfolk and sea elves rarely encounter them.</p>
			<h4>HAUGHTY NOBLES</h4>
			<p>As a result of their isolation and limited understanding of the Material Plane, tritons can come across as haughty and arrogant. They see themselves as caretakers of the sea, and they expect other creatures to pay them deep respect, if not complete deference. This attitude might grate on others, but it arises from a seed of truth. Few know of the tritons' great victories over dreadful undersea threats. The tritons make little allowance for such ignorance and are delighted to expound upon the great debt others owe them.</p>
			<p class="indent">Tritons also have a tendency to emerge from their isolation under the assumption that other folk will welcome them as respected allies and mentors. Again, distance drives much of this attitude. The tritons' limited view of the world leaves them ignorant of the kingdoms, wars, and other struggles of the surface world. Tritons readily see such concerns as minor events, a sideshow to the tritons' role as the world's true protectors.</p>
			<h4>STAUNCH CHAMPIONS</h4>
			<p>Despite their off-putting manners, tritons are benevolent creatures at heart, convinced that other civilized races deserve their protection. Their attitude might grate, but when pirate fleets prowl the waves or a kraken awakens from its slumber, they are among the first to take up arms to protect others.</p>
			<p class="indent">Tritons readily sacrifice themselves for the common good. They will fight and die for humans, merfolk, and other creatures without question. Their self-absorbed nature makes them overlook the history of other creatures, but they also endure a sense of guilt over allowing the evils of the Plane of Water to enter the Material Plane and threaten its inhabitants. The tritons believe they owe a debt of honor to the world, and they will fight and die to pay it.</p>
			<p class="indent">At times their fervor and ignorance of the world can lead them astray. Tritons encountering other creatures for the first time can underestimate them, leaving the tritons vulnerable to deception. With their strong martial tradition, tritons can sometimes be too eager to leap into a fight.</p>
			<h4>STRANGERS TO THE SURFACE</h4>
			<p>Given their isolation, most tritons have never been to the surface world. They struggle with the idea that they can't easily move up and down out of water, and the changing of the seasons mystifies them.</p>
			<p class="indent">Tritons also find the variety of social institutions, kingdoms, and other customs bewildering. For all their proud culture, they remain innocent of the surface world. The typical triton protectorate is tightly regimented, organized, and unified around a common cause. A triton on the surface becomes easily confused by the bewildering array of alliances, rivalries, and petty grievances that prevent the surface folk from truly unifying.</p>
			<p class="indent">At its worst, a triton's arrogance compounds the tendency for the triton. not to understand the ways of the surface world. It's easy for a triton to blame baffling social practices on what the triton perceives as the barbarism, weakness, or cowardice of surface folk.</p>
			<h4>TRITON PERSONALITY</h4>
			<p>Far from flawless, these champions of good mean well, but they are easily frustrated by others. You can select, roll, or adapt a triton-specific quirk from the Triton Quirks table. Use the quirk to inform how you portray your character.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">TRITON QUIRKS</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d6</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>You phrase requests as orders that you expect to be obeyed.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>You are quick to boast of the greatness of your civilization.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>You learned an antiquated version of Common and drop "thee" and "thou" into your speech.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>You assume that people are telling you the truth about local customs and expectations.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>The surface world is a wondrous place, and you catalog all its details in a journal.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>You mistakenly assume that surface folk know about and are impressed by your people's history.</td></tr>
			</table>
			<h4>TRITON NAMES</h4>
			<p>Most triton names have two or three syllables. Male names typically end with a vowel and the letters, and female names traditionally end with an n. Tritons use their home protectorate as a surname, with the name formed by adding a vowel followed by a "th" to the end of the protectorate's name.</p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Female Triton Names:</strong> Aryn, Belthyn, Duthyn, Feloren, Otanyn, Shalryn, Vlaryn, Wolyn</li>
				<li><strong>Male Triton Names:</strong> Corus, Delnis, Jhimas, Keros, Molos, Nalos, Vodos, Zunis</li>
				<li><strong>Triton Surnames:</strong> Ahlorsath, Pumanath, Vuuvaxath</li>
			</ul>
			<h4>TRITON TRAITS</h4>
			<p>Your triton character has the following racial traits.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Strength, Constitution, and Charisma scores each increase by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em></strong> Tritons reach maturity around age 15 and can live up to 200 years.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Alignment.</em></strong> Tritons tend toward lawful good. As guardians of the darkest reaches of the sea, their culture pushes them toward order and benevolence.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> Tritons are slightly sli'orter than humans, averaging about 5 feet tall. Your size is Medium.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your base walking speed is 30 feet, and you have a swimming speed of 30 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Darkvision.</em></strong> You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Amphibious.</em></strong> You can breathe air and water.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Control Air and Water.</em></strong> A child of the sea, you can call on the magic of elemental air and water. You can cast fog cloud with this trait. Starting at 3rd level, you can cast gust of wind with it, and starting at 5th level, you can also cast wall of water with it (see the spell in the sidebar). Once you cast a spell with this trait, you can’t cast that spell with it again until you finish a long rest. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Emissary of the Sea.</em></strong> Aquatic beasts have an extraordinary affinity with your people. You can communicate simple ideas with beasts that can breathe water. They can understand the meaning of your words, though you have no special ability to understand them in return.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Guardians of the Depths.</em></strong> Adapted to even the most extreme ocean depths, you have resistance to cold damage, and you ignore any of the drawbacks caused by a deep, underwater environment.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> You can speak, read, and write Common and Primordial.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<setters>
			<set name="names" type="male">Aryn, Belthyn, Duthyn, Feloren, Otanyn, Shalryn, Vlaryn, Wolyn</set>
			<set name="names" type="female">Corus, Delnis, Jhimas, Keros, Molos, Nalos, Vodos, Zunis</set>
			<set name="names" type="surname">Ahlorsath, Pumanath, Vuuvaxath</set>
			<set name="names-format">{{name}} {{surname}}</set>
			<set name="height" modifier="2d4">4'4"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="2d4">100 lb.</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="strength" value="1"/>
			<stat name="constitution" value="1"/>
			<stat name="charisma" value="1"/>
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="innate speed:swim" value="30" bonus="base" />
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_PRIMORDIAL" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_TRITON_AMPHIBIOUS" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_TRITON_CONTROL_AIR_AND_WATER" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_TRITON_EMISSARY_OF_THE_SEA" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_TRITON_GUARDIANS_OF_THE_DEPTHS" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Amphibious" type="Racial Trait" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_TRITON_AMPHIBIOUS">
		<description>
			<p>You can breathe air and water.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can breathe air and water.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Control Air and Water" type="Racial Trait" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_TRITON_CONTROL_AIR_AND_WATER">
		<description>
			<p>A child of the sea, you can call on the magic of elemental air and water. You can cast fog cloud with this trait. Starting at 3rd level, you can cast gust of wind with it, and starting at 5th level, you can also cast wall of water with it (see the spell in the sidebar). Once you cast a spell with this trait, you can’t cast that spell with it again until you finish a long rest. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>You can cast fog cloud. (Charisma)</description>
			<description level="3">You can cast fog cloud and gust of wind. (Charisma)</description>
			<description level="5">You can cast fog cloud, gust of wind, and wall of water. (Charisma)</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FOG_CLOUD" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUST_OF_WIND" level="3" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_VGTM_SPELL_WALL_OF_WATER" level="5" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Emissary of the Sea" type="Racial Trait" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_TRITON_EMISSARY_OF_THE_SEA">
		<description>
			<p>Aquatic beasts have an extraordinary affinity with your people. You can communicate simple ideas with beasts that can breathe water. They can understand the meaning of your words, though you have no special ability to understand them in return.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can communicate simple ideas with beasts that can breathe water. They can understand the meaning of your words, though you have no special ability to understand them in return.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Guardians of the Depths" type="Racial Trait" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_TRITON_GUARDIANS_OF_THE_DEPTHS">
		<description>
			<p>Adapted to even the most extreme ocean depths, you have resistance to cold damage, and you ignore any of the drawbacks caused by a deep, underwater environment.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have resistance to cold damage, and you ignore any of the drawbacks caused by a deep, underwater environment.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_COLD" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Wall of Water" type="Spell" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_VGTM_SPELL_WALL_OF_WATER">
		<supports>Triton</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You conjure up a wall of water on the ground at a point you can see within range. You can make the wall up to 30 feet long, 10 feet high, and 1 foot thick, or you can make a ringed wait up to 20 feet in diameter, 20 feet high, and 1 foot thick. The wall vanishes when the spell ends. The wall's space is difficult terrain.</p>
			<p class="indent">Any ranged weapon attack that enters the wall's space has disadvantage on the attack roll, and fire damage is halved if the fire effect passes through the wall to reach its target. Spells that deal cold damage that pass through the wall cause the area of the wan they pass through to freeze solid (at least a 5-foot square section is frozen), Each 5-foot square frozen section has AC 5 and 15 hit points. Reducing a frozen section to 0 hit points destroys it. When a section is destroyed, the wall's water doesn't fill it.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="level">3</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 10 minutes</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a drop of water</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>