<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Ancestral Guardian</name>
		<update version="0.0.5">
			<file name="barbarian-ancestralguardian.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/supplements/xanathars-guide-to-everything/archetypes/barbarian-ancestralguardian.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	
	<element name="Path of the Ancestral Guardian" type="Archetype" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_PATH_OF_THE_ANCESTRAL_GUARDIAN">
		<supports>Primal Path</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Some barbarians hail from cultures that revere their ancestors. These tribes teach that the warriors of the past linger in the world as mighty spirits, who can guide and protect the living. When a barbarian who follows this path rages, the barbarian contacts the spirit world and calls on these guardian spirits for aid.</p>
			<p class="indent">Barbarians who draw on their ancestral guardians can better fight to protect their tribes and their allies. In order to cement ties to their ancestral guardians, barbarians who follow this path cover themselves in elaborate tattoos that celebrate their ancestors’ deeds. These tattoos tell sagas of victories against terrible monsters and other fearsome rivals.</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANCESTRAL_GUARDIAN_ANCESTRAL_PROTECTORS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANCESTRAL_GUARDIAN_SPIRIT_SHIELD" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANCESTRAL_GUARDIAN_CONSULT_THE_SPIRITS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANCESTRAL_GUARDIAN_VENGEFUL_ANCESTORS" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="true">
			<description>Some barbarians hail from cultures that revere their ancestors.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANCESTRAL_GUARDIAN_ANCESTRAL_PROTECTORS" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANCESTRAL_GUARDIAN_SPIRIT_SHIELD" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANCESTRAL_GUARDIAN_CONSULT_THE_SPIRITS" level="10" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANCESTRAL_GUARDIAN_VENGEFUL_ANCESTORS" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Ancestral Protectors" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANCESTRAL_GUARDIAN_ANCESTRAL_PROTECTORS">
		<description>
			<p>Starting when you choose this path at 3rd level, spectral warriors appear when you enter your rage. While you’re raging, the first creature you hit with an attack on your turn becomes the target of the warriors, which hinder its attacks. Until the start of your next turn, that target has disadvantage on any attack roll that isn’t against you, and when the target hits a creature other than you with an attack, that creature has resistance to the damage dealt by the attack. The effect on the target ends early if your rage ends.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When raging, the first target you hit with an attack on your turn becomes the target of spectral warriors, Until the start of your next turn, it has disadvantage on attack rolls that are not against you, and when it hits a creature other than you, that creature has resistance to the damage dealt by the attack.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Spirit Shield" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANCESTRAL_GUARDIAN_SPIRIT_SHIELD">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 6th level, the guardian spirits that aid you can provide supernatural protection to those you defend. If you are raging and another creature you can see within 30 feet of you takes damage, you can use your reaction to reduce that damage by 2d6. When you reach certain levels in this class. you can reduce the damage by more: by 3d6 at 10th level and by 4d6 at 14th level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Reaction">
			<description>When raging, if another creature within 30ft takes damage, you can reduce that damage by 2d6.</description>
			<description level="10">When raging, if another creature within 30ft takes damage, you can reduce that damage by 3d6.</description>
			<description level="14">When raging, if another creature within 30ft takes damage, you can reduce that damage by 4d6.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Consult the Spirits" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANCESTRAL_GUARDIAN_CONSULT_THE_SPIRITS">
		<description>
			<p>At 10th level, you gain the ability to consult with your ancestral spirits. When you do so, you cast the augury or clairvoyance spell, without using a spell slot or material components. Rather than creating a spherical sensor, this use of clairvoyance invisibly summons one of your ancestral spirits to the chosen location. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells. After you cast either spell in this way, you can’t use this feature again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
			<description>You can cast Augury or Clairvoyance without using a spell slot or material components and Wisdom as your spellcasting ability. Rather than creating a spherical sensor, this use of clairvoyance invisibly summons one of your ancestral spirits to the chosen location.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AUGURY" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLAIRVOYANCE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Vengeful Ancestors" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ANCESTRAL_GUARDIAN_VENGEFUL_ANCESTORS">
		<description>
			<p>At 14th level, your ancestral spirits grow powerful enough to retaliate. When you use your Spirit Shield to reduce the damage of an attack, the attacker takes an amount of force damage equal to the damage that your Spirit Shield prevents.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you use your Spirit Shield to reduce the damage of an attack, the attacker takes an amount of force damage equal to the damage that your Spirit Shield prevents.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
</elements>