<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>College of Glamour</name>
    <description>The College of Glamour from Xanathar’s Guide to Everything</description>
    <author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/xanathars-guide-everything">Xanathar’s Guide to Everything</author>
    <update version="0.0.4">
      <file name="bard-glamour.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/supplements/xanathars-guide-to-everything/archetypes/bard-glamour.xml" />
    </update>
  </info>
  <element name="College of Glamour" type="Archetype" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_COLLEGE_OF_GLAMOUR">
    <supports>Bard College</supports>
    <description>
      <p>The College of Glamour is the home of bards who mastered their craft in the vibrant realm of the Feywild or under the tutelage Of someone who dwelled there. Tutored by satyrs, eladrin, and other fey, these bards learn to use their magic to delight and captivate others.</p>
      <p class="indent">The bards of this college are regarded with a mixture of awe and fear. Their performances are the stuff of legend. These bards are so eloquent that a speech or song that one of them performs can cause captors to release the bard unharmed and can lull a furious dragon into complacency. The same magic that allows them to quell beasts can also bend minds. Villainous bards of this college can leech off a community for weeks, misusing their magic to turn their hosts into thralls. Heroic bards of this college instead use this power to gladden the downtrodden and undermine oppressors.</p>
      <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_MANTLE_OF_INSPIRATION" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_ENTHRALLING_PERFORMANCE" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_MANTLE_OF_MAJESTY" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_UNBREAKABLE_MAJESTY" />
    </description>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_MANTLE_OF_INSPIRATION" level="3" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_ENTHRALLING_PERFORMANCE" level="3" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_MANTLE_OF_MAJESTY" level="6" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_UNBREAKABLE_MAJESTY" level="14" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Mantle of Inspiration" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_MANTLE_OF_INSPIRATION">
    <description>
      <p>When you join the College of Glamour at 3rd level, you gain the ability to weave a song of fey magic that imbues your allies with vigor and speed.</p>
      <p class="indent">As a bonus action, you can expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration to grant yourself a wondrous appearance. When you do so, choose a number of creatures you can see and that can see you within 60 feet of you, up to a number equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one). Each of them gains 5 temporary hit points. When a creature gains these temporary hit points, it can immediately use its reaction to move up to its speed, without provoking opportunity attacks.</p>
      <p class="indent">The number of temporary hit points increases when you reach certain levels in this class, increasing to 8 at 5th level, 11 at 10th level, and 14 at 15th level.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet action="Bonus Action">
      <description level="3">Expend one use of Bardic Inspiration, and choose up to {{mantle of inspiration:creature-count}} creatures within 60ft of you. Each of them gains {{mantle of inspiration:temp-hp}} temporary HP, and can use its reaction to move up to its speed, without provoking oppertunity attacks.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
		<stat name="mantle of inspiration:creature-count" value="1" bonus="mantle of inspiration" />
		<stat name="mantle of inspiration:creature-count" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="mantle of inspiration" />
		<stat name="mantle of inspiration:temp-hp" value="5" bonus="mantle of inspiration" />
		<stat name="mantle of inspiration:temp-hp" value="8" level="5" bonus="mantle of inspiration" />
		<stat name="mantle of inspiration:temp-hp" value="11" level="10" bonus="mantle of inspiration" />
		<stat name="mantle of inspiration:temp-hp" value="14" level="15" bonus="mantle of inspiration" />
	</rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Enthralling Performance" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_ENTHRALLING_PERFORMANCE">
    <description>
      <p>Starting at 3rd level, you can charge your performance with seductive, fey magic.</p>
      <p class="indent">If you perform for at least 1 minute, you can attempt to inspire wonder in your audience by singing, reciting a poem, or dancing. At the end of the performance, choose a number of humanoids within 60 feet of you who watched and listened to all of it, up to a number equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one). Each target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC or be charmed by you. While charmed in this way, the target idolizes you, it speaks glowingly of you to anyone who talks to it, and it hinders anyone who opposes you, although it avoids violence unless it was already inclined to fight on your behalf. This effect ends on a target after 1 hour, if it takes any damage, if you attack it, or if it witnesses you attacking or damaging any of its allies.</p>
      <p class="indent">If a target succeeds on its saving throw, the target has no hint that you tried to charm it.</p>
      <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet usage="1/Short Rest">
      <description>When performing for 1 minute, choose up to {{charisma:modifier}} creatures within 60ft who watched the whole performance, they make a DC{{spellcasting:dc:cha}} Wisdom save or are charmed by you. While charmed, they idolize you, speak glowingly of you, and hinder anyone that opposes you for 1 hour, or until they take damage, you attack it, or it sees you attacking any of its allies.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <element name="Mantle of Majesty" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_MANTLE_OF_MAJESTY">
    <description>
      <p>At 6th level, you gain the ability to cloak yourself in a fey magic that makes others want to serve you. As a bonus action, you cast command, without expending a spell slot, and you take on an appearance of unearthly beauty for 1 minute or until your concentration ends (as if you were concentrating on a spell). During this time, you can cast command as a bonus action on each of your turns, without expending a spell slot.</p>
      <p class="indent">Any creature charmed by you automatically fails its saving throw against the command you cast with this feature.</p>
      <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Long Rest">
      <description>Cast command, without expending a spell slot, for 1 minute, or until your concentration ends. Creatures charmed by you fail their save.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <element name="Unbreakable Majesty" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_GLAMOUR_UNBREAKABLE_MAJESTY">
    <description>
      <p>At 14th level, your appearance permanently gains an otherworldly aspect that makes you look more lovely and fierce.</p>
      <p class="indent">In addition, as a bonus action, you can assume a magically majestic presence for 1 minute or until you are incapacitated. For the duration, whenever any creature tries to attack you for the first time on a turn, the attacker must make a Charisma saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failed save, it can’t attack you on this turn, and it must choose a new target for its attack or the attack is wasted. On a successful save, it can attack you on this turn, but it has disadvantage on any saving throw it makes against your spells on your next turn.</p>
      <p class="indent">Once you assume this majestic presence, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
      <description>For 1 minute, whenever a creature tries to attack you for the first time on a turn, it must make a DC{{spellcasting:dc:cha}} Charisma saving throw. On a fail, it can't attack you this turn, and must choose a new target for the attack or waste it. On a succes, it can attack, but has disadvantage on saving throws against your spells.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
</elements>