<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>College of Swords</name>
    <description>The College of Swords from Xanathar’s Guide to Everything</description>
    <author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/xanathars-guide-everything">Xanathar’s Guide to Everything</author>
    <update version="0.0.4">
      <file name="bard-swords.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/supplements/xanathars-guide-to-everything/archetypes/bard-swords.xml" />
    </update>
  </info>
  <element name="College of Swords" type="Archetype" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_COLLEGE_OF_SWORDS">
    <supports>Bard College</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Bards of the College of Swords are called blades, and they entertain through daring feats of weapon prowess. Blades perform stunts such as sword swallowing, knife throwing and juggling, and mock combats. Though they use their weapons to entertain, they are also highly trained and skilled warriors in their own right.</p>
      <p class="indent">Their talent with weapons inspires many blades to lead double lives. One blade might use a circus troupe as cover for nefarious deeds such as assassination, robbery, and blackmail. Other blades strike at the wicked, bringing justice to bear against the cruel and powerful. Most troupes are happy to accept a blade’s talent for the excitement it adds to a performance, but few entertainers fully trust a blade in their ranks.</p>
      <p class="indent">Blades who abandon their lives as entertainers have often run into trouble that makes maintaining their secret activities impossible. A blade caught stealing or engaging in vigilante justice is too great a liability for most troupes. With their weapon skills and magic, these blades either take up work as enforcers for thieves’ guilds or strike out on their own as adventurers.</p>
      <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SWORDS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SWORDS_FIGHTING_STYLE" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SWORDS_BLADE_FLOURISH" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SWORDS_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SWORDS_MASTERS_FLOURISH" />
    </description>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SWORDS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="3" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SWORDS_FIGHTING_STYLE" level="3" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SWORDS_BLADE_FLOURISH" level="3" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SWORDS_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="6" />
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SWORDS_MASTERS_FLOURISH" level="14" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SWORDS_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
    <description>
      <p>When you join the College of Swords at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with medium armor and the scimitar.</p>
      <p class="indent">If you‘re proficient with a simple or martial melee weapon, you can use it as a spellcasting focus for your bard spells.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>If you‘re proficient with a simple or martial melee weapon, you can use it as a spellcasting focus for your bard spells.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
      <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SCIMITAR" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Fighting Style" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SWORDS_FIGHTING_STYLE">
    <description>
      <p>At 3rd level, you adopt a style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options. You can’t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if something in the game lets you choose again.</p>
      <h5>DUELING</h5>
      <p>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</p>
      <h5>TWO-WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
      <p>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false" />
    <rules>
      <select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style (College of Swords)" supports="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DUELING|ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_TWOWEAPON_FIGHTING" level="3"/>
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Blade Flourish" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SWORDS_BLADE_FLOURISH">
    <description>
      <p>At 3rd level, you learn to perform impressive displays of martial prowess and speed.</p>
      <p class="indent">Whenever you take the Attack action on your turn, your walking speed increases by 10 feet until the end of the turn, and if a weapon attack that you make as part of this action hits a creature, you can use one of the following Blade Flourish options of your choice. You can use only one Blade Flourish option per turn.</p>
      <p class="indent"><b><i>Defensive Flourish. </i></b>You can expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration to cause the weapon to deal extra damage to the target you hit. The damage equals the number you roll on the Bardic Inspiration die. You also add the number rolled to your AC until the start of your next turn.</p>
      <p class="indent"><b><i>Slashing Flourish. </i></b>You can expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration to cause the weapon to deal extra damage to the target you hit and to any other creature of your choice that you can see within 5 feet of you. The damage equals the number you roll on the Bardic Inspiration die.</p>
      <p class="indent"><b><i>Mobile Flourish. </i></b>You can expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration to cause the weapon to deal extra damage to the target you hit. The damage equals the number you roll on the Bardic Inspiration die. You can also push the target up to 5 feet away from you, plus a number of feet equal to the number you roll on that die. You can then immediately use your reaction to move up to your walking speed to an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the target.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When you attack as an action, your speed increases by 10ft until the end of the turn. If a weapon attack in this action hits, you can use one of your Bardic Inspirations to use a Blade Flourish of your choice.(1/turn) 
        <strong><em>Defensive Flourish.</em></strong> Roll a d{{bardic-inspiration:dice}}, the number you roll is added to the damage of the hit, and adds to your AC untill the start of the next turn. 
        <strong><em>Slashing Flourish.</em></strong> Roll a d{{bardic-inspiration:dice}}, the number you roll is added to the damage of the hit, and to any other creature within 5ft of you. 
        <strong><em>Mobile Flourish.</em></strong> Roll a d{{bardic-inspiration:dice}}, the number you roll is added to the damage of the hit, and you can push the target the number you rolled+5ft away from you. You can then move up to your walking speed towards the target as a reaction.
      </description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <!-- todo: create elements for these attacks? -->
  <element name="Extra Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SWORDS_EXTRA_ATTACK">
    <description>
      <p>Starting at 6th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
    </sheet>
	<rules>
		<stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
	</rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Master's Flourish" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BARD_SWORDS_MASTERS_FLOURISH">
    <description>
      <p>Starting at 14th level, whenever you use a Blade Flourish option, you can roll a d6 and use it instead of expending a Bardic Inspiration die.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Instead of expending a Bardic Inspiration die, you can roll a d6 for a Blade Flourish instead.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
</elements>