<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>Grave Domain</name>
    <description>The Grave Domain from Xanathar’s Guide to Everything</description>
    <author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/xanathars-guide-everything">Xanathar’s Guide to Everything</author>
    <update version="0.1.7">
      <file name="cleric-gravedomain.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/supplements/xanathars-guide-to-everything/archetypes/cleric-gravedomain.xml" />
    </update>
  </info>
  <element name="Grave Domain" type="Archetype" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_CLERIC_GRAVE_DOMAIN">
    <supports>Divine Domain</supports>
    <description>
      <p>Gods of the grave watch over the line between life and death. To these deities, death and the afterlife are a foundational part of the multiverse. To desecrate the peace of the dead is an abomination. Deities of the grave include Kelemvor, Wee jas, the ancestral spirits of the Undying Court, Hades, Anubis, and Osiris. Followers of these deities seek to put wandering spirits to rest, destroy the undead, and ease the suffering of the dying. Their magic also allows them to stave off death for a time. particularly for a person who still has some great work to accomplish in the world. This is a delay of death, not a denial of it, for death will eventually get its due.</p>
      <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRAVE_DOMAIN_DOMAIN_SPELLS" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRAVE_DOMAIN_CIRCLE_OF_MORTALITY" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRAVE_DOMAIN_EYES_OF_THE_GRAVE" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRAVE_DOMAIN_CD_PATH_TO_THE_GRAVE" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRAVE_DOMAIN_SENTINEL_AT_DEATHS_DOOR" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRAVE_DOMAIN_POTENT_SPELLCASTING" />
      <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRAVE_DOMAIN_KEEPER_OF_SOULS" />
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Gods of the grave watch over the line between life and death. To these deities, death and the afterlife are a foundational part of the multiverse. To desecrate the peace of the dead is an abomination.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRAVE_DOMAIN_DOMAIN_SPELLS" level="1"/>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRAVE_DOMAIN_CIRCLE_OF_MORTALITY" level="1"/>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRAVE_DOMAIN_EYES_OF_THE_GRAVE" level="1"/>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRAVE_DOMAIN_CD_PATH_TO_THE_GRAVE" level="2"/>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRAVE_DOMAIN_SENTINEL_AT_DEATHS_DOOR" level="6"/>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRAVE_DOMAIN_POTENT_SPELLCASTING" level="8"/>
      <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRAVE_DOMAIN_KEEPER_OF_SOULS" level="17"/>
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Domain Spells" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRAVE_DOMAIN_DOMAIN_SPELLS">
    <description>
      <p>You gain domain spells at the cleric levels listed in the Grave Domain Spells table. See the Divine Domain class feature for how domain spells work.</p>
      <h5>Grave Domain Spells</h5>
      <table>
        <thead>
          <tr><td>Cleric Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
        </thead>
        <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>bane, false life</em></td></tr>
        <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>gentle repose, ray of enfeeblement</em></td></tr>
        <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>revivify, vampiric touch</em></td></tr>
        <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>blight, death ward</em></td></tr>
        <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>antilife shell, raise dead</em></td></tr>
      </table>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description></description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE" level="1" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" />
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FALSE_LIFE" level="1" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" />
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GENTLE_REPOSE" level="3" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" />
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_ENFEEBLEMENT" level="3" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" />
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REVIVIFY" level="5" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" />
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_VAMPIRIC_TOUCH" level="5" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" />
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT" level="7" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" />
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD" level="7" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" />
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTILIFE_SHELL" level="9" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" />
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAISE_DEAD" level="9" spellcasting="Cleric" prepared="true" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Circle of Mortality" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRAVE_DOMAIN_CIRCLE_OF_MORTALITY">
    <description>
      <p>At 1st level, you gain the ability to manipulate the line between life and death. When you would normally roll one or more dice to restore hit points with a spell to a creature at 0 hit points, you instead use the highest number possible for each die.</p>
      <p class="indent">In addition, you learn the<i>spare the dying cantrip</i>, which doesn’t count against the number of cleric cantrips you know. For you, it has a range of 30 feet, and you can cast it as a bonus action.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>When rolling dice to restore HP with a spell, to a creature at 0HP, instead use the highest number possible for each die. Your <i>spare the dying</i> cantrip, has a range of 30ft and is a bonus action.</description>
    </sheet>
    <rules>
      <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPARE_THE_DYING" spellcasting="Cleric" />
    </rules>
  </element>
  <element name="Eyes of the Grave" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRAVE_DOMAIN_EYES_OF_THE_GRAVE">
    <description>
      <p>At lst level, you gain the ability to occasionally sense the presence of the undead, whose existence is an insult to the natural cycle of life. As an action, you can open your awareness to magically detect undead. Until the end of your next turn, you know the location of any undead within 60 feet of you that isn’t behind total cover and that isn’t protected from divination magic. This sense doesn’t tell you anything about a creature's capabilities or identity.</p>
      <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>{{wisdom:modifier}} times per long rest, as an action you know the location of any undead within 60 feet of you that isn’t behind total cover and that isn’t protected from divination magic.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <element name="Channel Divinity: Path to the Grave" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRAVE_DOMAIN_CD_PATH_TO_THE_GRAVE">
    <description>
      <p>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to mark another creature’s life force for termination.</p>
      <p class="indent">As an action, you choose one creature you can see within 30 feet of you, cursing it until the end of your next turn. The next time you or an ally of yours hits the cursed creature with an attack, the creature has vulnerability to all of that attack's damage, and then the curse ends.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet alt="Path to the Grave" action="Action" usage="Channel Divinity">
      <description>Choose one creature you can see within 30ft, and curse it until the end of your next turn. The next time you or an ally of yours hits the cursed creature with an attack, the creature has vulnerability to all of that attack's damage, and then the curse ends.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <element name="Sentinel at Death's Door" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRAVE_DOMAIN_SENTINEL_AT_DEATHS_DOOR">
    <description>
      <p>At 6th level, you gain the ability to impede death’s progress. As a reaction when you or a creature you can see within 30 feet of you suffers a critical hit, you can turn that hit into a normal hit. Any effects triggered by a critical hit are canceled. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet action="Reaction">
      <description>When you or a creature you can see within 30ft of you suffers a critical hit, turn that hit into a normal hit. ({{wisdom:modifier}}/day)</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <element name="Potent Spellcasting" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRAVE_DOMAIN_POTENT_SPELLCASTING">
    <description>
      <p>Starting at 8th level, you add your Wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Add {{wisdom:modifier}} to damage dealt with a cleric cantrip.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
  <element name="Keeper of Souls" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GRAVE_DOMAIN_KEEPER_OF_SOULS">
    <description>
      <p>Starting at 17th level. you can seize a trace of vitality from a parting soul and use it to heal the living. When an enemy you can see dies within 60 feet of you, you or one creature of your choice that is within 60 feet of you regains hit points equal to the enemy’s number of Hit Dice. You can use this feature only if you aren’t incapacitated. Once you use it, you can't do so again until the start of your next turn.</p>
    </description>
    <sheet>
      <description>Once per turn, when an enemy you can see dies within 60 feet of you, you or one creature of your choice that is within 60 feet of you regains hit points equal to the enemy’s number of Hit Dice.</description>
    </sheet>
  </element>
</elements>
