<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Sun Soul</name>
        <description>The Sun Soul archetype from Xanathar’s Guide to Everything</description>
        <author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/xanathars-guide-everything">Xanathar’s Guide to Everything</author>
        <update version="0.0.4">
            <file name="monk-sunsoul.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/supplements/xanathars-guide-to-everything/archetypes/monk-sunsoul.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Way of the Sun Soul" type="Archetype" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_WAY_OF_THE_SUN_SOUL">
        <supports>Monastic Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Monks of the Way of the Sun Soul learn to channel their life energy into searing bolts of light. They teach that meditation can unlock the ability to unleash the indomitable light shed by the soul of every living creature.</p>
            <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUN_SOUL_RADIANT_SUN_BOLT" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUN_SOUL_SEARING_ARC_STRIKE" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUN_SOUL_SEARING_SUNBURST" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUN_SOUL_SUN_SHIELD" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Transforms ki into bursts of fire and searing bolts of light</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUN_SOUL_RADIANT_SUN_BOLT" level="3"/>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUN_SOUL_SEARING_ARC_STRIKE" level="6"/>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUN_SOUL_SEARING_SUNBURST" level="11"/>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUN_SOUL_SUN_SHIELD" level="17"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Radiant Sun Bolt" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUN_SOUL_RADIANT_SUN_BOLT">
        <description>
            <p>Starting when you Choose this tradition at 3rd level, you can hurl searing bolts of magical radiance.</p>
            <p class="indent">You gain a new attack option that you can use with the Attack action. This special attack is a ranged spell attack with a range of 30 feet. You are proficient with it, and you add your Dexterity modifier to its attack and damage rolls. Its damage is radiant, and its damage die is a d4. This die changes as you gain monk levels, as shown in the Martial Arts column of the Monk table.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you take the Attack action on your turn and use this special attack as part of it, you can spend 1 ki point to make the special attack twice as a bonus action.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you gain the Extra Attack feature, this special attack can be used for any of the attacks you make as part of the Attack action.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Attack">
            <description>Make a ranged spell attack ({{radiant sun bolt:range}}ft, +{{radiant sun bolt:attack}} vs AC, {{radiant sun bolt:die:count}}d{{radiant sun bolt:die:size}}+{{radiant sun bolt:damage}} radiant damage) When you use this attack, spend 1 ki point to make it twice as a bonus action.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="radiant sun bolt:attack" value="proficiency" bonus="proficiency" />
            <stat name="radiant sun bolt:attack" value="dexterity:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
            <stat name="radiant sun bolt:damage" value="dexterity:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
            <stat name="radiant sun bolt:range" value="30" />
            <stat name="radiant sun bolt:die:count" value="1" />
            <stat name="radiant sun bolt:die:size" value="martial arts:dice" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Searing Arc Strike" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUN_SOUL_SEARING_ARC_STRIKE">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level, you gain the ability to channel your ki into searing waves of energy. Immediately after you take the Attack action on your turn, you can spend 2 ki points to cast the <i>burning hands</i> spell as a bonus action.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can spend additional ki points to cast burning hands as a higher-level spell. Each additional ki point you spend increases the spell’s level by 1. The maximum number of ki points (2 plus any additional points) that you can spend on the spell equals half your monk level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>After an attack, spend 2 ki point to cast <i>burning hands</i>. Additional ki points to cast the spell at higher levels (1/level). You can spent maximum {{searing arc strike:ki maximum}} ki points (2 plus any additional points).</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="searing arc strike:ki maximum" value="level:monk:half" />
            <!-- setters for modification on spells not completed -->
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BURNING_HANDS" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Searing Sunburst" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUN_SOUL_SEARING_SUNBURST">
        <description>
            <p>At 11th level, you gain the ability to create an orb of light that erupts into a devastating explosion. As an action, you magically create an orb and hurl it at a point you choose within 150 feet, where it erupts into a sphere of radiant light for a brief but deadly instant.</p>
            <p class="indent">Each creature in that 20—foot-radius sphere must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or take 2d6 radiant damage. A creature doesn’t need to make the save if the creature is behind total cover that is opaque.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can increase the spheres damage by spending ki points. Each point you spend, to a maximum of 3, increases the damage by 2d6.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action">
            <description>Create an orb and hurl it up to 150ft, where it erupts into a 20ft radius sphere of Radiant light. Each creature within it makes a DC{{ki:dc}} Constitution saving throw or takes 2d6 Radiant damage. Spend up to 3 ki point to increase the damage by 2d6/ki point spent.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Sun Shield" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_SUN_SOUL_SUN_SHIELD">
        <description>
            <p>At 17th level, you become wreathed in a luminous, magical aura. You shed bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet. You can extinguish or restore the light as a bonus action.</p>
            <p class="indent">If a creature hits you with a melee attack while this light shines, you can use your reaction to deal radiant damage to the creature. The radiant damage equals 5 + your Wisdom modifier.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can extinguish or restore the light of your aura as a bonus action. If a creature hits you with a melee while the light shines, you can use your reaction to deal {{sun shield:damage}} radiant damage to the creature.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="sun shield:damage" value="5" />
            <stat name="sun shield:damage" value="wisdom:modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>
</elements>