<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Drunken Master</name>
		<description>The Drunken Master archetype from Xanathar’s Guide to Everything</description>
		<author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/xanathars-guide-everything">Xanathar’s Guide to Everything</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="monk-drunkenmaster.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/supplements/xanathars-guide-to-everything/archetypes/monk-drunkenmaster.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

    <element name="Way of the Drunken Master" type="Archetype" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_WAY_OF_THE_DRUNKEN_MASTER">
        <supports>Monastic Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The Way of the Drunken Master teaches its students to move with the jerky, unpredictable movements of a drunkard. A drunken master sways, tottering on unsteady feet, to present what seems like an incompetent combatant who proves frustrating to engage. The drunken master’s erratic stumbles conceal a carefully executed dance of blocks, parries, advances, attacks, and retreats.</p>
            <p class="indent">A drunken master often enjoys playing the fool to bring gladness to the despondent or to demonstrate humility to the arrogant, but when battle is joined, the drunken master can be a maddening, masterful foe.</p>
            <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUNKEN_MASTER_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUNKEN_MASTER_DRUNKEN_TECHNIQUE" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUNKEN_MASTER_TIPSY_SWAY" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUNKEN_MASTER_DRUNKARDS_LUCK" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUNKEN_MASTER_INTOXICATED_FRENZY" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Confounds foes through a martial arts tradition inspired by the swaying of a drunkard</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUNKEN_MASTER_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="3"/>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUNKEN_MASTER_DRUNKEN_TECHNIQUE" level="3"/>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUNKEN_MASTER_TIPSY_SWAY" level="6"/>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUNKEN_MASTER_DRUNKARDS_LUCK" level="11"/>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUNKEN_MASTER_INTOXICATED_FRENZY" level="17"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Bonus Profiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUNKEN_MASTER_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
        <description>
            <p>When you choose this tradition at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in the Performance skill if you don’t already have it. Your martial arts technique mixes combat training with the precision of a dancer and the antics of a jester. You also gain proficiency with brewer’s supplies if you don’t already have it.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERFORMANCE" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_BREWERS_SUPPLIES" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Drunken Technique" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUNKEN_MASTER_DRUNKEN_TECHNIQUE">
        <description>
            <p>At 3rd level, you learn how to twist and turn quickly as part of your Flurry of Blows. Whenever you use Flurry of Blows, you gain the benefit of the Disengage action, and your walking speed increases by 10 feet until the end of the current turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you use Flurry of Blows, you gain the benefit of Disengage, and your speed increases by 10ft until the end of the current turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Tipsy Sway" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUNKEN_MASTER_TIPSY_SWAY">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 6th level, you can move in sudden, swaying ways. You gain the following benefits.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Leap to Your Feet. </i></b>When you’re prone, you can stand up by spending 5 feet of movement, rather than half your speed.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Redirect Attack. </i></b>When a creature misses you with a melee attack roll, you can spend 1 ki point as a reaction to cause that attack to hit one creature of your choice, other than the attacker.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Standing up only costs 5ft of movement. Reaction: When a creatures misses you with a melee attack, spand 1 ki point to cause the attack to hit one creature of your choice, within 5ft.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Drunkard's Luck" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUNKEN_MASTER_DRUNKARDS_LUCK">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at llth level, you always seem to get a lucky bounce at the right moment. When you make an ability check, an attack roll, or a saving throw and have disadvantage on the roll, you can spend 2 ki points to cancel the disadvantage for that roll.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can spend 2 ki point to cancel disadvantage for an ability check, attack roll, or saving throw.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Intoxicated Frenzy" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_DRUNKEN_MASTER_INTOXICATED_FRENZY">
        <description>
            <p>At 17th level, you gain the ability to make an overwhelming number of attacks against a group of enemies. When you use your Flurry of Blows, you can make up to three additional attacks with it (up to a total of five Flurry of Blows attacks), provided that each Flurry of Blows attack targets a different creature this turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you use your Flurry of Blows, make up to 3 additional attacks, provided they each target a different creature.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>