<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
  <info>
    <name>Gray Dwarves (Duergar)</name>
    <description>Subrace from the Sword Coast Adventurer’s Guide.</description>
    <author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/sc-adventurers-guide">Wizards of the Coast</author>
    <update version="0.1.2">
      <file name="race-duergar.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/supplements/sword-coast-adventurers-guide/races/race-duergar.xml" />
    </update>
  </info>

  <element name="Duergar" type="Sub Race" source="Sword Coast Adventurer’s Guide" id="ID_SCAG_SUBRACE_GRAY_DWARF">
    <supports>Dwarf</supports>
    <description>
        <p>The gray dwarves, or duergar, live deep in the Underdark. After delving deeper than any other dwarves, they were enslaved by mind flayers for eons. Although they eventually won their freedom , these grim, ashen-skinned dwarves now take slaves of their own and are as tyrannical as their former masters.</p>
        <p class="indent">Physically similar to other dwarves in some ways, duergar are wiry and lean, with black eyes and bald heads, with the males growing long, unkempt, gray beards.</p>
        <p class="indent">Duergar value toil above all else. Showing emotions other than grim determination or wrath is frowned on in their culture, but they can sometimes seem joyful when at work. They have the typical dwarven appreciation for order, tradition, and impeccable craftsmanship, but their goods are purely utilitarian, disdaining aesthetic or artistic value.</p>
        <p class="indent">Few duergar become adventurers, fewer still on the surface world, because they are a hidebound and suspicious race. Those who leave their subterranean cities are usually exiles. Check with your Dungeon Master to see if you can play a gray dwarf character.</p>
      <p>
        <span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span>Your Strength score increases by 1.<br />
        <span class="feature">Superior Darkvision.</span>Your darkvision has a radius of 120 feet.<br />
        <span class="feature">Extra Language.</span>You can speak, read, and write Undercommon.<br />
        <span class="feature">Duergar Resilience.</span>You have advantage on saving throws against illusions and against being charmed or paralyzed.<br />
        <span class="feature">Duergar Magic.</span>When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the enlarge/reduce spell on yourself once with this trait, using only the spell's enlarge option. When you reach 5th level, you can cast the invisibility spell on yourself once with this trait. You don't need material components for either spell, and you can't cast them while you're in direct sunlight, a lthough sunlight has no effect on them once cast. You regain the ability to cast these spells with this trait when you finish a long rest. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for these spells.<br />
        <span class="feature">Sunlight Sensitivity.</span>You have disadvantage on attack rolls and on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight when you, the target of your attack, or whatever you are trying to perceive is in direct sunlight.<br />
      </p>
    </description>
    <sheet display="false"/>
    <rules>
      <stat name="strength" value="1" />
      <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_SUPERIORDARKVISION" />
      <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_UNDERCOMMON" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_DUERGAR_RESILIENCE" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_DUERGAR_MAGIC" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_SUNLIGHT_SENSITIVITY" />
    </rules>
  </element>

	<element name="Duergar Resilience" type="Racial Trait" source="Sword Coast Adventurer’s Guide" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_DUERGAR_RESILIENCE">
		<description>
			<p>You have advantage on saving throws against illusions and against being charmed or paralyzed.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have advantage on saving throws against illusions and against being charmed or paralyzed.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Duergar Magic" type="Racial Trait" source="Sword Coast Adventurer’s Guide" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_DUERGAR_MAGIC">
		<requirements>[level:3]</requirements>
		<description>
			<p>When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the enlarge/reduce spell on yourself once with this trait, using only the spell's enlarge option. When you reach 5th level, you can cast the invisibility spell on yourself once with this trait. You don't need material components for either spell, and you can't cast them while you're in direct sunlight, although sunlight has no effect on them once cast. You regain the ability to cast these spells with this trait when you finish a long rest. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>You can cast enlarge on yourself. (Spellcasting: Intelligence)</description>
			<description level="5">You can cast enlarge and invisibility on yourself. (Spellcasting: Intelligence)</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<!-- <stat name="duergar magic:spellcasting:ability" value="Intelligence" /> -->
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENLARGE_REDUCE" level="3" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY" level="5" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>  