<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="ranger-favored-enemies.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/supplements/ranger-favored-enemies.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
	<element name="Derro" type="Class Feature" source="Mordenkainen’s Tome of Foes" id="ID_WOTC_MTF_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_DERRO">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Derro slink through the subterranean realms, seeking places that are safe from the perils of the Underdark. Equal parts fearful and vicious, bands of these dwarfkin prey on those weaker than themselves, while giving simpering obeisance to any creatures they deem more powerful. Wild-haired, haggard, shuddering, and shabbily dressed, a lone derro seems a pitiable creature, but when a cackling, spitting, growling, howling horde of them attacks, the sight inspires both fear and revulsion.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Giff" type="Class Feature" source="Mordenkainen’s Tome of Foes" id="ID_WOTC_MTF_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_GIFF">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>It’s easy to spot the giff in a room: a group of 7-foot-tall, hippopotamus-headed humanoids attired in gaudy military uniforms, with gleaming pistols and muskets on display. These spacefaring mercenaries are renowned for their martial training and their love of explosives.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Meazel" type="Class Feature" source="Mordenkainen’s Tome of Foes" id="ID_WOTC_MTF_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_MEAZEL">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>In places where the Shadowfell washes against the shores of the Material Plane dwell meazels, hateful hermits who left behind their old lives to contemplate their misery in shadow. Now evil burns in their hearts, and they resent any intrusion into their suffering.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Nagpa" type="Class Feature" source="Mordenkainen’s Tome of Foes" id="ID_WOTC_MTF_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_NAGPA">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Long ago, the Raven Queen cursed a cabal of thirteen powerful wizards for meddling in a ritual that would have helped avert a war between the gods. She stripped them of their beauty, turning them into scabrous, birdlike monstrosities. The nagpas now plot as they ever did, but they now strive to bring about terrible, world-shaking calamities so they can pry secrets and power from the wreckage their conspiracies create.</p>
			<p class="indent">The nagpas fear the Raven Queen and do their best to avoid her and her agents. When it’s impossible to do so, they become cringing, fawning things, eager to please and thereby escape the cold gaze of the being who brought them so low. All of the original thirteen remain alive, thanks to their cunning and their willingness to do whatever is necessary to survive.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Skulk" type="Class Feature" source="Mordenkainen’s Tome of Foes" id="ID_WOTC_MTF_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_SKULK">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Skulks are the soulless shells of travelers who became lost in the Shadowfell, wandering its gray wastes until they lost all sense of self. They are so devoid of identity that they have become permanently invisible. Only children can see a skulk without the help of a mirror or a special candle. On the rare occasions when a skulk is visible, it appears as a drab, featureless, hairless humanoid.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Tortles" type="Class Feature" source="Mordenkainen’s Tome of Foes" id="ID_WOTC_MTF_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_TORTLE">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Tortles are omnivorous, turtle-like humanoids with shells that cover most of their bodies. Tortles have a saying: "We wear our homes on our backs." Consequently, tortles feel little need to stay put for long.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Kraul" type="Class Feature" source="Guildmasters’ Guide to Ravnica" id="ID_WOTC_GGTR_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_KRAUL">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Kraul society is organized into well-defined roles and castes. The vast majority of the kraul occupy various tiers of soldiery, from commanders and elite troops down to the lowliest infantry.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Loxodons" type="Class Feature" source="Guildmasters’ Guide to Ravnica" id="ID_WOTC_GGTR_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_LOXODON">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The humanoid elephants called loxodons are often oases of calm in the busy streets of Ravnica. They hum or chant in sonorous tones and move slowly or sit in perfect stillness. If provoked to action, loxodons are true terrors—bellowing with rage, trumpeting and flapping their ears. Their serene wisdom, fierce loyalty, and unwavering conviction are tremendous assets to their guilds.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Lava Children" type="Class Feature" source="Waterdeep: Dungeon of the Mad Mage" id="ID_WOTC_WDMM_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_LAVA_CHILD">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Physically identical to one another, lava children have muscular builds and childish, perpetually grinning faces. Most are born in the Fountains of Creation, also known as the Plane of Magma, which is wedged between the Elemental Planes of Earth and Fire. Within volcanic caverns, lava children form communities, serving primordial beings out of fear or worshiping gods of earth and fire.</p>
			<p class="indent">Though they’re not violent by nature, lava children fiercely defend territory they claim as their own. Many intruders have been fooled by a lava child’s smile, belie~ing themselves welcome when in fact they’re about to be torn limb from limb. Lava children typically stick close to their lairs, but actively hunt when food grows scarce.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Locathah" type="Class Feature" source="Ghosts of Saltmarsh" id="ID_WOTC_GOS_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_LOCATHAH">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>These resilient and proud fish-folk (found in Danger at Dunwater) have endured war, slavery, and mistreatment at the hands of other aquatic creatures. They dwell in submerged tribal communities along seacoasts, and hunt both above and below the water.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Mongrelfolk" type="Class Feature" source="Curse of Strahd" id="ID_WOTC_COS_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_MONGRELFOLK">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Mongrelfolk are humanoids that have undergone, or whose ancestors underwent, horrific magical transformations, to the extent that they retain only a fraction of their original being. Their humanoid bodies incorporate the features of various beasts. For example, one mongrelfolk might have the basic body shape of a dwarf with a head that combines the features of a cat and a lizard, one arm that ends in a crab’s pincer, and one leg that ends in a cloven hoof. Another might have the skin and horns of a cow, the eyes of a spider, frog’s legs, and a scaly lizard’s tail. Each mongrelfolk’s mad combination of humanoid and animal forms results in its having a slow, awkward gait.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Firenewt" type="Class Feature" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGM_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_FIRENEWT">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>In regions that contain hot springs, volcanic activity, or similar hot and wet conditions, firenewts might be found. These humanoid amphibians live in a militaristic theocracy that reveres elemental fire in its worst incarnation.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Grung" type="Class Feature" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGM_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_GRUNG">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Grungs are aggressive frog-like humanoids found in rain forests and tropical jungles. They are fiercely territorial and see themselves as superior to most other creatures.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Tabaxi" type="Class Feature" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGM_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_TABAXI">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Hailing from a strange and distant land, wandering tabaxi are catlike humanoids driven by curiosity to collect interesting artifacts, gather tales and stories, and lay eyes on all the world’s wonders. Ultimate travelers, the inquisitive tabaxi rarely stay in one place for long. Their innate nature pushes them to leave no secrets uncovered, no treasures or legends lost.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Tritons" type="Class Feature" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGM_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_TRITON">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Tritons guard the ocean depths, building small settlements beside deep trenches, portals to the elemental planes, and other dangerous spots far from the eyes of land-bound folk. Long-established guardians of the deep ocean floor, in recent years the noble tritons have become increasingly active in the world above.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Firbolg" type="Class Feature" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGM_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_FIRBOLG">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Firbolg tribes cloister in remote forest strongholds, preferring to spend their days in quiet harmony with the woods. When provoked, firbolgs demonstrate formidable skills with weapons and druidic magic.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Goliaths" type="Class Feature" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGM_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_GOLIATH">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>At the highest mountain peaks-far above the slopes where trees grow and where the air is thin and the frigid winds howl-dwell the reclusive goliaths. Few folk can claim to have seen a goliath, and fewer still can claim friendship with them. Goliaths wander a bleak realm of rock, wind, and cold. Their bodies look as if they are carved from mountain stone and give them great physical power. Their spirits take after the wandering wind, making them nomads who wander from peak to peak. Their hearts are infused with the cold regard of their frigid realm, leaving each goliath with the responsibility to earn a place in the tribe or die trying.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Xvart" type="Class Feature" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGM_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_XVART">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Xvarts are cruel, cowardly humanoids spawned by a cowardly, renegade demigod. They have blue skin, vivid orange eyes, and receding hairlines, mirroring their creator’s appearance. They stand about 3 feet tall.</p>
			<p class="indent">Xvarts live in remote hills, forests, and caves. Each tribe is led by a speaker, who is usually the brightest one among them. The speaker serves as the tribe’s ambassador, and often dons short wooden stilts and heavy robes to look taller and more imperious. The rest of the tribe hunts for food, plundering crops and livestock from nearby farms if the hunt goes poorly. Xvarts aren’t much of a threat to civilized locations because they are somewhat fearful of humans, dwarves, and elves.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Genasi" type="Class Feature" source="Princes of the Apocalypse" id="ID_WOTC_POTA_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_GENASI">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Those who think of other planes at all consider them remote, distant realms, but planar influence can be felt throughout the world. It sometimes manifests in beings who, through an accident of birth, carry the power of the planes in their blood. The genasi are one such people, the offspring of genies and mortals.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Changelings" type="Class Feature" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_CHANGELINGS">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A changeling can shift its face and form with a thought. Many changelings use this gift as a form of artistic and emotional expression, but it’s an invaluable tool for grifters, spies, and others who wish to deceive. This leads many people to treat known changelings with fear and suspicion.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Shifters" type="Class Feature" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_SHIFTERS">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Shifters are sometimes called the weretouched, as many believe that they are the descendants of humans and lycanthropes. They are humanoids with a bestial aspect. While they can’t fully change shape, they can temporarily enhance their animalistic features—a state they call shifting. Whatever their origins, shifters have evolved into a unique race. A shifter walks on the knife’s edge between the wilds and the world around them. Do they embrace their primal instincts or the path of civilization?</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Kalashtar" type="Class Feature" source="Eberron: Rising from the Last War" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_KALASHTAR">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The kalashtar are a compound race created from the union of humanity with renegade spirits from the plane of dreams—spirits called the quori. Kalashtar are often seen as wise, spiritual people with great compassion for others. But there is an unmistakable alien quality to the kalashtar, and they are haunted by the conflicts of their otherworldly spirits.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
	<element name="Verdans" type="Class Feature" source="Acquisitions Incorporated" id="ID_WOTC_AI_CLASS_FEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY_HUMANOID_VERDAN">
		<supports>Humanoid Favored Enemy</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The verdan owe their existence to chaos. Descended and transformed from a large clan of goblins and hobgoblins, those who became the verdan were simply living their lives, doing goblinoid things. But then passing through the shadow of That-Which-Endures changed them forever. Now the newest race to call Faerûn home, the verdan do their best to find their way in an unfamiliar world.</p>
		</description>
	</element>
</elements>