<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.1.4">
			<file name="sources.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/supplements/sources.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Hoard of the Dragon Queen" type="Source" source="Hoard of the Dragon Queen" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_HOARD_OF_THE_DRAGON_QUEEN">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p><strong>Fight the war against draconic oppression in this adventure for the world’s greatest roleplaying game.</strong></p><p>In an audacious bid for power, the Cult of the Dragon, along with its dragon allies and the Red Wizards of Thay, seek to bring Tiamat from her prison in the Nine Hells to Faerûn. To this end, they are sweeping from town to town, laying waste to all those who oppose them and gathering a hoard of riches for their dread queen. The threat of annihilation has become so dire that groups as disparate as the Harpers and Zhentarim are banding together in the fight against the cult. Never before has the need for heroes been so desperate.</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">HOTDQ</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/hoard-dragon-queen</set>
			<set name="image">http://dnd.wizards.com/sites/default/files/media/styles/product_tabletop_left/public/images/product/DnD_HoardDraQueen.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20140819</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Rise of Tiamat" type="Source" source="Rise of Tiamat" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_RISE_OF_TIAMAT">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p><strong>Avert the Cataclysmic Return of Tiamat in this Adventure for the World’s Greatest Roleplaying Game.</strong></p><p>The Cult of the Dragon leads the charge in an unholy crusade to bring Tiamat back to the Realms, and the situation grows more perilous for good people with each passing moment. The battle becomes increasingly political as opportunities to gather allies and gain advantage present themselves. From Waterdeep to the Sea of Moving Ice to Thay, it is a race against Evil. Succeed or succumb to the oppression of draconic tyranny. Win or lose, things will never be the same again.</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">ROT</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/rise-tiamat</set>
			<set name="image">http://dnd.wizards.com/sites/default/files/media/styles/product_tabletop_left/public/images/product/DnD_RiseTiamat.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20141104</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Princes of the Apocalypse" type="Source" source="Princes of the Apocalypse" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_PRINCES_OF_THE_APOCALYPSE">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p><strong>Abolish an ancient evil threatening devastation in this adventure for the world’s greatest roleplaying game!</strong></p><p>Called by the Elder Elemental Eye to serve, four corrupt prophets have risen from the depths of anonymity to claim mighty weapons with direct links to the power of the elemental princes. Each of these prophets has assembled a cadre of cultists and creatures to serve them in the construction of four elemental temples of lethal design. It is up to adventurers from heroic factions such as the Emerald Enclave and the Order of the Gauntlet to discover where the true power of each prophet lay, and dismantle it before it comes boiling up to obliterate the Realms.</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">POTA</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/princes-apocalypse</set>
			<set name="image">http://dnd.wizards.com/sites/default/files/media/styles/product_tabletop_left/public/images/product/POTA.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20150407</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Out of the Abyss" type="Source" source="Out of the Abyss" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_OUT_OF_THE_ABYSS">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p><strong>Dare to descend into the Underdark in this adventure for the world’s greatest roleplaying game!</strong></p><p>The Underdark is a subterranean wonderland, a vast and twisted labyrinth where fear reigns. It is the home of horrific monsters that have never seen the light of day. It is here that the dark elf Gromph Baenre, Archmage of Menzoberranzan, casts a foul spell meant to ignite a magical energy that suffuses the Underdark and tears open portals to the demonic Abyss. What steps through surprises even him, and from that moment on, the insanity that pervades the Underdark escalates and threatens to shake the Forgotten Realms to its foundations. Stop the madness before it consumes you!</p><p><em>A Dungeons &amp; Dragons adventure for characters of levels 1–15</em></p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">OOTA</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/outoftheabyss</set>
			<set name="image">http://dnd.wizards.com/sites/default/files/media/styles/product_tabletop_left/public/images/product/DnD_OotA.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20150915</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sword Coast Adventurer’s Guide" type="Source" source="Sword Coast Adventurer’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_SWORD_COAST_ADVENTURERS_GUIDE">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>WELCOME TO THE SWORD COAST—a region of Faerûn that comprises shining paragons of civilization and culture, perilous locales fraught with dread and evil, and encompassing them all, a wilderness that offers every explorer vast opportunity and simultaneously promises great danger.</p><p>While the Sword Coast Adventurer’s Guide is a valuable resource for Dungeon Masters, it was crafted with players and their characters foremost in mind. There is a plethora of new character options to intrigue and inspire every member of the adventuring party.</p><p>For use with the fifth edition Player’s Handbook, Monster Manual, and Dungeon Master’s Guide, the Sword Coast Adventurer’s Guide provides the setting, story, and character options needed to participate in a game anywhere along the Sword Coast of the Forgotten Realms.</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">SCAG</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/sc-adventurers-guide</set>
			<set name="image">http://dnd.wizards.com/sites/default/files/media/styles/product_tabletop_left/public/images/product/DnD_SCAG.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20151103</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Curse of Strahd" type="Source" source="Curse of Strahd" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_CURSE_OF_STRAHD">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p><strong>Unravel the mysteries of Ravenloft in this dread adventure for the world’s greatest roleplaying game</strong></p><p>Under raging storm clouds, the vampire Count Strahd von Zarovich stands silhouetted against the ancient walls of Castle Ravenloft. Rumbling thunder pounds the castle spires. The wind’s howling increases as he turns his gaze down toward the village of Barovia. A lightning flash rips through the darkness, but Strahd is gone. Only the howling of the wind fills the midnight air. The master of Castle Ravenloft is having guests for dinner—and you are invited.</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">COS</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/curse-strahd</set>
			<set name="image">http://dnd.wizards.com/sites/default/files/media/styles/product_tabletop_left/public/images/product/CurseofStrahd_ProductImage.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20160315</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Storm King’s Thunder" type="Source" source="Storm King's Thunder" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_STORM_KINGS_THUNDER">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p><strong>To fight giants, you must be giant.</strong></p><p>This 256-page adventure for characters of 1st level to 11th level or higher provides everything a Dungeon Master needs to create an exciting and memorable play experience for the Storm King’s Thunder story, including rune magic items, a new treasure option for characters.</p><p>Giants have emerged from their strongholds to threaten civilization as never before. Hill giants are stealing all the grain and livestock they can, while stone giants have been scouring settlements that have been around forever. Fire giants are press-ganging the small folk into the desert, while frost giant longships have been pillaging along the Sword Coast. Even the elusive cloud giants have been witnessed, their wondrous floating cities appearing above Waterdeep and Baldur’s Gate. Where is the storm giant King Hekaton, who is tasked with keeping order among the giants?</p><p>The humans, dwarves, elves, and other small folk of the Sword Coast will be crushed underfoot by the onslaught of these giant foes. The only chance at survival is for the small folk to work together to investigate this invasion and harness the power of rune magic, the giants’ weapon against their ancient enemies, the dragons. The only way the people of Faerûn can restore order is to use the giants’ own power against them.</p><p><em>Stand with or against the giants in this adventure for the world's greatest roleplaying game.</em></p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">SKT</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/storm-kings-thunder</set>
			<set name="image">http://dnd.wizards.com/sites/default/files/media/styles/product_tabletop_left/public/images/product/SKT_Book.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20160906</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" type="Source" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_VOLOS_GUIDE_TO_MONSTERS">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p><strong>Research has never been so dangerous…</strong></p><p>Explore the breadth of D&amp;D’s monsters in this immersive 224-page volume filled with beautiful illustrations and in-depth lore. Volo’s Guide to Monsters provides something exciting for players and Dungeon Masters everywhere!</p><p>The esteemed loremaster Volothamp Geddarm is back and he’s written a fantastical dissertation, covering some of the most iconic monsters in the Forgotten Realms. Unfortunately, the Sage of Shadowdale himself, Elminster, doesn’t believe Volo gets some of the important details quite right. Don’t miss out as Volo and Elminster square off (academically speaking of course) to illuminate the uninitiated on creatures both common and obscure. Uncover the machinations of the mysterious Kraken Society, what is the origin of the bizarre froghemoth, or how to avoid participating in the ghastly reproductive cycle of the grotesque vargouille.</p><p>Dungeon Masters and players will get some much-needed guidance as you plan your next venture, traipsing about some dusty old ruin in search of treasure, lore, and let’s not forget ... dangerous creatures whose horns, claws, fangs, heads, or even hides might comfortably adorn the walls of your trophy room. If you survive.</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">VGTM</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/volos-guide-to-monsters</set>
			<set name="image">http://dnd.wizards.com/sites/default/files/media/styles/product_tabletop_left/public/images/product/Volos_Monster_manual_1.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20161115</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Tales from the Yawning Portal" type="Source" source="Tales from the Yawning Portal" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_TALES_FROM_THE_YAWNING_PORTAL">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p><strong>Dread tales told in the dead of night!</strong></p><p>When the shadows grow long in Waterdeep and the fireplace in the taproom of the Yawning Portal dims to a deep crimson glow, adventurers from across the Forgotten Realms, and even from other worlds, spin tales and spread rumors of dark dungeons and lost treasures. Some of the yarns overheard by Durnan, the barkeep of the Yawning Portal, are inspired by places and events in far-flung lands from across the D&amp;D multiverse, and these tales have been collected into a single volume.</p><p>Within this tome are seven of the most compelling dungeons from the 40+ year history of Dungeons &amp; Dragons. Some are classics that have hosted an untold number of adventurers, while others are some of the most popular adventures ever printed.</p><p>The seeds of these stories now rest in your hands. D&amp;D’s most storied dungeons are now part of your modern repertoire of adventures. Enjoy, and remember to keep a few spare character sheets handy.</p><p>For use with the fifth edition Player’s Handbook, Monster Manual, and Dungeon Master’s Guide, this book provides fans with adventures, magic items and deadly monsters, all of which have been updated to the fifth edition rules. Explore seven deadly dungeons in this adventure supplement for the world’s greatest roleplaying game.</p><p><strong><em>Tales from the Yawning Portal includes the following adventures:</em></strong></p><ul><li>Against the Giants</li><li>Dead in Thay</li><li>Forge of Fury</li><li>Hidden Shrine of Tamoachan</li><li>Sunless Citadel</li><li>Tomb of Horrors</li><li>White Plume Mountain</li></ul>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">TFTYP</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/tales-yawning-portal</set>
			<set name="image">http://dnd.wizards.com/sites/default/files/media/styles/product_tabletop_left/public/images/product/2016_010516_Yawning_Portal_Product_TFTYP.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20170404</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Tomb of Annihilation" type="Source" source="Tomb of Annihilation" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_TOMB_OF_ANNIHILATION">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p><strong>Dare to defy death in this adventure for the world’s greatest roleplaying game.</strong></p><p>The talk of the streets and taverns has all been about the so-called death curse: a wasting disease afflicting everyone who’s ever been raised from the dead. Victims grow thinner and weaker each day, slowly but steadily sliding toward the death they once denied.</p><p>When they finally succumb, they can’t be raised—and neither can anyone else, regardless of whether they’ve ever received that miracle in the past. Temples and scholars of divine magic are at a loss to explain a curse that has affected the entire region, and possibly the entire world.</p><p>The cause is a necromantic artifact called the Soulmonger, which is located somewhere in Chult, a mysterious peninsula far to the south, ringed with mountains and choked with rainforests.</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">TOA</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/tomb-annihilation</set>
			<set name="image">http://dnd.wizards.com/sites/default/files/media/styles/product_tabletop_left/public/images/product/65DX_ToA_ProductShot.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20170919</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" type="Source" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_XANATHARS_GUIDE_TO_EVERYTHING">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p><strong>Explore a wealth of new rules options for both players and Dungeon Masters in this supplement for the world’s greatest roleplaying game.</strong></p><p>The beholder Xanathar—Waterdeep’s most infamous crime lord—is known to hoard information on friend and foe alike. The beholder catalogs lore about adventurers and ponders methods to thwart them. Its twisted mind imagines that it can eventually record everything!</p><p>Xanathar's Guide to Everything is the first major expansion for fifth edition Dungeons &amp; Dragons, offering new rules and story options:</p><ul><li>Over twenty-five new subclasses for the character classes in the Player’s Handbook, including the Cavalier for the fighter, the Circle of Dreams for the druid, the Horizon Walker for the ranger, the Inquisitive for the rogue, and many more.</li><li>Dozens of new spells, a collection of racial feats, and a system to give your character a randomized backstory.</li><li>A variety of tools that provide Dungeon Masters fresh ways to use traps, magic items, downtime activities, and more—all designed to enhance a D&amp;D campaign and push it in new directions.</li></ul><p>Amid all this expansion material, Xanathar offers bizarre observations about whatever its eyestalks happen to glimpse. Pray they don’t come to rest on you.</p><p><strong>Beauty and guile are in the eyes of the beholder!</strong></p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">XGTE</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/xanathars-guide-everything</set>
			<set name="image">http://dnd.wizards.com/sites/default/files/media/styles/products_thumbnail/public/images/product/DX_Xanathar_ProductShotv2_0.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20171121</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Mordenkainen’s Tome of Foes" type="Source" source="Mordenkainen’s Tome of Foes" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_MORDENKAINENS_TOME_OF_FOES">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>This tome is built on the writings of the renowned wizard from the world of Greyhawk, gathered over a lifetime of research and scholarship. In his travels to other realms and other planes of existence, he has made many friends, and has risked his life an equal number of times, to amass the knowledge contained herein. In addition to Mordenkainen’s musings on the endless wars of the multiverse, the book contains game statistics for dozens of monsters: new demons and devils, several varieties of elves and duergar, and a vast array of other creatures from throughout the planes of existence.</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">MTOF</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/mordenkainens-tome-foes</set>
			<set name="image">http://dnd.wizards.com/sites/default/files/media/styles/product_tabletop_left/public/images/product/dkjch1825_ProductImg1.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20180529</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Waterdeep: Dragon Heist" type="Source" source="Waterdeep: Dragon Heist" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_WATERDEEP_DRAGON_HEIST">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p><strong>A fantastic treasure trove is yours for the taking in this adventure for the world's greatest roleplaying game.</strong></p><p>Famed explorer Volothamp Geddarm needs you to complete a simple quest. Thus begins a mad romp through the wards of Waterdeep as you uncover a villainous plot involving some of the city’s most influential figures.</p><p>A grand urban caper awaits you. Pit your skill and bravado against villains the likes of which you’ve never faced before, and let the dragon hunt begin!</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">WDDH</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/dragonheist</set>
			<set name="image">http://dnd.wizards.com/sites/default/files/media/styles/product_tabletop_left/public/images/product/BdENOuKjMg.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20180918</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Guildmasters’ Guide to Ravnica" type="Source" source="Guildmasters’ Guide to Ravnica" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_GUILDMASTERS_GUIDE_TO_RAVNICA">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p><strong><em>Explore a worldwide cityscape filled to the brim with adventure and intrigue in this campaign setting for the world’s greatest roleplaying game.</em></strong></p><p>A perpetual haze of dreary rain hangs over the spires of Ravnica. Bundled against the weather, the cosmopolitan citizens in all their fantastic diversity go about their daily business in bustling markets and shadowy back alleys. Through it all, ten guilds—crime syndicates, scientific institutions, church hierarchies, military forces, judicial courts, buzzing swarms, and rampaging gangs—vie for power, wealth, and influence.</p><p>These guilds are the foundation of power on Ravnica. They have existed for millennia, and each one has its own identity and civic function, its own diverse collection of races and creatures, and its own distinct subculture. Their history is a web of wars, intrigue, and political machinations as they have vied for control of the plane.</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">GGTR</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/guildmasters-guide-ravnica</set>
			<set name="image">http://dnd.wizards.com/sites/default/files/media/styles/product_tabletop_left/public/images/product/IXH6CK32k3.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20181120</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Waterdeep: Dungeon of the Mad Mage" type="Source" source="Waterdeep: Dungeon of the Mad Mage" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_WATERDEEP_DUNGEON_OF_THE_MAD_MAGE">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p><strong>Explore the mega-dungeon of Undermountain in this adventure for the world’s greatest roleplaying game.</strong></p><p>In the city of Waterdeep rests a tavern called the Yawning Portal, named after the gaping pit in its common room. At the bottom of this crumbling shaft is a labyrinthine dungeon shunned by all but the most daring adventurers. Known as Undermountain, this dungeon is the domain of the mad wizard Halaster Blackcloak. Long has the Mad Mage dwelt in these forlorn depths, seeding his lair with monsters, traps, and mysteries—to what end is a constant source of speculation and concern.</p><p>This adventure picks up where Waterdeep: Dragon Heist leaves off, taking characters of 5th level or higher all the way to 20th level should they explore the entirety of Halaster’s home. Twenty-three levels of Undermountain are detailed herein, along with the subterranean refuge of Skullport. Treasures and secrets abound, but tread with care!</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">WDDMM</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/waterdeep-dungeon-mad-mage</set>
			<set name="image">http://dnd.wizards.com/sites/default/files/media/styles/product_tabletop_left/public/images/product/PsqeYFr25s.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20181120</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ghosts of Saltmarch" type="Source" source="Ghosts of Saltmarch" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_GHOSTS_OF_SALTMARCH">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p><strong>Explore the waves above and the fathoms below in these watery adventures for the world’s greatest roleplaying game.</strong></p><p>Nestled on the coast of the Azure Sea is Saltmarsh, a sleepy fishing village that sits on the precipice of destruction. Smugglers guide their ships to hidden coves, willing to slit the throat of anyone foolhardy enough to cross their path. Cruel sahuagin gather beneath the waves, plotting to sweep away coastal cities. Drowned sailors stir to unnatural life, animated by dark magic and sent forth in search of revenge. The cult of a forbidden god extends its reach outward from a decaying port, hungry for fresh victims and willing recruits. While Saltmarsh slumbers, the evils that seek to plunder it grow stronger. Heroes must arise to keep the waves safe!</p><p>Hoist your sails, pull up anchor, and set a course for adventure!</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">GOS</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/ghosts-saltmarsh</set>
			<set name="image">http://dnd.wizards.com/sites/default/files/media/styles/product_tabletop_left/public/images/product/qwjuqh323.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20190521</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Lost Laboratory of Kwalish" type="Source" source="Lost Laboratory of Kwalish" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_LOST_LABORATORY_OF_KWALISH">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p><strong>In centuries long past, a common scholar named Kwalish took an unlikely path to becoming one of the most powerful arcane inventors of all time.!</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">LLOK</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/lost-laboratory-kwalish</set>
			<set name="image">http://dnd.wizards.com/sites/default/files/media/styles/product_tabletop_left/public/images/product/jQaanTEhph.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20181110</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Acquisitions Incorporated" type="Source" source="Acquisitions Incorporated" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_ACQUISITIONS_INCORPORATED">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p><strong>Explore a wealth of peril and personalities for the world’s greatest roleplaying game.</strong></p><p>When you’re just starting out in the adventuring business, it might be nice to have a leg up. It can be a big help to have access to the powerful artifacts, expertise, and jobs that Acquisitions Incorporated (Acq Inc) has to offer a new franchise. Join Omin Dran, Jim Darkmagic, and Viari like never before with the new Acquisitions Incorporated campaign book for Dungeons & Dragons!</p><p>Set yourself up for success when pursuing your own fantasy-business endeavors, using all the ingredients you need to include Acquisitions Incorporated in your D&D campaign, to establish your own franchise, and take on specialized roles therein. Plus, there are always openings coming available… Just try not to think about why.</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">ACQINC</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/acqinc</set>
			<set name="image">http://dnd.wizards.com/sites/default/files/media/styles/product_tabletop_left/public/images/product/DnD_AcqInc_Prod.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast, Penny Arcade</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20190618</set>
		</setters>
	</element>


	<!-- Adventurers League -->
	<element name="Adventurers League: Tyranny of Dragons" type="Source" source="Adventurers League: Tyranny of Dragons" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_AL_TYRANNY_OF_DRAGONS">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>The D&amp;D Adventurers League is an ongoing official campaign for Dungeons &amp; Dragons. It uses the fifth edition Dungeons &amp; Dragons rules, and features the Forgotten Realms setting. You can play D&amp;D Adventurers League games literally anywhere. Players use the fifth edition rules to create a character and bring that character to games anywhere D&amp;D Adventurers League play is happening.</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">ALTOD</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/playevents/organized-play</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="league">true</set>
			<set name="release">20150101</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Adventurers League: Elemental Evil" type="Source" source="Adventurers League: Elemental Evil" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_AL_ELEMENTAL_EVIL">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>The D&amp;D Adventurers League is an ongoing official campaign for Dungeons &amp; Dragons. It uses the fifth edition Dungeons &amp; Dragons rules, and features the Forgotten Realms setting. You can play D&amp;D Adventurers League games literally anywhere. Players use the fifth edition rules to create a character and bring that character to games anywhere D&amp;D Adventurers League play is happening.</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">ALEE</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/playevents/organized-play</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="league">true</set>
			<set name="release">20150102</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Adventurers League: Rage of Demons" type="Source" source="Adventurers League: Rage of Demons" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_AL_RAGE_OF_DEMONS">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>The D&amp;D Adventurers League is an ongoing official campaign for Dungeons &amp; Dragons. It uses the fifth edition Dungeons &amp; Dragons rules, and features the Forgotten Realms setting. You can play D&amp;D Adventurers League games literally anywhere. Players use the fifth edition rules to create a character and bring that character to games anywhere D&amp;D Adventurers League play is happening.</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">ALROD</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/playevents/organized-play</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="league">true</set>
			<set name="release">20150103</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Adventurers League: Curse of Strahd" type="Source" source="Adventurers League: Curse of Strahd" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_AL_CURSE_OF_STRAHD">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>The D&amp;D Adventurers League is an ongoing official campaign for Dungeons &amp; Dragons. It uses the fifth edition Dungeons &amp; Dragons rules, and features the Forgotten Realms setting. You can play D&amp;D Adventurers League games literally anywhere. Players use the fifth edition rules to create a character and bring that character to games anywhere D&amp;D Adventurers League play is happening.</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">ALCOS</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/playevents/organized-play</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="league">true</set>
			<set name="release">20150104</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Adventurers League: Storm King’s Thunder" type="Source" source="Adventurers League: Storm King’s Thunder" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_AL_STORM_KINGS_THUNDER">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>The D&amp;D Adventurers League is an ongoing official campaign for Dungeons &amp; Dragons. It uses the fifth edition Dungeons &amp; Dragons rules, and features the Forgotten Realms setting. You can play D&amp;D Adventurers League games literally anywhere. Players use the fifth edition rules to create a character and bring that character to games anywhere D&amp;D Adventurers League play is happening.</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">ALSKT</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/playevents/organized-play</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="league">true</set>
			<set name="release">20150105</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Adventurers League: Tales from the Yawning Portal" type="Source" source="Adventurers League: Tales from the Yawning Portal" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_AL_TALES_FROM_THE_YAWNING_PORTAL">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>The D&amp;D Adventurers League is an ongoing official campaign for Dungeons &amp; Dragons. It uses the fifth edition Dungeons &amp; Dragons rules, and features the Forgotten Realms setting. You can play D&amp;D Adventurers League games literally anywhere. Players use the fifth edition rules to create a character and bring that character to games anywhere D&amp;D Adventurers League play is happening.</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">ALTOTYP</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/playevents/organized-play</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="league">true</set>
			<set name="release">20150106</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Adventurers League: Tomb of Annihilation" type="Source" source="Adventurers League: Tomb of Annihilation" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_AL_TOMB_OF_ANNIHILATION">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>The D&amp;D Adventurers League is an ongoing official campaign for Dungeons &amp; Dragons. It uses the fifth edition Dungeons &amp; Dragons rules, and features the Forgotten Realms setting. You can play D&amp;D Adventurers League games literally anywhere. Players use the fifth edition rules to create a character and bring that character to games anywhere D&amp;D Adventurers League play is happening.</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">ALTOA</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/playevents/organized-play</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="league">true</set>
			<set name="release">20150107</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Adventurers League: Waterdeep" type="Source" source="Adventurers League: Waterdeep" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_AL_WATERDEEP">
		<description>
			<![CDATA[<p>The D&amp;D Adventurers League is an ongoing official campaign for Dungeons &amp; Dragons. It uses the fifth edition Dungeons &amp; Dragons rules, and features the Forgotten Realms setting. You can play D&amp;D Adventurers League games literally anywhere. Players use the fifth edition rules to create a character and bring that character to games anywhere D&amp;D Adventurers League play is happening.</p>]]>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">ALWD</set>
			<set name="url">http://dnd.wizards.com/playevents/organized-play</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="league">true</set>
			<set name="release">20150108</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>