<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Unearthed Arcana: Barbarian and Monk</name>
        <description>The barbarian receives a new Primal Path feature: Path of the Wild Soul. Meanwhile the monk gains a new Monastic Tradition feature: the Way of the Astral Self.</description>
        <author url="https://dnd.wizards.com/articles/unearthed-arcana/barbarian-and-monk">Wizards of the Coast</author>
        <update version="0.0.2">
            <file name="20190815.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/unearthed-arcana/2019/20190815.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
	<element name="Unearthed Arcana: Barbarian and Monk" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_UNEARTHED_ARCANA_20190815">
		<description>
			<p>The barbarian receives a new Primal Path feature: Path of the Wild Soul. Meanwhile the monk gains a new Monastic Tradition feature: the Way of the Astral Self.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">UA20190815</set>
			<set name="url">https://dnd.wizards.com/articles/unearthed-arcana/barbarian-and-monk</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="playtest">true</set>
			<set name="release">20190815</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

    <!-- Way of the Astral Self-->
    <element name="Way of the Astral Self" type="Archetype" source="Unearthed Arcana: Barbarian and Monk" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_WAY_OF_THE_ASTRAL_SELF">
        <supports>Monastic Tradition</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Monks of the Way of the Astral Self have an internal struggle with their ki. They see their mystical energy as a representation of their true form, an astral self. This form has the capacity to be a force of good or destruction, with some monasteries training students to either temper their nature or embrace their impulses. </p>
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ASTRAL_SELF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMS_OF_THE_ASTRAL_SELF" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ASTRAL_SELF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VISAGE_OF_THE_ASTRAL_SELF" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ASTRAL_SELF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AWAKENING_OF_THE_ASTRAL_SELF" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_ASTRAL_SELF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COMPLETE_ASTRAL_SELF" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Monks of the Way of the Astral Self have an internal struggle with their ki.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ASTRAL_SELF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMS_OF_THE_ASTRAL_SELF" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ASTRAL_SELF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VISAGE_OF_THE_ASTRAL_SELF" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ASTRAL_SELF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AWAKENING_OF_THE_ASTRAL_SELF" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ASTRAL_SELF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COMPLETE_ASTRAL_SELF" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Arms of the Astral Self" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Barbarian and Monk" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ASTRAL_SELF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARMS_OF_THE_ASTRAL_SELF">
        <description>
            <p>At 3rd level, your mastery of your ki allows you to summon a portion of your astral self. On your turn, you can spend 2 ki points as a bonus action to summon the arms of your astral self for 10 minutes. These spectral arms hover near your shoulders. You determine the arms’ appearance based on the qualities of your character.</p>
            <p class="indent">While your astral arms are summoned, you gain the following benefits:</p>
            <ul>
            <li>You can use your Wisdom modifier in place of your Strength modifier when making Strength checks and Strength saving throws.</li>
            <li>The arms are monk weapons and have a reach of 10 feet. The arms deal radiant or necrotic damage (your choice). When you attack with the arms, you can use your Wisdom modifier instead of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls.</li>
            <li>Immediately after you use the Attack action with your astral arms on your turn, you can make one extra attack with your astral arms as a bonus action. The number of extra attacks increases when you reach certain levels in this class, increasing to two at 11th level and three at 17th level.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>For 2 Ki points you can summon Astral Arms for the next 10 minutes. With these arms you can use your wisdom modifier instead of strength when making strength checks and saving throws. The arms are Monk weapons and have a reach of 10 ft. dealing radiant or necrotic damage, you can use your wisdom modifier for attacks made with the arms. When you attack with your arms you can use a bonus action to attack again.</description>
            <description level="11">For 2 Ki points you can summon Astral Arms for the next 10 minutes. With these arms you can use your wisdom modifier instead of strength when making strength checks and saving throws. The arms are Monk weapons and have a reach of 10 ft. dealing radiant or necrotic damage, you can use your wisdom modifier for attacks made with the arms. When you attack with your arms you can use a bonus action to attack again twice.</description>
            <description level="17">For 2 Ki points you can summon Astral Arms for the next 10 minutes. With these arms you can use your wisdom modifier instead of strength when making strength checks and saving throws. The arms are Monk weapons and have a reach of 10 ft. dealing radiant or necrotic damage, you can use your wisdom modifier for attacks made with the arms. When you attack with your arms you can use a bonus action to attack again three times.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Visage of the Astral Self" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Barbarian and Monk" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ASTRAL_SELF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_VISAGE_OF_THE_ASTRAL_SELF">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 6th level, you can summon the visage of your astral self. On your turn, you can spend 1 ki point as a bonus action, or as part of summoning your astral arms, to summon this visage for 10 minutes. The spectral visage covers your face like a helmet or mask. You determine its appearance based on the qualities of your character.</p>
            <p class="indent">While your visage is summoned, you gain the following benefits.</p>
            <ul>
            <li><b>Wisdom of the Spirit. </b>You have advantage on Wisdom (Insight) and Charisma (Intimidation) checks.</li>
            <li><b>Astral Sight. </b>You can see normally in darkness, both magical and nonmagical, to a distance of 120 feet.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can spend 1 Ki point to summon a visage for 10 minutes that grants you advantage on Insight and Intimidation checks, and also giving you vision in magical and nonmagical darkness for up to 120 feet. This can be summoned at the same time as the Arms of the Astral Self.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Awakening of the Astral Self" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Barbarian and Monk" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ASTRAL_SELF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_AWAKENING_OF_THE_ASTRAL_SELF">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 11th level, you tap into the greater power of your astral self. While you have both your astral arms and visage summoned, you gain the following benefits.</p>
            <ul>
            <li><b>Deflect Energy. </b>When you take acid, cold, fire, lightning, or force damage, you can use your reaction to deflect it. When you do so, the damage you take is reduced by 1d10 + your Wisdom modifier + your monk level.</li>
            <li><b>Empowered Arms. </b>Once on each of your turns when you hit a target with your astral arms, you can deal extra damage to the target equal to your Martial Arts die.</li>
            <li><b>Word of the Sprit. </b>When you speak through your visage, you can direct your words to a creature of your choice that you can see within 30 feet of you, making it so only that creature can hear you. Alternatively, you can amplify your voice so that all creatures within 600 feet can hear you.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you have both your Astral Arms and Astral Visage summoned you gain additional benefits. When you take acid, cold, fire, lightning or force damage you can use your reaction to reduce it by 1d10 + {{astral:energy deflect}}. Once per turn when you hit a target with your astral arms you can deal {{martial arts:dice}} extra damage. When you speak through your Visage you can either direct your words towards a creature within 30 feet or allow all creatures within 600ft to hear you.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="astral:energy deflect" value="level:monk" />
            <stat name="astral:energy deflect" value="wisdom:modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Complete Astral Self" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Barbarian and Monk" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ASTRAL_SELF_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_COMPLETE_ASTRAL_SELF">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 17th level, your connection to your astral self is complete, allowing you summon it entirely. On your turn, you can spend 10 ki points as a bonus action to summon the arms, visage, and body of your astral self for 10 minutes. This spectral body covers your physical form like a suit of armor, connecting with the arms and visage. You determine its appearance based on the qualities of your character.</p>
            <p class="indent">While your astral self is summoned, you gain the following benefits.</p>
            <ul>
            <li><b>Armor of the Spirit. </b>You gain a +2 bonus to AC while you aren’t incapacitated.</li>
            <li><b>Astral Barrage. </b>Whenever you use the Extra Attack feature to attack twice, you can instead attack three times using your astral arms.</li>
            <li><b>Ki Consumption. </b>When a creature within 10 feet of you is reduced to 0 hit points, you can use your reaction to regain ki points equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum 1).</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can spend 10 Ki points to summon your Astral Arms, Visage and Body for the next 10 minutes. When you do this you gain the following benefits. +2 to AC. When you use extra attack with your Astral Arms you can attack 3 times instead. When a creature within 10 ft. of you is reduced to 0 HP you can use your reaction to regain {{wisdom:modifier}} Ki points.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Path of the Wild Soul" type="Archetype" source="Unearthed Arcana: Barbarian and Monk" id="ID_WOTC_UA_ARCHETYPE_PATH_OF_THE_WILD_SOUL">
        <supports>Primal Path</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The realm of the Feywild abounds with beauty, unpredictable emotion, and rampant magic. A barbarian exposed to this realm feels emotions powerfully and magic saturates their body. When a barbarian who follows this path rages, it is a bellowing roar for freedom, an explosion of expression, manifesting in unpredictable ways.</p>
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_WILD_SOUL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LINGERING_MAGIC" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_WILD_SOUL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WILD_SURGE" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_WILD_SOUL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGIC_RESERVE" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_WILD_SOUL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANE_REBUKE" />
            <div element="ID_WOTC_UA_WILD_SOUL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHAOTIC_FURY" />
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description></description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_WILD_SOUL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LINGERING_MAGIC" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_WILD_SOUL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WILD_SURGE" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_WILD_SOUL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGIC_RESERVE" level="6" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_WILD_SOUL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANE_REBUKE" level="10" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA_WILD_SOUL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHAOTIC_FURY" level="14" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Lingering Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Barbarian and Monk" id="ID_WOTC_UA_WILD_SOUL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_LINGERING_MAGIC">
        <description>
            <p>At 3rd level, your body reacts to the presence of magic. You can cast the detect magic spell without using a spell slot or components. Constitution is your spellcasting ability for this spell. You faintly glow a color corresponding to the school of magic you detect (you choose the colors).</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Constitution modifier (minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="{{constitution:modifier}}/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast Detect Magic. Spellcasting: Constitution.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Wild Surge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Barbarian and Monk" id="ID_WOTC_UA_WILD_SOUL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_WILD_SURGE">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 3rd level, magic erupts from you as you rage. When you enter your rage, roll on the Wild Surge table to determine the magical effect produced.</p>
            <p class="indent">If the wild surge requires a saving throw, the DC equals 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier.</p>
            <h6>WILD SURGE</h6>
            <table>
				<thead><tr><td>d8</td><td>Effect</td></tr></thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>Necrotic energy bursts from you. Each creature within 30 feet of you takes 1d10 necrotic damage, and you gain temporary hit points equal to the sum of the necrotic damage dealt to the creatures</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>You teleport up to 20 feet to an unoccupied space you can see. Until your rage ends, you can activate this effect again on each of your turns as a bonus action.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>You conjure 1d4 intangible spirits that look like flumphs in unoccupied spaces within 30 feet of you. Each spirit immediately flies 30 feet in a random direction. At the end of your turn, all spirits explode and each creature within 5 feet of one or more of them must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 2d8 force damage.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>Arcane energy enshrouds you. Until your rage ends, you gain a +2 bonus to AC, and whenever a creature within 10 feet of you hits you with an attack, that creature takes force damage equal to your Constitution modifier</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>Plant life temporarily grows around you: until your rage ends, the ground within 10 feet of you is difficult terrain.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>Arcane energy taps into the minds of those around you. Each creature within 30 feet of you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or you see a glimpse of the creature’s thoughts, learning how it plans to attack you. As a result, the creature has disadvantage on attack rolls against you until the start of your next turn.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>7</td><td>Shadows weave around a weapon of your choice you are holding. Until your rage ends, your weapon deals psychic damage instead of its bludgeoning, slashing, or piercing damage, and it gains the light and thrown properties with a normal range of 20 feet and a long range of 60 feet. If you drop the weapon or throw it, the weapon dissipates and reappears in your hand at the end of your turn.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>8</td><td>A beam of brilliant light lances from your chest in a 5-foot-wide, 60-foot-long line. Each creature in the line must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or take 2d8 radiant damage and be blinded until the start of your next turn.</td></tr>
			</table>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you rage, roll on the Wild Surge Table. The save DC is {{wild surge:dc}}</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="wild surge:dc" value="8" />
            <stat name="wild surge:dc" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="wild surge:dc" value="constitution:modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Magic Reserve" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Barbarian and Monk" id="ID_WOTC_UA_WILD_SOUL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MAGIC_RESERVE">
        <description>
            <p>At 6th level, you can channel the magic surging inside you into other creatures. As an action, you can touch a creature and roll a d4. The creature recovers an expended spell slot of a level equal to the number rolled. If the creature you touch can’t recover a spell slot of that level, the creature instead gains temporary hit points equal to five times the number rolled.</p>
            <p class="indent">You take force damage equal to five times the number rolled.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you reach 14th level in this class, you increase the die to a d6.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action">
            <description>Touch a creature and roll a d4. The creature regains an expended spell slot equal to the level rolled. If the creature cannot regain the spell slot they gain temporary HP equal to 5 times the number rolled. You take force damage equal to the number rolled.</description>
            <description level="14">Touch a creature and roll a d6. The creature regains an expended spell slot equal to the level rolled. If the creature cannot regain the spell slot they gain temporary HP equal to 5 times the number rolled. You take force damage equal to the number rolled.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Arcane Rebuke" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Barbarian and Monk" id="ID_WOTC_UA_WILD_SOUL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ARCANE_REBUKE">
        <description>
            <p>At 10th level, the magic crackling within your soul lashes out. When a creature forces you to make a saving throw while you are raging, you can use your reaction to deal 3d6 force damage to that creature.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Reaction">
            <description>When you are forced to make a saving throw while you are raging, deal 3d6 force damage against the creature.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Chaotic Fury" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Barbarian and Monk" id="ID_WOTC_UA_WILD_SOUL_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_CHAOTIC_FURY">
        <description>
            <p>At 14th level, you become a wellspring of wild magic while you are raging. As a bonus action, you can reroll on the Wild Surge table, replacing your current effect with the new one.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Bonus Action">
            <description>While raging, you can reroll on the Wild Surge Table replacing your current effect with the new one.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
</elements>