<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Strojanow Prisoner</name>
        <description>The Strojanow Prisoner background from Curse of Strahd</description>
        <author url="http://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/curse-strahd">Wizards of the Coast</author>
        <update version="0.0.4">
            <file name="background-strojanowprisoner.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/supplements/curse-of-strahd/backgrounds/background-strojanowprisoner.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    <element name="Stojanow Prisoner" type="Background" source="Adventurers League: Curse of Strahd" id="ID_WOTC_COS_BACKGROUND_STOJANOW_PRISONER">
        <description>
            <p>"We need to leave, now!” Those words still haunt your dreams at night. When everyone was fleeing Phlan, you choose to stay. Whether out of an emotional attachment, or pursuit of riches, you made the decision that would affect the rest of your life. Food became scarcer for those without connections. You became a beggar and to stay alive you bartered information to any interested party with food or gold to spare. You were good at what you did, and thought you were invincible. That changed when you were captured by the Tears of Virulence, the soldiers of Vorgansharax, the Maimed Virulence, for selling secrets to those bent on overthrowing the dragon. They locked you in the cells of Stojanow Gate. The first weeks you hoped to stay alive. As the weeks turned into months, and the interrogations continued you began to pray for death.</p>
            <p>
                <b>Skill Proficiencies: </b>Deception, Perception<br/>
                <b>Tool Proficiencies: </b> One type of gaming set, thieves’ tools<br/>
                <b>Equipment:</b> A small knife, a set of common clothes, a trinket from the life you stayed behind to defend, a belt pouch with 10 gp
            </p>
            <div element="ID_WOTC_COS_BACKGROUND_STOJANOW_PRISONER_FEATURE_EXCONVICT" />
            <h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
            <!-- ? -->
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="short">Deception, Perceptions, Gaming Set, Thieves’ Tools</set>
        </setters>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_DECEPTION" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION" />
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Gaming Set (Stojanow Prisoner)" supports="Gaming Set"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_THIEVES_TOOLS" />
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_WOTC_COS_BACKGROUND_STOJANOW_PRISONER_FEATURE_EXCONVICT" />
            <select name="Personality Trait" type="List" number="2">
                <item id="1">I am a bully; others will suffer as I have.</item>
                <item id="2">I always say yes even when I mean no; it’s just easier.</item>
                <item id="3">I aim to misbehave.</item>
                <item id="4">I go out of my way to frustrate or anger those in power.</item>
                <item id="5">I strive to obey the law. I will never again make the mistake of going against authority.</item>
                <item id="6">I always plan everything out. The one time I let others plan things it did not end well for me.</item>
                <item id="7">I take blame to protect others from pain.</item>
                <item id="8">I hoard information, you never know what may come in handy.</item>
            </select>
            <select name="Ideal" type="List">
                <item id="1">Loss: I freely give those who offend me what was so brutally denied me, death. (Chaos)</item>
                <item id="2">Dedication: I never betray those who trust me. (Law)</item>
                <item id="3">Vengeance: I use any means to get information I need; I have been well taught. (Evil)</item>
                <item id="4">Redemption: Everyone deserves a second chance. (Good)</item>
                <item id="5">Resilience: I can survive any challenge (Any)</item>
                <item id="6">Leadership: The best teams are made up of those that society has discarded.</item>
            </select>
            <select name="Bond" type="List">
                <item id="1">I take up arms to help establish a free Phlan.</item>
                <item id="2">The horrors of my time in Stojanow haunt my dreams, only after a day of hard work can I find sleep.</item>
                <item id="3">I am indebted to those who freed me from prison, I will repay this debt.</item>
                <item id="4">My torturer survived the attack that set me free, I will find him/her.</item>
                <item id="5">I will not rest while others suffer fates similar to mine.</item>
                <item id="6">I am searching for a way to heal the scars of Stojanow, both physical and emotional.</item>
            </select>
            <select name="Flaw" type="List">
                <item id="1">During stressful times, I find myself crying for no reason.</item>
                <item id="2">My nerve endings are shot from the interrogations; I am numb to all but the harshest touch.</item>
                <item id="3">I am incapable of standing up for myself.</item>
                <item id="4">I folded under the torture, and gave information that I promised would be kept secret. My life would be in jeopardy if others found out.</item>
                <item id="5">Survival is worth more than friendship.</item>
                <item id="6">The ghosts from my past hinder my actions.</item>
            </select>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Feature: Ex-Convict" type="Background Feature" source="Adventurers League: Curse of Strahd" id="ID_WOTC_COS_BACKGROUND_STOJANOW_PRISONER_FEATURE_EXCONVICT">
		<supports>Background Feature</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The knowledge gained during your incarceration lets you gain insight into local guards and jailors. You know which will accept bribes, or look the other way for you. You can also seek shelter for yourself from authorities with other criminals in the area.</p>
        </description>
		<sheet alt="Ex-Convict" />
    </element>
</elements>