<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <info>
        <name>Kor</name>
        <description>Kor Race from Planeshift: Zendikar</description>
        <author url="https://media.wizards.com/2016/downloads/magic/Plane%20Shift%20Zendikar.pdf">Planeshift: Zendikar</author>
        <update version="0.0.3">
            <file name="race-kor.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/unearthed-arcana/planeshift/zendikar/race-kor.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    
    <element name="Kor" type="Race" source="Plane Shift: Zendikar" id="ID_WOTC_PSZ_RACE_KOR">
        <description>
            <p>Deeply reverent of the land and its sacred sites, the nomadic kor live a spare existence defined by their constant travels. Masters of ropes and hooks, they scale sheer cliffs and cross yawning chasms with such skill and agility that they sometimes seem almost to take flight.</p>
            <p class="indent">Kor are associated with white mana, and their wizards and clerics employ spells of healing, of banishing the dark, and of protection. Their personalities and ideals also mesh with the characteristics of white mana in their emphasis on an ordered, harmonious community with strong traditions binding its members together.</p>
            <h4>SLENDER AND SILENT</h4>
            <p>Kor are tall, slender humanoids with light hair and gray, blue-gray, or ivory skin. All kor have slightly pointed ears, and males have short, fleshy barbels on their chins. They paint softly glowing geometric patterns on their faces and bodies, suggestive of the shapes and design of the hedrons that appear across Zendikar. Their clothing tends to leave their arms and shoulders free to facilitate climbing, and they keep most of their gear in pouches and slings at their waists.</p>
            <p class="indent">The kor have a nonverbal language of hand signs and gestures that allows communication despite significant distance (particularly when augmented with whirling ropes) or howling winds. They also use this sign language among themselves when they wish to avoid being overheard, giving rise to misguided rumors that they are incapable of speech. When they do speak, they typically use as few words as possible to convey their meaning.</p>
            <h4>KOR TRAITS</h4>
            <p>Kor are athletic climbers, known for their use of rope to swing and climb through the dizzying vertical terrain of Zendikar. Your kor character has these traits.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Ability Score Increase. </i></b>Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Wisdom score increases by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Age. </i></b>Kor mature at the same rate as humans and live about as long.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Alignment. </i></b>Most kor are lawful good, with a strong dedication to community and the traditions of their ancestors.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Size. </i></b>Kor average nearly 6 feet tall, but are much lighter and more slender than humans. Your size is Medium.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Speed. </i></b>Your base walking speed is 30 feet. You also have a climbing speed of 30 feet as long as you are not encumbered or wearing heavy armor.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Kor Climbing. </i></b>You have proficiency in the Athletics and Acrobatics skills.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Lucky. </i></b>When you roll a 1 on an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Brave. </i></b>You have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Languages. </i></b>You can speak, read, and write Common, and communicate in the silent speech of the kor.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <stat name="dexterity" value="2" />
            <stat name="wisdom" value="1" />
            <stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
            <stat name="innate speed:climb" value="30" bonus="base" equipped="![armor:heavy]" />
            <grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_WOTC_PSZ_LANGUAGE_KOR" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_LUCKY" />
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_BRAVE" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS" />
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS" />
        </rules>
    </element>

    <!-- Languages -->
    <element name="Kor" type="Language" source="Plane Shift: Zendikar" id="ID_WOTC_PSZ_LANGUAGE_KOR">
        <description>
            <p>The silent language of the Kor.</p>
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="exotic">true</set>
            <set name="speakers">Kor</set>
            <set name="script">Kor</set>
        </setters>
    </element>


</elements>