<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Elf Subraces</name>
		<description>Elf Subrace from Planeshift: Zendikar</description>
		<author url="https://media.wizards.com/2016/downloads/magic/Plane%20Shift%20Zendikar.pdf">Planeshift: Zendikar</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="subrace-elf-zendikar.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/unearthed-arcana/planeshift/zendikar/subrace-elf-zendikar.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<!-- Plane Shift Exclusion -->
	<element name="Plane Shift Zendikar Subraces" type="Grants" source="Core" id="ID_UA_PSK_GRANTS_ELF_SUBRACE" />

	<!-- Tajuru Elf -->
	<element name="Tajuru Elf" type="Sub Race" source="Plane Shift: Zendikar" id="ID_WOTC_PSK_SUBRACE_TAJURU_ELF">
		<supports>Elf</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The Tajuru nation is the largest of the three main elven nations, concentrated in Murasa and spread across other parts of Zendikar as hundreds of far-flung clans. Tajuru elves are the most open to people of other races, seeing their skills and perspectives as valuable new tools for survival. The Tajuru are also more open to new lifestyles, be it living in a mountaintop citadel or roaming grassy plains.</p>
			<h4>TAJURU ELF TRAITS</h4>
			<p>Tajuru elves gain the following traits</p>
			<p>
				<span class="feature">Ability Score Increase. </span>You lose the Dexterity increase but increase Wisdom by 2 and Charisma by 1.<br />
				<span class="feature">Skill Versatility. </span>You gain proficiency in any combination of two skills or tools of your choice.  <br />
			</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_UA_PSK_GRANTS_ELF_SUBRACE" />
			<stat name="wisdom" value="2" />
			<stat name="charisma" value="1" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Proficiency (Tajuru Elf)" supports="Tool||Skill" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<!-- Joraga Elf -->
	<element name="Joraga Elf" type="Sub Race" source="Plane Shift: Zendikar" id="ID_WOTC_PSK_SUBRACE_JORAGA_ELF">
		<supports>Elf</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The elves of the imperious Joraga nation of Bala Ged have little respect for any other race of Zendikar—or even for other elves. The survival of their nation and its traditions is the Joraga elves’ only goal, and they view the influence of others as a weakness. The Joraga eschew the goods and habits of others, even avoiding the pathways blazed by the Tajuru when possible. Many view the nomadic Joraga clans as little more than bands of roving murderers, but a complex culture hides behind those clans’ aggressive exterior</p>
			<h4>JORAGA ELF TRAITS</h4>
			<p>Joraga elves gain the following traits</p>
			<p>
				<span class="feature">Ability Score Increase. </span>You lose the Dexterity increase but increase Wisdom by 2 and Dexterity by 1.<br />
				<span class="feature">Elf Weapon Training.</span>You have proficiency with the longsword, shortsword, shortbow, and longbow.<br />
				<span class="feature">Fleet of Foot. </span>Your base walking speed increases to 35 feet.  <br />
				<span class="feature">Mask of the Wild. </span>You can attempt to hide even when you are only lightly obscured by foliage, heavy rain, falling snow, mist, and other natural phenomena.  <br />
			</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_UA_PSK_GRANTS_ELF_SUBRACE" />
			<stat name="wisdom" value="2" />
			<stat name="dexterity" value="1" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_WEAPON_TRAINING" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_FLEET_OF_FOOT" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_MASK_OF_THE_WILD" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<!-- Mul Daya -->
	<element name="Mul Daya Elf" type="Sub Race" source="Plane Shift: Zendikar" id="ID_WOTC_PSK_SUBRACE_MUL_DAYA_ELF">
		<supports>Elf</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Elves of the Mul Daya nation of Bala Ged are set apart from other elves by their relationship with the spirits of their elven ancestors. To the Mul Daya, the spirit world and the mortal realm are different only in terms of their tangibility. Death and the spirits of the dead are as much a part of the lives of the Mul Daya as is the natural world. This is not a macabre sentiment to the elves; they simply view it as the truest sense of the natural order.</p>
			<p class="indent">Mul Daya elves can often be recognized by their face painting and tattooing. Many Mul Daya decorate their skins with an enwrapping vine motif, and make use of poisons and acids collected at great cost from strange creatures and plants in the depths of Kazandu.</p>
			<h4>MUL DAYA ELF TRAITS</h4>
			<p>Mul Daya elves gain the following traits</p>
			<p>
				<span class="feature">Ability Score Increase. </span>You lose the Dexterity increase but increase Wisdom by 2 and Strength by 1.<br />
				<span class="feature">Elf Weapon Training.</span>You have proficiency with the longsword, shortsword, shortbow, and longbow.<br />
				<span class="feature">Superior Darkvision. </span>Your darkvision has a radius of 120 feet.  <br />
				<span class="feature">Sunlight Sensitivity. </span>You have disadvantage on attack rolls and on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight when you, the target of your attack, or whatever you are trying to perceive is in direct sunlight. <br />
				<span class="feature">Mul Daya Magic. </span>You know the chill touch cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the hex spell once with this trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. When you reach 5th level, you can cast the darkness spell once with this trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.<br />
			</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_UA_PSK_GRANTS_ELF_SUBRACE" />
			<stat name="wisdom" value="2" />
			<stat name="strength" value="1" />
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_SUPERIORDARKVISION" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_ELF_WEAPON_TRAINING" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_SUNLIGHT_SENSITIVITY" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_PSK_RACIAL_TRAIT_MUL_DAYA_MAGIC" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Mul Daya Magic" type="Racial Trait" source="Plane Shift: Zendikar" id="ID_WOTC_PSK_RACIAL_TRAIT_MUL_DAYA_MAGIC">
		<description>
			<p>You know the chill touch cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the hex spell once with this trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. When you reach 5th level, you can cast the darkness spell once with this trait and regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Chill Touch. (Spellcasting: Wisdom)</description>
			<description level="3">1/day Chill Touch and Hex. (Spellcasting: Wisdom)</description>
			<description level="5">1/day Chill Touch, Hex, and Darkness. (Spellcasting: Wisdom)</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHILL_TOUCH" level="1" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEX" level="3" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DARKNESS" level="5" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>