<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<update version="0.1">
			<file name="source.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/supplements/rime-of-the-frostmaiden/source.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>	
	<element name="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_ICEWIND_DALE_RIME_OF_THE_FROSTMAIDEN">
		<description>			
			<p><strong><em>Feel the cold touch of death in this adventure for the world’s greatest roleplaying game.</em></strong></p>
			<p>In Icewind Dale, adventure is a dish best served cold.</p>
			<p>Beneath the unyielding night sky, you stand before a towering glacier and recite an ancient rhyme, causing a crack to form in the great wall of ice. Beyond this yawning fissure, the Caves of Hunger await. And past this icy dungeon is a secret so old and terrifying that few dare speak of it. The mad wizards of the Arcane Brotherhood long to possess that which the god of winter’s wrath has so coldly preserved—as do you! What fantastic secrets and treasures are entombed in the sunless heart of the glacier, and what will their discovery mean for the denizens of Icewind Dale? Can you save Ten-Towns from the Frostmaiden’s everlasting night?</p>
			<p>Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden is a tale of dark terror that revisits the forlorn, flickering candlelights of civilization known as Ten-Towns and sheds light on the many bone-chilling locations that surround these frontier settlements.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">ROTF</set>
			<set name="url">https://dnd.wizards.com/products/tabletop-games/rpg-products/icewind-dale-rime-frostmaiden</set>
			<set name="image">https://media.dnd.wizards.com/styles/product_tabletop_left/public/images/product/YiKwcXaQkJ.png</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="supplement">true</set>
			<set name="release">20200915</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Blade of Disaster" type="Spell" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_SPELL_BLADE_OF_DISASTER">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You create a blade-shaped planar rift about 3 feet long in an unoccupied space you can see within range. The blade lasts for the duration. When you cast this spell, you can make up to two melee spell attacks with the blade, each one against a creature, loose object, or structure within 5 feet of the blade. On a hit, the target takes 4d12 force damage. This attack scores a critical hit if the number on the d20 is 18 or higher. On a critical hit, the blade deals an extra 8d12 force damage (for a total of 12d12 force damage).</p>
			<p class="indent">As a bonus action on your turn, you can move the blade up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see and then make up to two melee spell attacks with it again.</p>
			<p class="indent">The blade can harmlessly pass through any barrier, including a wall of force.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">9</set>
			<set name="school">Conjuration</set>
			<set name="time">1 bonus action</set>
			<set name="range">60 feet</set>
			<set name="duration">Concentration, up to 1 minute</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"></set>
			<set name="isConcentration">true</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Create Magen" type="Spell" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_SPELL_CREATE_MAGEN">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>While casting the spell, you place a vial of quicksilver in the chest of a life-sized human doll stuffed with ash or dust. You then stitch up the doll and drip your blood on it. At the end of the casting, you tap the doll with a crystal rod, transforming it into a magen clothed in whatever the doll was wearing. The type of magen is chosen by you during the casting of the spell. See appendix C for different kinds of magen and their statistics.</p>
			<p class="indent">When the magen appears, your hit point maximum decreases by an amount equal to the magen's challenge rating (minimum reduction of 1). Only a wish spell can undo this reduction to your hit point maximum.</p>
			<p class="indent">Any magen you create with this spell obeys your commands without question.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">7</set>
			<set name="school">Transmutation</set>
			<set name="time">1 hour</set>
			<set name="range">Touch</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
			<set name="materialComponent">a vial of quicksilver worth 500 gp and a life-sized human doll, both of which the spell consumes, and an intricate crystal rod worth at least 1,500 gp that is not consumed</set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Frost Fingers" type="Spell" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_SPELL_FROST_FINGERS">
		<supports>Wizard</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Freezing cold blasts from your fingertips in a 15-foot cone. Each creature in that area must make a Constitution saving throw, taking 2d8 cold damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</p>
			<p class="indent">The cold freezes nonmagical liquids in the area that aren't being worn or carried.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>At Higher Levels.</em></strong> When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords"></set>
			<set name="level">1</set>
			<set name="school">Evocation</set>
			<set name="time">1 action</set>
			<set name="range">Self (15-foot cone)</set>
			<set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
			<set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
			<set name="hasMaterialComponent">false</set>
			<set name="materialComponent"></set>
			<set name="isConcentration">false</set>
			<set name="isRitual">false</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Snowshoes" type="Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_ITEM_SNOWSHOES">
		<description>
			<p>Snowshoes reduce the likelihood of their wearer getting stuck in the deep snow.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">2</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">feet</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="The Incantations of Iriolarthas" type="Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_ITEM_THE_INCANTATIONS_OF_IRIOLARTHAS">
		<description>
			<p>The Incantations of Iriolarthas is a weighty spellbook. Its black leather covers have dead, toothy worms glued to them, sheathed in glossy varnish. Set into this morbid display on the front cover is a gold rune that resembles a stylized eye with a pupil shaped like a candle flame—the sigil of Iriolarthas, a Netherese lich.</p>
			<p class="indent">The book contains sixty pages of brittle yellow vellum. Written on these pages are the following wizard spells:</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>1st level: </em></strong> alarm, detect magic, identify, magic missile, shield, Tasha's hideous laughter, thunderwave</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>2nd level: </em></strong> arcane lock, continual flame, invisibility, knock, levitate, Melf's acid arrow, mirror image</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>3rd level: </em></strong> animate dead, bestow curse, clairvoyance, counterspell, dispel magic, fireball, glyph of warding</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>4th level: </em></strong> arcane eye, banishment, blight, dimension door, Evard's black tentacles, phantasmal killer</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>5th level: </em></strong> Bigby's hand, cloudkill, dominate person, planar binding, scrying, telekinesis</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>6th level: </em></strong> create undead, disintegrate, globe of invulnerability, move earth, Otto's irresistible dance</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>7th level: </em></strong> create magen, finger of death, prismatic spray, teleport</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>8th level: </em></strong> demiplane, dominate monster, mind blank, power word stun</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>9th level: </em></strong> blade of disaster, power word kill</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Crampons" type="Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_ITEM_CRAMPONS">
		<description>
			<p>A crampon is a metal plate with spikes that is strapped to the sole of a boot. A creature wearing crampons can't fall prone while moving across slippery ice.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">2</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="4">4 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Clothing, Cold Weather" type="Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_ITEM_CLOTHING_COLD_WEATHER">
		<description>
			<p>This outfit consists of a heavy fur coat or cloak over layers of wool clothing, as well as a fur-lined hat or hood, goggles, and fur-lined leather boots and gloves.</p>
			<p class="indent">As long as cold weather clothing remains dry, its wearer automatically succeeds on saving throws against the effects of extreme cold.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Adventuring Gear</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">10</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="5">5 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Dogsled" type="Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_ITEM_DOGSLED">	
		<description>
			<p>An empty sled costs 20 gp, weighs 300 pounds, and has room at the back for one driver.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Mounts &amp; Vehicles</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">20</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0" excludeEncumbrance="true">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Vehicle</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Sled Dog" type="Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_ITEM_SLED_DOG">
		<description>
			<p>A sled dog (use the wolf stat block in appendix A of the Monster Manual) costs 50 gp and can pull 360 pounds.</p>
			<p class="indent">Sled dogs must take a short rest after pulling a sled for 1 hour; otherwise, they gain one level of exhaustion.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> 40 ft.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Mounts &amp; Vehicles</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">50</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0" excludeEncumbrance="true">—</set>
			<set name="type">Mount</set>
		</setters>
	</element> 
	<element name="Axe Beak" type="Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_ITEM_AXE_BEAK">
		<description>
			<p>An axe beak's splayed toes allow it to run across snow, and it can carry as much weight as a mule. A domesticated axe beak can be purchased in Ten-Towns for 50 gp.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> 40 ft.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Carrying Capacity.</em></strong>420 lb.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Mounts &amp; Vehicles</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">50</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0" excludeEncumbrance="true">—</set>
			<set name="type">Mount</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Abracadabrus" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_ABRACADABRUS">
		<description>
			<p>An abracadabrus is an ornate, gemstone-studded wooden chest that weighs 25 pounds while empty. Its interior compartment is a cube measuring 1½ feet on a side.</p>
			<p class="indent">The chest has 20 charges. A creature can use an action to touch the closed lid of the chest and expend 1 of the chest's charges while naming one or more nonmagical objects (including raw materials, foodstuffs, and liquids) worth a total of 1 gp or less. The named objects magically appear in the chest, provided they can all fit inside it and the chest doesn't contain anything else. For example, the chest can conjure a plate of strawberries, a bowl of hot soup, a flagon of water, a stuffed animal, or a bag of twenty caltrops. Food and drink conjured by the chest are delicious, and they spoil if not consumed after 24 hours. Gems and precious metals created by the chest disappear after 1 minute.</p>
			<p class="indent">The chest regains 1d20 expended charges daily at dawn. If the item's last charge is expended, roll a d20. On a 1, the chest loses its magic (becoming an ordinary chest), and its gemstones turn to dust.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="25">25 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Very Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Cauldron of Plenty" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_CAULDRON_OF_PLENTY">
		<description>
			<p>This cauldron is made of thick copper that has turned green with age. It is 4 feet wide, has a mouth 3½ feet in diameter, weighs 50 pounds, and can hold up to 30 gallons of liquid. Embossed on its bulging sides are images of satyrs and nymphs in repose, holding ladles. The cauldron comes with a lid and has side handles. It sits on five little clawed feet that keep it from tipping.</p>
			<p class="indent">If water is poured into the cauldron and stirred for 1 minute, it transforms into a hearty, hot stew, which can provide one nourishing meal for up to four people per gallon. The stew remains hot while in the cauldron, then cools naturally after it is removed. The outside of the cauldron remains safe to touch despite the heat of the stew.</p>
			<p class="indent">The cauldron can create stew three times. It then ceases to function until the next dawn, when it regains all its uses.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="50">50 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Hook of Fisher's Delight" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_HOOK_OF_FISHERS_DELIGHT">
		<description>
			<p>This tiny silver fishhook has a little gold feather attached to it. For it to function, the feathered hook must be tied to the end of a fishing line and immersed in enough water to fill at least a 10-foot cube. At the end of each uninterrupted hour of immersion, roll a d6. On a 6, a floppy, 6-inch-long magical fish appears on the end of the hook. The color and properties of the conjured fish are determined by rolling on the Hook of Fisher's Delight table. Once the hook conjures a fish, it can't do so again until the next dawn.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">Hook of Fisher's Delight</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d20</td><td>Fish Color</td><td>Result</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1-10</td><td>Green with copper bands</td><td>This tasty fish provides a day's worth of nourishment to one creature that eats it. The fish loses this property and rots if it's not eaten within 24 hours of being caught.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>11-14</td><td>Yellow with black stripes</td><td>Once removed from the hook, this awful-tasting fish can be thrown up to 120 feet, targeting a creature the thrower can see. The target must succeed on a DC 15 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone. The fish then disappears.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>15-18</td><td>Blue with white bands</td><td>When released from the hook, this fish squirms free, sprouts wings, follows you around, and sings a beautiful tune in Aquan. It disappears after 2d4 hours or when reduced to 0 hit points. The fish uses the quipper stat block, except that it can breathe air and has a flying speed of 30 feet.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>19-20</td><td>Gold with silver stripes</td><td>This tasty fish provides a day's worth of nourishment to one creature that eats it and grants 2d10 temporary hit points to that creature. The fish loses these properties and rots if it's not eaten within 24 hours of being caught.</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Lantern of Tracking" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_LANTERN_OF_TRACKING">
		<description>
			<p>This hooded lantern burns for 6 hours on 1 pint of oil, shedding bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent">Each lantern of tracking is designed to track down a certain type of creature, which is determined by rolling on the Lantern of Tracking table. Once determined, this creature type can't be changed. While the lantern is within 300 feet of any creature of that type, its flame turns bright green. The lantern doesn't pinpoint the creature's exact location, however.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">Lantern of Tracking</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>d10</td><td>Creature Type</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>Aberrations</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>Celestials</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>Constructs</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>Dragons</td></tr>
				<tr><td>5</td><td>Elementals</td></tr>
				<tr><td>6</td><td>Fey</td></tr>
				<tr><td>7</td><td>Fiends</td></tr>
				<tr><td>8</td><td>Giants</td></tr>
				<tr><td>9</td><td>Monstrosities</td></tr>
				<tr><td>10</td><td>Undead</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Orc Stone" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_ORC_STONE">
		<description>
			<p>I saved the life of an orc, who gave me a stone with the symbol of the Many-Arrows tribe (a humanoid skull pierced by three arrows) carved into it. The stone is an uncommon magic item that requires attunement, and only I can attune to it.</p>
			<p class="indent">As an action, I can use the stone to summon the spirit of an orc warrior, which appears within 30 feet of me. The spirit uses the orc war chief stat block in the Monster Manual and disappears after 10 minutes or when reduced to 0 hit points. The spirit understands any language I speak and obeys my commands.</p>
			<p class="indent">After the stone is used three times, it turns to dust. (See Appendix B of Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden)</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a pecipient only">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Professor Skant" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_PROFESSOR_SKANT">
		<description>
			<p>The professor orb owned by Vellynne Harpell and stolen by Nass Lantomir calls itself Professor Skant. It is lawful good, and it has a Wisdom of 11 and a Charisma of 9. It speaks and reads Common, Draconic, Elvish, and Loross (the dead language of the Empire of Netheril). Professor Skant is a chatterbox and assumes all humanoids are dunderheads. When elaborating on its areas of expertise, it adopts an unintentionally patronizing tone. It has the following four areas of expertise:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>The history of Netheril (see the "Fate of Netheril" sidebar)</li>
				<li>Vampirism and the traits of vampires</li>
				<li>Rituals surrounding the making, bottling, and drinking of Elverquisst (a rare, ruby-colored elven liquor distilled from sunshine and rare summer fruits)</li>
				<li>The tarrasque (see the Monster Manual)</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Psi Crystal" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_PSI_CRYSTAL">
		<description>
			<p>This crystal grants you telepathy for as long as you remain attuned to it. See the introduction of the Monster Manual for rules on how this telepathy works.</p>
			<p class="indent">The crystal also glows with a purplish inner light while you are attuned to it.</p>
			<p class="indent">The higher your intelligence, the greater the light's intensity and the greater the range of the telepathy (see the Psi Crystal Properties table).</p>
			<h5 class="caption">Psi Crystal Properties</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Intelligence Score</td><td>Range of Telepathy</td><td>Light Intensity</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>3-7</td><td>15 feet</td><td>Dim light out to a range of 5 feet</td></tr>
				<tr><td>8-11</td><td>30 feet</td><td>Bright light in a 5-foot radius and dim light for an additional 5 feet</td></tr>
				<tr><td>12-15</td><td>60 feet</td><td>Bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet</td></tr>
				<tr><td>16 or higher</td><td>120 feet</td><td>Bright light in a 15-foot radius and dim light for an additional 15 feet</td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Uncommon</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a creature with an intelligence score of 3 or higher">true</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Scroll of Tarrasque Summoning" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_SCROLL_OF_TARRASQUE_SUMMONING">
		<description>
			<p>Using an action to read the scroll causes the tarrasque (see the creature's entry in the Monster Manual) to appear in an unoccupied space you can see within 1 mile of you. The tarrasque disappears when it drops to 0 hit points and is hostile toward all creatures other than itself.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Scrolls</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Scroll</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Scroll of the Comet" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_SCROLL_OF_THE_COMET">
		<description>
			<p>By using an action to read the scroll, you cause a comet to fall from the sky and crash to the ground at a point you can see up to 1 mile away from you. You must be outdoors when you use the scroll, or nothing happens and the scroll is wasted.</p>
			<p class="indent">The comet creates a 50-foot-deep, 500-foot-radius crater on impact. Any creature in that radius must make a DC 20 Dexterity saving throw, taking 30d10 force damage on a failed saving throw, or half as much damage on a successful one. All structures in the crater are destroyed, as are all nonmagical objects that aren't being worn or held.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Scrolls</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Scroll</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Shield Guardian Amulet" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_SHIELD_GUARDIAN_AMULET">
		<description>
			<p>The amulet is a 4-inch-wide disk composed of silver-framed wood, with a rune carved into its face. A detect magic spell reveals a magical aura of enchantment around the amulet.</p>
			<p class="indent">Every shield guardian has an amulet magically linked to it. A shield guardian can have only one corresponding amulet, and if that amulet is destroyed, the shield guardian is incapacitated until a replacement amulet is created.</p>
			<p class="indent">A shield guardian's amulet is subject to direct attack if it isn't being worn or carried. It has AC 10, 10 hit points, and immunity to poison and psychic damage. Crafting an amulet requires 1 week and costs 1,000 gp in components.</p>
			<p class="indent">A shield guardian's solitary focus is to protect the amulet's wearer. The amulet's wearer can command the guardian to attack its enemies or to guard the wielder against attack. If an attack threatens to injure the wearer, the construct can magically absorb the blow into its own body, even at a distance.</p>
			<p class="indent">A humanoid that attunes to this amulet knows the distance and direction of the shield guardian, provided the amulet and the guardian are on the same plane of existence. As an action, the amulet's attuned wearer can try to reactivate the shield guardian, doing so with a successful DC 20 Intelligence (Arcana) check. Reactivation can only be attempted while the amulet and guardian are within 10 feet of each other.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Rare</set>
			<set name="slot">neck</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a humanoid">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="The Codicil of White" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_THE_CODICIL_OF_WHITE">
		<description>
			<p>The Codicil of White is a tall, thin volume bound in white ermine fur over seasoned boards of white pine and sealed with a clasp and lock of tarnished silver. The book is cold to the touch, and the fur is worn about the edges from use. The twenty-seven pages within are of vellum painted with silver gilt on the outer edges. The whole is sewn to a leather binding with strips of sinews, making it quite durable.</p>
			<p class="indent">A creature with the codicil in its possession has resistance to cold damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">The codicil was written by followers of Auril as a primer on her worship. The first page is a title page with the snowflake symbol of Auril on it. The remaining pages describe various priestly rituals and ceremonies in chilling detail. Nestled among these descriptions is a spell that wizards can learn (frost fingers, and a poem called "Rime of the Frostmaiden" (see appendix E)). The poem is an incantation, the power of which can be used to split a glacier (see chapter 6). The poem might have other capabilities, at your discretion</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="slot">misc</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_COLD" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Thermal Cube" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_THERMAL_CUBE">
		<description>
			<p>This 3-inch cube of solid brimstone generates enough dry heat to keep the temperature within 15 feet of it at 95 degrees Fahrenheit (35 degrees Celsius).</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Common</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Ythryn Mythallar" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_YTHRYN_MYTHALLAR">
		<description>
			<p>A mythallar looks like an enormous crystal ball held in an ornate cradle. The globe sheds bright light in a 300-foot radius and dim light for an additional 300 feet. The globe draws magic from the Weave that can be harnessed for various purposes. For example, Netherese mages used mythallars to keep their cities aloft and empower their magic items. The bigger the mythallar, the more magic it can hold. The largest mythallars are 150 feet in diameter.</p>
			<p class="indent">The Ythryn mythallar is a relatively small device—a mere 50 feet in diameter. To attune to this mythallar, a creature must finish a short rest within 30 feet of it, meditating on the mythallar. Up to eight creatures can be attuned to it at one time; otherwise, the Ythryn mythallar follows the attunement rules in the Dungeon Master's Guide. If a ninth creature tries to attune to the mythallar, nothing happens.</p>
			<p class="indent">All creatures attuned to the Ythryn mythallar can sense when the device is being used. A creature attuned to the device can use any of its properties, but only if all other creatures attuned to the device agree to allow it. The Ythryn mythallar's properties are as follows:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>While you're on the same plane of existence as the Ythryn mythallar, you can use an action to cause it to fly in any direction you choose at a speed of 30 feet. All matter within 500 feet of the device moves with it. The Ythryn mythallar and all structures held aloft by it hover in place when not in motion.</li>
				<li>As an action, you can cause one magic item you are holding within 30 feet of the Ythryn mythallar to immediately regain all its expended charges or uses. A magic item recharged in this manner can't be recharged by the Ythryn mythallar again until after the item regains expended charges or uses on its own.</li>
				<li>You can use the Ythryn mythallar to cast the control weather spell without requiring any components and without the need for you to be outdoors. This casting of the spell has a 50-mile radius. For the duration of the spell's casting time, you must be within 30 feet of the Ythryn mythallar or the spell fails.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Touching the Mythallar.</em></strong> Any creature that touches the globe of the mythallar must make a DC 22 Constitution saving throw, taking 180 (20d10 + 70) radiant damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. Undead have disadvantage on this saving throw. Any object that touches the globe, other than an artifact or the mythallar's cradle, is disintegrated instantly (no save).</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
			<set name="rarity">Legendary</set>
			<set name="attunement" addition="by a spellcaster">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Charm of Biting Cold" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_CHARM_OF_BITING_COLD">
		<description>
			<p>This charm has 3 charges. As a bonus action, you can expend 1 of the charm's charges to wreathe your weapon attacks with biting cold for 1 minute. Until this effect ends, you deal an extra 1d6 cold damage when you hit with a melee or ranged weapon attack. Once all its charges have been expended, this charm vanishes from you.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Charm of Bounty" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_CHARM_OF_BOUNTY">
		<description>
			<p>This charm has 3 charges. As an action, you can expend 1 of the charm's charges to cast the create food and water spell, requiring no components. Once all its charges have been expended, this charm vanishes from you.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Charm of Cold Resistance" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_CHARM_OF_COLD_RESISTANCE">
		<description>
			<p>This charm allows you to give yourself resistance to cold damage as an action. This benefit lasts for 24 hours, after which the charm vanishes from you.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Charm of Snowball Strike" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_CHARM_OF_SNOWBALL_STRIKE">
		<description>
			<p>This charm has 5 charges. As a bonus action, you can expend 1 of the charm's charges to create a magical snowball in your hand and throw it. You must have a hand free to hold the snowball, or the charge is wasted. The snowball is a magic ranged weapon with which you are proficient. It has a normal range of 20 feet and a long range of 60 feet, it deals 1d4 cold damage on a hit, and it scores a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20. If you score a critical hit with the snowball, the target is blinded until the end of its next turn. The snowball vanishes immediately after you hit or miss with it, or at the end of your turn if you don't throw it. Once all its charges have been expended, this charm vanishes from you.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Charm of the Ice Troll" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_CHARM_OF_THE_ICE_TROLL">
		<description>
			<p>This charm allows you to use your reaction when you take cold damage to reduce the damage to 0. You regain a number of hit points equal to half the cold damage you would have taken. Once you do so, the charm vanishes from you.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Charm of the Snow Walker" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_CHARM_OF_THE_SNOW_WALKER">
		<description>
			<p>This charm has 3 charges. As an action, you can expend 1 of the charm's charges to gain the following benefits for 24 hours:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You and your allies within 15 feet of you ignore difficult terrain caused by snow or ice.</li>
				<li>You can see through areas heavily obscured by snow to a distance of 60 feet.</li>
				<li>You are immune to the effects of extreme cold, as described in the Dungeon Master's Guide (though you gain no protection from cold damage).</li>
			</ul>
			<p>Once all its charges have been expended, this charm vanishes from you.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Charm of the Traveler's Haven" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_CHARM_OF_THE_TRAVELERS_HAVEN">
		<description>
			<p>This charm has 3 charges. As an action, you can expend 1 of the charm's charges to cast the Leomund's tiny hut spell, no components required. Once all its charges have been expended, this charm vanishes from you.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Vlagomir's Spark" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_VLAGOMIRS_SPARK">
		<description>
			<p>You gain 1 foot of height every hour and become proportionately heavier until you stand 21 feet tall and weigh 7,700 pounds. When you are 9 feet tall, your Strength becomes 19 unless it is already higher. For every 3 additional feet of height you gain, your Strength increases by 1, to a maximum of 23. Armor and clothing you are wearing and weapons you are carrying magically increase in size to match your growth. If you are the recipient of a greater restoration spell or similar magic, this charm vanishes from you, and you immediately shrink back to normal size, along with any armor, clothing, and weapons in your possession.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Vlagomir's Spark, Strength 19" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_VLAGOMIRS_SPARK_19">
		<description>
			<p>You gain 1 foot of height every hour and become proportionately heavier until you stand 21 feet tall and weigh 7,700 pounds. When you are 9 feet tall, your Strength becomes 19 unless it is already higher. For every 3 additional feet of height you gain, your Strength increases by 1, to a maximum of 23. Armor and clothing you are wearing and weapons you are carrying magically increase in size to match your growth. If you are the recipient of a greater restoration spell or similar magic, this charm vanishes from you, and you immediately shrink back to normal size, along with any armor, clothing, and weapons in your possession.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="strength:score:set" value="19" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Vlagomir's Spark, Strength 20" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_VLAGOMIRS_SPARK_20">
		<description>
			<p>You gain 1 foot of height every hour and become proportionately heavier until you stand 21 feet tall and weigh 7,700 pounds. When you are 9 feet tall, your Strength becomes 19 unless it is already higher. For every 3 additional feet of height you gain, your Strength increases by 1, to a maximum of 23. Armor and clothing you are wearing and weapons you are carrying magically increase in size to match your growth. If you are the recipient of a greater restoration spell or similar magic, this charm vanishes from you, and you immediately shrink back to normal size, along with any armor, clothing, and weapons in your possession.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="strength:score:set" value="20" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Vlagomir's Spark, Strength 21" type="Magic Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_MAGIC_ITEM_VLAGOMIRS_SPARK_21">
		<description>
			<p>You gain 1 foot of height every hour and become proportionately heavier until you stand 21 feet tall and weigh 7,700 pounds. When you are 9 feet tall, your Strength becomes 19 unless it is already higher. For every 3 additional feet of height you gain, your Strength increases by 1, to a maximum of 23. Armor and clothing you are wearing and weapons you are carrying magically increase in size to match your growth. If you are the recipient of a greater restoration spell or similar magic, this charm vanishes from you, and you immediately shrink back to normal size, along with any armor, clothing, and weapons in your possession.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Supernatural Gifts</set>
			<set name="type">Charm</set>
			<set name="slot">gift</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="strength:score:set" value="21" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Spider-Shaped Brooch" type="Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_ITEM_TREASURE_SPIDER_SHAPED_BROOCH">
		<description>
			<p>A spider-shaped brooch made of obsidian and engraved with the symbol of House Dalambra.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Treasure</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">25</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
			<set name="valuable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Harp of Exotic Wood" type="Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_ITEM_TREASURE_EXOTIC_HARP">
		<description>
			<p>A carved harp of exotic wood with ivory inlay and zircon gemstones.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">ivory,gemstones</set>
			<set name="category">Treasure</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">750</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
			<set name="valuable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Decorative Pearl Bead" type="Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_ITEM_TREASURE_DECORATIVE_PEARL_BEAD">
		<description>
			<p>A pearl carved into a decorative bead.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Treasure</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">5</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
			<set name="valuable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Electrum Pendant" type="Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_ITEM_TREASURE_ELECTRUM_PENDANT">
		<description>
			<p>An electrum chain with a bloodstone pendant.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">chain,necklace,bloodstone</set>
			<set name="category">Treasure</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">250</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
			<set name="valuable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Gold Whirlpool Ring" type="Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_ITEM_TREASURE_GOLD_WHIRLPOOL_RING">
		<description>
			<p>A gold ring with a black pearl set into a fixture shaped like a whirlpool.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Treasure</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">750</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
			<set name="valuable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Mummy's Golden Mask" type="Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_ITEM_TREASURE_MUMMYS_GOLDEN_MASK">
		<description>
			<p>This mummy's golden mask is a Netherese art object.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Treasure</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">750</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
			<set name="valuable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Silk Robe" type="Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_ITEM_TREASURE_SILK_ROBE">
		<description>
			<p>A silk robe spun by the spiders.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">spiders</set>
			<set name="category">Treasure</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">250</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
			<set name="valuable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Undamaged Remorhaz Egg" type="Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_ITEM_TREASURE_UNDAMAGED_REMORHAZ_EGG">
		<description>
			<p>An undamaged remorhaz egg can be sold to an interested buyer in Bryn Shander for up to 500 gp.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Treasure</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">500</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
			<set name="valuable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Vial of Quicksilver" type="Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_ITEM_TREASURE_VIAL_OF_QUICKSILVER">
		<description>
			<p>A vial of quicksilver.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Treasure</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">500</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
			<set name="valuable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Intricate Crystal Rod" type="Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_ITEM_TREASURE_INTRICATE_CRYSTAL_ROD">
		<description>
			<p>An intricate crystal rod.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Treasure</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">1800</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
			<set name="valuable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
	<element name="Miniature Netherese Skycoach" type="Item" source="Icewind Dale: Rime of the Frostmaiden" id="ID_WOTC_IDROTF_ITEM_TREASURE_MINIATURE_NETHERESE_SKYCOACH">
		<description>
			<p>A miniature Netherese skycoach in a bottle.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Treasure</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">750</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="stackable">true</set>
			<set name="valuable">true</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
</elements>